Chapter 370: Challenge (2)

“What’s so funny? I only wished to not injure you out of kindness!” When this cultivator saw that Han Li didn’t seem to care, he couldn’t help but become angry and increasingly flaunt his status as a ‘superior’.

Han Li tapped the floor with the tip of his foot, indifferently saying, “It’s nothing! I only feel that this competition is going to be easier than I had imagined.”

“What? You dare to look down on me?!” The middle aged cultivator’s face completely reddened. He raised his hand and revealed many glistening items. But before he could act, he suddenly saw the person in front of him blur. His vision then blackened, and he fell to the floor not knowing what had happened.

……

A short moment later, Han Li carried the unconscious middle-aged man off the stage with an indifferent expression.

When the other cultivators saw this, they were stunned.

There was a clear difference in their cultivation, but the victor was Han Li. This was far beyond their expectations.

Even the old man, who had appeared moody from the very beginning, revealed an odd expression.

He took a deep look at Han Li. Although he didn’t say anything, he seemed to know how Han Li had taken action.

Han Li chuckled and calmly handed the two bamboo sticks to the old man. He then dropped his unconscious opponent to the floor and went over to the group of victorious cultivators.

The old man saw that the middle-aged cultivator was still unconscious and lightly shook his head, revealing a mysterious smile.

“Number eight!”

……

When the final victor was decided, the old man looked at the ten cultivators that hadn’t gone on the platform and lightly coughed. He then spoke with an indifferent tone, “We will now start the challenges in order of number. If you feel that your magic power is severely exhausted, you may take a moment to rest before facing your next challenge. However, these challenges must finish by today; it will count as a forfeit otherwise. Also, challengers are forbidden from challenging those who have already fought. As for the extra eleventh challenger, they will be allowed to challenge any one of the winning incumbents after the ten winners have been decided.”

“Now, let’s start!”

The first challenger selected the incumbent with the lowest cultivation and entered the stage with him.

As his opponent’s cultivation was only of the sixth layer and his cultivation was of the seventh, it appeared that he had high odds of winning.

But after the time it took to make a cup of tea, the sixth layer cultivator left the stage first. As for the first challenger, he reappeared in a miserable state.

He was ashamed and quickly left the hall without a word.

The remaining challengers revealed changed expressions. As for the victor, he returned to the other ten without the slightest of care.

“Next!” The old man shouted. He didn’t reveal the slightest surprise as if he had expected that cultivator to win!

“Senior, my magic power is deficient. I wish to rest for a moment!” The second chosen cultivator spoke with a slight blush.

“Number three!” The old man didn’t care whether his magic power truly hadn’t recovered and shouted the next number.

The following cultivator lightly creased his brow and also avoided the next fight.

As for the fourth challenger, he appeared to be unwilling to lose face and summoned the courage to choose an opponent, entering the stage.

In the end, the same result occurred. The fourth challenger was heavily injured, causing the remaining challengers to all be shaken.

Having seen this, the following two challengers took the opportunity to delay their fights. They thought that they would be able to make a better choice after seeing how it ended up for the others.

The old man’s face stirred for a moment, before slowly calling out Han Li’s number, “Number Seven!”

Han Li silently walked forward and pointed to an opponent with a sixth layer cultivation.

The opponent was a burly man. Having seen Han Li fearlessly select him, he suddenly revealed a malicious smile and walked toward the stage in large strides.

In contrast, Han Li walked forward with slow steps as if he was deliberating about the coming match.

Soon, Han Li and the burly man disappeared into the white light. Everyone looked in the direction of the stage with interest.

The old man then closed his eyes as if he had extended his spiritual sense.

But after a short moment, his cheeks slightly moved. He then opened his eyes and revealed a trace of astonishment.

With a flash of white light, a person appeared on the platform.

The many cultivators hurriedly turned their gaze. The light faded away to reveal Han Li. He didn’t have the slightest injury, but he was dragging his opponent who had his entire body scorched. He leisurely walked off the platform as if he hadn’t spent the slightest effort.

Not only were the challengers stupefied, even the incumbent opponents also had looks of disbelief on their faces.

As for Wen Qiang who stood behind the old man, his mouth was gaping. He didn’t close it until some time later.

Han Li dragged his still-breathing opponent towards the old man and left him there, before returning to his original position with a leisurely stride.

When the other challengers saw this, they couldn’t help but turn their gaze and reveal a trace of reverence.

Han Li coldly smiled in his heart.

It seemed that regardless of where he went, strength was the most effective method of speech.

Perhaps it was because Han Li’s unexpected triumph inspired confidence in the remaining challengers, the following challengers didn’t avoid their fight and immediately chose an opponent.

However, this only resulted in defeat and heavy injuries.

The challengers who had delayed their fights were appalled. With their competitive spirits completely extinguished, each one of them had eventually decided to forfeit.

After all, they knew that they were no match. Only an idiot would decide to fight regardless!

As such, the old man declared that only Han Li, on behalf of the Gu Clan, had acquired the qualifications for main island trade.

Afterwards, the old man handed a blue jade slip to Han Li and told him it would be settled once he gave that to the Gu Clan.

The old man then unceremoniously dismissed the cultivators, chasing them out of the hall with his voice.

……

Han Li handed the blue jade slip to Master Gu in the corridor.

His expressions were quite marvelous. He appeared incredulous, astonished, and finally ecstatic with joy.

“Immortal Han, I am grateful beyond words. Please feel at ease, the Gu Clan will definitely fulfill their promise with you.”

By the time he said these words, Han Li, Master Gu, and Wang Changqing were already sitting in the carriage and were on their way back to the Gu Clan Estate.

As he was speaking these grateful words, his hands were tightly grasping the jade slip as if he was afraid that it would fly away. It made for quite a funny scene.

Leaning against the back of the carriage, Han Li said with a slight smile, “I believe Mister Gu isn’t someone who would abandon their benefactor upon achieving their goals, especially when the benefactor in question is a cultivator.”

With the warning laced in Han Li’s words, Master Gu and Wang Changqing paled and repeatedly said that they didn’t dare.

Not long after that, Han Li returned to his wooden house on the hill. Crooked Soul was still obediently on guard.

Han Li only managed to refine Qi for three days before Wang Changqing went to find him.

He had come to inform Han Li that Han Li could now go the Immortal Mountain’s Immortal Records Pavilion and acquire permanent residence at Stalwart Star Island. They would also provide him with a cultivation area.

After all, the cultivators of the island all had their own Immortal’s cave.

Since he hadn’t participated in the Great Spirit Land Contest, his area was certain to have thinner Spiritual Qi, but it would still have enough to be considered an area of cultivation.

Han Li pocketed the guarantor’s document that the Gu Clan had given him and flew towards the center of Stalwart Star Island. Crooked Soul was naturally left behind to guard his small house.

On his way, Han Li flew past seven cities and several tens of small towns before finally catching view of the Immortal Mountain that Wang Changqing had mentioned.

It was a huge, azure, tri-peaked mountain that penetrated through the clouds. The sight was truly majestic and beyond lofty.

Innumerable smaller peaks surrounded the huge mountain.

Han Li was unable to tell how expansive the mountain was from a glance.

He blankly stared at this “Immortal Mountain” while lost in thought.

“Hm? Aren’t you Fellow Daoist Han?” Han Li suddenly heard someone call out to him from behind.

Han Li was slightly alarmed and hastily turned around. The voice sounded familiar.

Not far behind him, the gentle and frail Wen Qiang was looking at him with a smile, flying on his wheel magic tool.

After staring blankly for a moment, Han Li responded with a chuckle, “So it was Fellow Daoist Wen! What a coincidence!”

“Hehe! I didn’t expect to see you! Fellow Daoist Han was actually able to defeat a cultivator from the protector squad. I really admire you!”

“Protector squad?” Han Li was startled to hear this!

Chapter 400: Dignified

“Elder Zhao, sorry for the long wait! This is Senior Han, the owner of those demon beast materials!” After entering the room, Fan Jingmei spoke to the grey-clothed old man with a respectful tone.

The grey-clothed old man replied, “Oh, so it’s Fellow Daoist Han! Please, sit. This old man just steeped a pot of ice-cloud spirit tea. Please, have a taste.”

Han Li frowned. There was nothing odd about the old man’s appearance apart from unusually red cheeks, as if he had just recovered from a grave illness. He couldn’t help but feel somewhat puzzled.

His current spiritual sense was far stronger than cultivators of the same rank. In an instant, he was able to see that the old man was an early Core Formation cultivator. Han Li didn’t say anything in refusal and bluntly took a seat across from the old man. Han Li indifferently stared at the old man as he poured a cup of fragrant tea, but didn’t move to take it.

Han Li didn’t mean to slight the old man as he was acting out of habitual carefulness. He definitely wasn’t going to drink something from an unfamiliar place.

The old man didn’t reveal any displeasure at Han Li’s cautious actions. Instead, he faintly smiled and poured himself a cup, placing all other matters to the back of his head for that instant.

“Senior Han! We’ve come to find you on behalf of the Exquisite Sound Sect to purchase all of your remaining demon beast materials. Let’s discuss the price.” Just as Fan Jingmei sat down, she gently spoke to Han Li with a dainty composure.

How could Han Li easily admit to still having many rare materials despite not knowing their intentions? After some calm thought about what they had said, Han Li decided to block them for the time being, “It is true that I had previously acquired quite a few demon beast materials. However, I have just sold my last batch. I fear I that must disappoint you.”

When Lady Fan heard Han Li’s refusal, she sweetly smiled and softly spoke with a hint of laughter, “It seems Senior Han wishes to fool us. Although our sect doesn’t know how many demon beast materials you have, we are certain that it’s a large amount. Otherwise, Senior Han wouldn’t have so carefully sought out small, travelling merchants to sell them to. In addition, every transaction was done in very small amounts, and you look for a different buyer every time.”

“Had our sect not happened to be gathering related materials, it’s likely we wouldn’t have discovered something was amiss. Senior sure is scared of having his wealth exposed! If this is the case, Senior Han can dispel those fears. Although our sect isn’t some sort of superpower, our sect holds quite a positive reputation in the Scattered Star Seas. If Senior were to sell all the materials to us, it would save us the trouble of repeatedly purchasing them from small merchants!”

The woman spoke with a beaming smile and a calm appearance. However, Han Li’s eyes coldly glinted, and he slightly scowled. Finding out you had been secretly investigated wasn’t a happy matter!

In response to Han Li’s scowl, Lady Fan suddenly changed the subject and gave Han Li an explanation, “Senior Han, please don’t blame me for my rude conduct from before. This matter is quite urgent and we had to make use of a majority of our power in Heavenly Star City to track you down. We hope that Senior will provide us assistance, just this once!”

This time, she had placed herself in a weaker position with her words and gaze revealing a slight intention to implore.

Han Li’s scowl gradually subsided, but he didn’t give an immediate response. Instead, he started to lightly tap the table with an indifferent expression. At this moment, Han Li’s mind was continuously churning through lines of thought, analyzing the pros and cons at lightning speed.

Although he didn’t know why the Exquisite Sound Sect required such a large quantity of demon beast materials, they clearly believed that he possessed what they desired. If Han Li further denied them, it would only serve to create a meaningless grudge.

While he hadn’t heard of the Exquisite Sound Sect before, they shouldn’t be too weak, given the appearance of Elder Zhao. Han Li didn’t wish to make an enemy of them without good reason.

In addition, he possessed a bit too many demon beast materials. If he continued to sell them off bit by bit, it would only be a matter of time before he was found out. As such, wouldn’t it be better to take advantage of this opportunity and cleanly handle the matter all at once? After all, this was Heavenly Star City where fights were prohibited. He wouldn’t have to worry about anything going amiss.

With that thought, Han Li was silent for a moment more before serenely saying, “Since you’ve spoken as such, I won’t further conceal the truth. I do possess a few of the demon beast materials that your sect desires, but I don’t know whether or not I have enough to satisfy you!”

The two women revealed joy at Han Li’s admittance. As for the old man sipping tea as if he were above the world, he gazed at Han Li with a much more relaxed expression.

“How much are you in possession of?!” Lady Fan impatiently asked, gazing at Han Li in anticipation.

Han Li faintly smiled and replied with an astonishing number, much to the pleasant surprise of the woman. Although she knew Han Li possessed quite a bit, she didn’t expect the quantity to be at such a degree. She could finally finish her mission.

“I want all of those materials! Does Senior have time to do the trade today?” The Exquisite Sound Sect’s Lady Fan couldn’t keep her composure and spoke with a slight tremble in her voice, fearful that Han Li would change his mind.

Han Li felt quite surprised at this woman’s impatience. However, he also felt that it would be best for this trade to made as quickly as possible. There would be less time for any unwelcome problems to appear. After some thought, he said, “I do. Let’s do the trade here! Lady Fan should go get the spirit stones. I’ll go and fetch the demon beast materials.” Han Li’s clear decisiveness was in agreement with the woman’s intentions. She repeatedly nodded her head with a gaze of happiness.

Han Li then indifferently stood up and took his leave, walking out of the room in large strides.

A moment after Han Li disappeared from view, Lady Fan’s excited appearance gradually faded away. She suddenly turned her head towards the old man and asked, “Senior Zhao, how is his cultivation? I’ve heard that he had just achieved Core Formation. He shouldn’t have had the time to refine a magic treasure. If you were to take take him by surprise, could you overcome him? If you are confident, we would be able to save quite a huge sum of spirit stones.”

By the time this woman icily said those words, her dainty temperament had changed into a chilling, sinister expression.

“Impossible! Although this person hasn’t been in Core Formation for long, his cultivation art is unordinary. Not only is his magic power exceedingly pure, but his body conceals the faint Qi of a magic treasure. While he didn’t have the time to secretly refine a magic treasure, he is in possession of an inherited magic treasure. We cannot look down on him.” Elder Zhao shook his head and opposed the suggestion.

The woman’s eyes glinted with a strange expression as she slowly said, “So it seems this person isn’t weak. How about we pull him into our operation in the coming month? If things goes smoothly, we can spend a bit to rope him in. If things goes unfavorably, we can just abandon him!”

“That really is a good method! But from the recent conversation, he appears to know when it is appropriate to retreat despite appearing so youthful. It doesn’t seem he will be easily taken advantage of. What is your grasp of the situation? Are you thinking about seducing him?” As the old man spoke, he revealed displeasure.

Lady Fan shot a glance at the old man. Then, while stifling laughter, her eyes revealed fawning. “Hehe, Senior, you’re jealous! Relax, I won’t touch any man apart from you.” She pulled away at her muslin shawl to reveal her extremely enchanting face.

The old man originally appeared somewhat sickly. But upon seeing the woman, he was at a loss for words, and his cheeks flushed to an even deeper red. This scene left Lady Fan feeling very satisfied.

“Senior, in order to protect me, you suffered a great injury. It is something that I will always remember!” After saying this, Lady Fan spun her lithe, well-endowed body around and slid into the old man’s embrace, caressing the old man’s chest with her slender, white hands.

At this moment, Lady Fan’s face revealed overflowing thoughts of love, and her eyes appeared moist to the point of overflowing with tears. Her alluring beauty was capable of even resurrecting dead men.

The old man let out a breath as the woman’s white hand climbed up his chest out of impatient desire. He then crudely responded by embracing her fragrant body with equivalently impure intentions.

This scene caused the young woman who still remained in the room to deeply blush. She averted her gaze with a lowered head.

“Lian’er! How about you wait outside and report back once he returns?” Lady Fan softly whispered as if she had moaned.

“Yes, of course.” The young woman hastily responded as if she were being spared and stepped out of the room.

But before she even left the room, they still continued.

“That young girl has become far more beautiful these past two years. How about you give me a few years to teach her a couple things? Since good things shouldn’t be given to outsiders...”

“Bah! You’re dreaming! I only kept her around because she was useful! I forbid you from laying your hands on her! Could it be that I...”

Having clearly heard the two’s flirtatious banter, the young woman sighed and left the room.

Happy 400th Chapter Guys!

Whew, we've made it so far! Thank you to the readers that kept up so far, and my patrons (noted on the sidebar)! Cheers to a new arc with Han Li making use of his new Core Formation capabilities!

Call out to my former tl: Gandalf's Socks, my former editor: Koreanmist, my elusive proofreader Asvare, and my current editor Barbant (and Maxforce).

Thank you, your support have helped me a great deal! Now another 2046 chapters to go! We're a little bit less than 20% of the way there!

Ending note: Barbant's suggested title and an easter egg.

Chapter 402: Envoys of the Left and Right

“It was stolen?” Han Li’s gaze flashed with distrust.

“Although Senior isn’t convinced, this matter is completely true!” Lady Fan then revealed a wry smile.

“Two months ago, our store was undergoing a large transaction. The profit was such that our Exquisite Sound Sect wouldn’t have had to conduct business for another ten years. Thus, our sect collected a large amount of materials and sent them off, escorted by our Sect Master Wang and the majority of our experts. However, a group of masked cultivators intercepted our convoy. The techniques of their six Core Formation cultivators were profound and evil, and the remaining cultivators were proficient in cooperative techniques. Our sect master was overwhelmed and died at the scene, and the storage pouches holding the items were stolen. A majority of our ordinary sect disciples perished in the attack as well. Were it not for two of our elders throwing caution to the wind and using secret techniques that lowered their cultivation, they would’ve killed us all and no one would’ve known.” The woman’s voice had turned gloomy and her expression turned remorseful.

“It wasn’t a trap setup by the buyer?” Han Li instantly blurted out.

“That is impossible! Our buyer was a member of the Four Elements Merchant Union. They have a flawless reputation. Why would they ruin their reputation over robbing such a minor amount of goods, given their strength?” Lady Fan lightly shook her head and denied this with a pale face, revealing an appearance of frail powerlessness.

Han Li coldly gazed on and didn’t say anything. He didn’t have the slightest intention of consoling the woman.

In response to Han Li’s indifference, Lady Fan could only softly put away her grief and continue her explanation, “That small stalk of Heaven Lightning Bamboo was the treasure of a small sect. However, the sect had declined extremely far and only had a single remaining descendant. As such, the single descendant had sold the item to our Exquisite Sound Sect. My sect master had carried this item on his body and planned to auction it off at Heavenly Star City after the deal was concluded. We didn’t expect it to be plundered as well.”

“But when my sect master was transporting these goods, he had conducted a minor trick on them and we were able to quickly track down their hideout as a result. However, these thieves have quite a few Core Formation cultivators among them, and our sect doesn’t have the strength to take them down. As a result, this meeting wasn’t just about purchasing your goods. We were also assigned the responsibility to scout out high level cultivators for assistance. Seniors’ magic power is quite profound. If you are willing to help us, we wouldn’t mind giving you the Heaven Lightning Bamboo.”

The woman chose her words carefully before arriving at her original intention. Han Li’s expression was indifferent when he heard this, but his eyes continuously shifted around as if he were thinking about something.

When Lady Fan saw this, she knew Han Li was weighing the advantages and disadvantages, and she hurriedly attempted to make the deal sweeter, “If Senior still feels the price is low, our sect is willing to gift an outstanding beauty to Senior as a servant.”

“Not interested!” Han Li bluntly rejected her without the slightest consideration. The woman immediately revealed disappointment in response.

Han Li lightly exhaled and asked a question that greatly surprised the woman, “Has the Heaven Lightning Bamboo been refined? Can it continue to age?”

“It hasn’t been refined. The Heaven Lightning Bamboo was carefully nurtured by that small sect for over a hundred years. It can be further nurtured and continue to sprout out more stalks without a problem. Could it be that Senior doesn’t wish to use it to refine a magic treasure and wishes to leave it behind for his descendants? However, the Heaven Lightning Bamboo grows extremely slowly. After every thousand years, it only grows by only a inch. It is truly difficult to breed!” The woman asked, baffled.

Han Li didn’t respond to her question, lowering his head in contemplation.

Just when Elder Zhao started to appear impatient, Han Li finally came to decision and calmly said, “In addition to the Heaven Lightning Bamboo, we still require another item as payment. After all, Crooked Soul is taking action alongside me.”

“That isn’t a problem. Our sect finds these conditions acceptable!” Lady Fan agreed to the conditions with a beaming smile as if she had no intention of arguing.

“Since this is the case, send someone to inform me at my cave residence when the time comes. Surely your esteemed sect should know where it is.”

Without waiting for Lady Fan to say anything more, he cupped his hands and quickly left with Crooked Soul, not allowing her any additional opportunities to use any of her bewitchment techniques.

Han Li’s blunt departure left Elder Zhao and Lady Fan looking at each other in dismay. Lady Fan’s eyes revealed complicated emotions as her face continuously shifted between clear and gloomy.

After returning to his cave residence, rather than quietly waiting for the Exquisite Sound Sect to call on him, he visited a few of his Core Formation cultivator acquaintances and made a few inquiries about the Exquisite Sound Sect.

Surprisingly, they had all heard of this sect before. One of them even had previous transactions with them.

According to what they said, the Exquisite Sound Sect was acceptable and their business dealings were good. However, their sect had only had women in positions of power for generations. This included the position of sect master.

The Exquisite Sound Sect’s strength couldn’t be said to be powerful. Apart from the sect master, the only other high positions were the Envoy of the Left and the Envoy of the Right. As such, it was only natural that they would employ two or three guest elders as support. Among mid-grade powers, they could be considered to be among neither the best nor the worst.

But even with their strength being nothing of note, they weren’t to be easily provoked. This was because the female cultivators of the Exquisite Sound Sect were each as beautiful as a flower and well cultured. Those in power would often fight over their outstanding female cultivators to be their Dao companion. As such, they received quite a bit of both open and hidden support.

However, what Han Li was most concerned about was that while their reputation was decent, he heard that they had plotted a small number of malicious conspiracies to murder other cultivators. But what was most famous about the Exquisite Sound Sect were their bewitchment techniques. There were a large number of male cultivators that had become completely infatuated with their sect’s female disciples.

After acquiring this information, Han Li felt that he now had a general understanding of the Exquisite Sound Sect. After some consideration, it seemed that he would have to take this job as he was unable to resist the Heaven Lightning Bamboo.

As such, ever since he had returned to his cave residence, he started to quickly craft grade three puppets without end.

Half a month later, a sound transmission talisman flew into Han Li’s hand. After Han Li took a look, he tranquilly arranged his items and then brought Crooked Soul along with his two Bloodjade Spiders out of his cave residence.

When he arrived at one of Heavenly Star City’s gates, the young woman named Lian’er was waiting for him apprehensively. When she saw Han Li and Crooked Soul arrive, she hastily ran over to them with a smile and said, “Seniors! My mistress wishes for me to bring you to the island we’re gathering at. We will then set off on our journey afterwards.”

Han Li nodded his head and wordlessly spit out his Green Brilliance Dagger. After wrapping the girl in the dagger’s light, he flew off.

Crooked Soul turned into a streak of yellow light and followed after them.

This seemed to be the young woman’s first time using a magic treasure to fly. Between occasionally giving Han Li some directions, she continuously gazed at Han Li’s swordlight with great curiosity. But whenever her gaze met Han Li’s, she bashfully turned her head away.

The young woman and Han Li were quite close within the sword light, almost touching each other. If Han Li slightly lowered his head, he would be able to see her white, flawless neck and smell the woman’s sweet fragrance, taking advantage of his minor amount of luck.

The woman seemed to have noticed this and her cheeks blushed a result, leaving Han Li feeling quite amused. He couldn’t help but wear a mysterious smile.

He had guessed that since Lady Fan sent her personal servant to guide his way, she was attempting to use a genuine beauty to entrap him as her bewitchment techniques had proven ineffective on him.

With that thought, he inwardly sneered and presumptuously took a deep whiff of the young woman’s scent, causing her to slightly tremble. Her delicate, white ears turned pink, and she appeared somewhat panicked.

However, Han Li’s imprudent actions stopped there, and he didn’t progress a single step further. The young woman eventually regained her calm and continued to give Han Li directions.

An hour later, Han Li descended onto a small barren, nameless island.

About a hundred meters away from the mountaintop, in addition to Lady Fan and Elder Zhao, there were over a dozen people sitting in meditation or whispering amongst themselves.

There were five Core Formation cultivators, and the others were late Foundation Establishment. It seemed that the Exquisite Sound Sect had spent quite a bit of their influence to gather this many people.

Upon seeing her servant arrive together with Han Li and Crooked Soul, Lady Fan couldn’t help but reveal happiness and hastily walked over with light steps.

“It is truly fortunate for our Sect that you two Seniors have agreed to come! Let me introduce you to the others!” The woman’s eyes appeared to be overflowing with emotion.

She introduced Han Li and Crooked Soul to a Core Formation cultivator surnamed Meng and four Foundation Establishment cultivators.

But what was baffling was that after Lady Fan introduced them to these people, as if in an attempt to demonstrate her power, she didn’t introduce them to the others.

Lady Fan looked at a pretty woman wearing lotus green clothing, and Han Li followed her gaze, realizing that the cultivators she hadn’t introduced to them appeared to be affiliated with the green clothed woman.

The woman had long eyebrows, upturned eyes, and a tall, slender nose. Her elegant eyes seemed to conceal a baleful aura. From a single glance, one could tell that she held a position of authority. However, her appearance aroused a desire to conquer her among men.

This woman coldly laughed after seeing Lady Fan, but she appeared slightly shocked upon seeing Han Li and Crooked Soul. She then turned around and whispered to a middle-aged cultivator behind her, not paying attention to Lady Fan in the slightest.

“Who is she?” Han Li asked with a calm expression.

Fan Jingmei gave a start before begrudgingly giving an answer, “Zhuo Ruting, our sect’s Envoy of the Right.”

“Hm.” Han Li couldn’t help but take another glance at this woman, much to the displeasure of Fan Jingmei.

Han Li didn’t have any unbecoming thoughts towards this Zhuo Ruting. He merely felt that the grace and appearance of this woman gave him a feeling of strong familiarity, and he couldn’t help but sink into contemplation.

Lady Fan grew sullen upon seeing this and turned to speak with Crooked Soul. However, Crooked Soul remained expressionless while she spoke and didn’t utter a single word in response, leaving her even gloomier.

Vetoed. The author is free to share his... discretions.

Chapter 404: A Deceptive Situation

The night quietly passed by.

Just as dawn broke, the cultivators silently appeared above the evil cultivators’ lair.

“It’s here?” Fairy Violet Spirit looked down at the small black island beneath her with confusion. The island was truly small and it only had a radius of about two kilometers. It would be more accurate to call this a huge reef.

“That’s right. Not only have the Golden Cicada Wasps arrived at this location, but the two elders have also confirmed it. Those evil cultivators are here.” Lady Fan softy said.

The violet-clothed woman then silently nodded her head and no longer held doubt.

However, this place was obviously a temporary hideout. Not only was the island pathetically small, but there was only an extremely simple illusion formation placed down that was basically worthless.

“Kill without hesitation!” After Fairy Violet Spirit coldly shouted her command, Eccentric Scarletflame’s bewildering laugh echoed out of his black cloud, easily wiping out their pathetic formation with resounding bolts of lighting. Afterwards the other cultivators bluntly rushed down.

The sound of their formation breaking had obviously alerted the people below.

Several sharp whistles sounded out from below. Fifty streaks of radiance flourished out, and a large number of cultivators met their advance. The three Core Formation cultivators leading them were surprised to see the Exquisite Sound Sect. But without waiting for their reply, Lady Fan yelled, “Strike!” She then released a silver wheel magic tool and took the initiative to attack.

When the other cultivators saw this, they bluntly followed her lead and attacked.

The sky was suddenly filled with flashes of radiance and deafening whistles.

Since Han Li was acting under the intention of acquiring the Heaven Lightning Bamboo, he naturally found it embarrassing to stay idle. As a result, he and Crooked Soul casually took out their magic treasures and tied down five Foundation Establishment cultivators, preparing to eliminate them in one blow.

As two Core Formation cultivators, they should’ve been able to easily deal with a small group of Foundation Establishment cultivators. However, something shocking had occurred.

When the five Foundation Cultivators discovered that two Core Formation cultivators were attacking them, their clothes were ripped away to reveal fiend demons. Han Li was shocked to the point that his eyes had nearly fallen out of his head despite having seen them before.

But even with their greatly increased cultivation and speed, Han Li was no longer a mere Foundation Establishment cultivator. They only managed to resist for a few moments more before Han Li and Crooked Soul turned them to ash with their magic treasures.

At this point, Han LI had discovered that their fiend demon transformations were different from that of the Black Fiend School. Not only did their transformations not require an incantation or cocoon, but an elemental blood core wasn’t present in their bodies.

Han Li felt extremely confused and puzzled. He pondered for a moment on whether or not they had some sort of relationship to the Black Fiend School. But he immediately dropped the thought and attentively looked in the other directions. Now was not the time to ponder these questions. It would be absurd if he allowed anyone to ambush him just because his thoughts were running astray.

However, what Han Li saw only made his doubts grow stronger. A majority of the evil Foundation Establishment cultivators had underwent a fiend demon transformation. In addition, they formed small groups and were fiercely fighting with all their might.

The three enemy Core Formation cultivators had earlier been restrained by Eccentric Scarletflame’s black cloud and were unable of escaping. Judging from the incessant rolls of thunder from the cloud, it seemed they were being quite strenuously held in place.

At the moment, the enemy’s several Core Formation cultivators and many Foundation Establishment cultivators had been reduced to under half of their original numbers in the blink of an eye. But even so, the remaining survivors still fearlessly fought on.

Their dauntless attitude had left many attacking Exquisite Sound Sect cultivators greatly astonished.

But at that moment, a fierce whistle pierced the air, leaving the Exquisite Sound Sect cultivators deafened for a moment. Everyone’s expressions had involuntarily changed.

“Why are you all standing still? Quickly kill them off! Something troublesome is about to arrive!” Eccentric Scarletflame’s words croaked out of his black cloud, waking the many cultivators from a daze and allowing them to continue their fierce attacks.

When the evil cultivators heard the sharp whistle, their spirits were greatly roused, becoming even more tenacious. For the time being, they were unable to be struck down.

In the following instant, several streaks of ash gray light arrived above the island.

When the Exquisite Sound Sect cultivators saw this, they stopped and stared at the five newly arrived Core formation cultivators with grave vigilance.

The large, middle-aged man leading them had an ashen complexion. Although his facial appearance was ordinary, he wore a menacing expression. His magic power fluctuations far exceeded that of his four allies and appeared to be late Core Formation. The other four were merely early Core Formation cultivators, but they gazed at the Exquisite Sound Sect cultivators with rage all the same.

“Who are you to dare slaughter the disciples of our Hidden Fiend Sect? We must repay this debt of blood!” His expression grew dark after seeing that there weren’t many of his disciples left.

The others were stunned. These bandits had no idea why they had come to pay them a visit and they actually spoke so boldly and righteously.

A few of the more quick witted individuals couldn’t help but look towards Fairy Violet Spirit, Lady Fan, and Zhuo Ruting with slight hesitation.

Fairy Violet Spirit clear, beautiful eyes revealed a trace of doubt and thought to say something before she was interrupted by a shout, “Stop your nonsense! You’ve committed crimes that cannot be repaid even with death!” Elder Zhao who had been closely following Lady Fan suddenly flew out from the crowd and waved his arm, releasing a three meter long streak of fiery light towards the enemy.

The middle-aged cultivator furiously grimaced and released an ash-gray devilish Qi with a boom. The huge forty-meter-tall aura of ash-gray Qi formed a huge misty ghost face in an instant.

As soon as the ghost face came into existence, it opened its mouth and fiercely charged forward.

Elder Zhao’s attack had disappeared within the huge mouth of the ghost face. The ghost face then charged towards Elder Zhao without pause.

Suddenly, Elder Zhao revealed panic and quickly blurred several times, returning to the group of allied cultivators at a speed much faster than when he had left them. He loudly yelled, “Everyone, act together! He is a late Core Formation cultivator. We don’t stand a chance if we fight alone!”

These obviously inciting words caused two Core Formation cultivators and a portion of the Foundation Establishment cultivators to immediately release their magic tools and treasures to strike the ghost face.

However, a majority of them detachedly gazed on with doubt. The scene appeared somewhat messy.

Having seen this, Han Li’s face slightly twitched, and he slowly slipped towards the back of the crowd along with Crooked Soul. The situation appeared discouraging. Although he didn’t know what was about to happen, Han Li thought to immediately distance himself from the coming danger.

“Don’t yet act! There is something strange about it!” The violet-clothed woman saw that something was amiss and coldly scolded the Exquisite Sound Sect disciples. However, the attacking Exquisite Sound Sect cultivators seemed to have ignored her and continued their focused attacks on the ghost face.

When Han Li saw this, his expression slightly shifted, and his heart felt heavy.

The enemy middle-aged cultivator wasn’t foolish and also saw that something was queer.

After some slight surprise, he decisively waved his hand towards the ghost head, causing it to release a strange hiss. It then opened its mouth and spat out countless ashen spheres of light. The magic tools and treasures that they struck suddenly swayed with instability. He took advantage of this opportunity to have the ghost head fly back towards him.

The attacking cultivators were stunned and didn’t dare to separate from the group to continue their attack.

“Can someone tell me what is going on?” Taking advantage of this opportunity, Fairy Violet Spirit flew out from the group and coldly asked while she stood in between both sides.

“What’s going on? You killed my sect disciples without cause and you ask their sect master?” The middle-aged man coldly said. His eyes had already turned to a shade of a peculiar dark green.

The violet-clothed woman emotionlessly met his gaze as she slowly asked, “Were you the ones who robbed our Exquisite Sound Sect and killed our sect master?”

The middle aged man responded with a furious tone, “Preposterous! Our Hidden Fiend School has always had very few dealings with outsiders. Why would we do such a contemptuous thing?”

When the violet-clothed woman heard this, she grew silent and her eyes became ice-cold.

When the others heard this, they seemed to realize something, and their expressions became strange.

Lady Fan suddenly emerged from the group and slowly proclaimed, “It seems that we’ve fallen into someone’s trap!”

“Humph! Was it you that have fallen into a trap or was it us?” The middle-aged man eerily spoke with a resentful expression.

The disciples that he had spent such a great number of years nurturing had all died within a day. It was impossible for him to not feel vehement hatred towards them.

Were it not for the fact that the Exquisite Sound Sect possessed too many Core Formation cultivators and the uncertainty he held towards the strange cultivator within the black cloud, he would’ve used the entirety of his strength to heavily wound them despite knowing he had fallen into someone else’s trap.

As the violet-clothed woman’s gaze became completely void of emotion, Lady Fan waited from the side with a bitter smile.

“Elder Zhao, Elder Fu. How about you give us an explanation?” Fairy Violet Spirit slowly turned around and focused her attention on two people within the group.

Alternative Title

Chapter 419: Ancient Treasure

After the formation flags and plates were appropriately arranged, Han Li took a deep breath and was about to cast a technique before being interrupted by the sounds of whistles coming from the horizon. A blue radiance flashed through the horizon followed by a blue streak resembling a flood dragon quickly flying across the ocean. In the blink of an eye, it arrived above them.

Once the light faded away, an eccentric wearing dual swords on his back was revealed.

Upon seeing his appearance, the others were startled. Above them hovered a shriveled and thin figure, with a red, rash covered face, and fierce, triangular eyes framed by long, messy white hair. This odd looking man wore a black short sleeved shirt with a strange flower basket hanging from his waist. From his Spiritual Qi fluctuations, it appeared he was a mid Core Formation cultivator.

After getting a clear view of the area, the eccentric was surprised to see so many Core Formation cultivators. But after his gaze fell onto the red light barrier and Han Li’s formation setup tools, his expression greatly changed.

“Are you Juniors seeking death? You dare to take advantage of this island lord’s absence to pry into his project? Hurry up and get off this island!” The eccentric yelled with an ominous glare.

“Island lord?”

“This is yours?”

Hu Yue and Jin Qing looked at one another for a moment while Han Li and the others were at an even greater loss.

This wasn’t an uninhabited island?

Hu Yue frowned and calmly asked, “Fellow Daoist is the lord of this island?”

“Obviously! I have already been this island’s lord for several hundred years.” The eccentric replied without a trace of politeness.

“That’s odd, my Brother Jin and I never caught a single glimpse of you on our last trip here!” Hu Yue stated in a calm manner.

“What? You’ve already come here once? Humph! It’s the same as the current situation. You came here while I was preoccupied with matters off the island.” The eccentric glared at them with even greater anger.

Hu Yue sneered and derisively said, “So you’re saying that you are the sole inhabitant of this island? Then your esteemed title of island lord is self conferred.”

As the restriction before him was about be eliminated, Hu Yue was unwilling to pay any attention to the eccentric before him.

“Humph! Stop equivocating! In any case, you’ve performed the grave crime of destroying these restrictions. Since you don’t wish to leave, then I will help you remain here permanently!”

Suddenly, the wicker basket on his waist turned into a streak of chilling white Qi, shooting straight towards Hu Yue.

This time, Han Li and the others were the ones to be surprised.

Had this person gone mad? Did he not see how many Core Formation cultivators they had on their side? Was his mind addled?

Hu Yue responded in furious alarm. With a wave of his sleeve two red lights shot straight towards the incoming white mist. With a muffled peng, the white mist was scattered and dissipated in every direction.

“It seems this dog’s bark is bigger than his bite!” Hu Yue relaxed upon seeing the mist scatter and bluntly made some cutting remarks.

The eccentric remained silent but strangely smiled.

Hu Yue’s heart trembled and his expression suddenly changed, before yelling, “What’s going on? My flying knives!”

After breaking the white Qi transformed from the basket, the two flying knives were tottering in their original place as if they were failing.

Afterwards, the scattered white Qi quickly reassembled itself, and with a flash of radiance, it reformed back into its appearance as a flower basket. The two flying knives were trapped inside the flower basket while enveloped in the white Qi, incapable of breaking free.

Hu Yue looked on in disbelief as his magic treasure was restrained. The other’s also paled in response.

However, the eccentric didn’t give them any time to think. He coldly laughed and his shoulders flashed with light. Shooting down two streaks of grey swordlight towards Hu Yue.

As he was next to Hu Yue, Jin Qing naturally found it embarrassing to just stand idle. He flicked his hand and threw out a small block stamp which grew larger as it smashed towards the grey light.

With a clap of thunder, the three magic treasures released brilliant flashes of interwoven colors.

At that moment, the cultivator surnamed Jian looked at Han Li and Crooked soul before silently raising his hand, and shooting a pitchfork glowing with black and white Qi towards the eccentric.

Han Li inwardly sighed. Since everyone else had acted, he and Crooked Soul could no longer just stand idle and had to join them against the eccentric. With that thought, Han Li and Crooked Soul released their Immemorial Bowl and Green Brilliant Dagger, sending them into the fray.

When the eccentric saw this, he didn’t reveal any fear. Instead he bellowed in savage laughter and spat out a pearl of black blood towards their magic treasures.

A huge series of explosions rang out!

Greatly going against their expectations, the bead had released a black radiance just as their magic treasures touched the bead and exploded, causing great spiritual damage to the magic treasures and all of their lights to immediately dim.

The cultivator surnamed Jian felt great heartache and appeared extremely regretful. His hands formed into an incantation seal to retrieve the flying pitchfork. From that strike, he would need to nurture it in his primal soul for about a year before recovering to normal.

However, he was late in retrieving his magic treasure.

As the eccentric coldly laughed, his wicker basket flashed with white light and suddenly shot towards the magic treasures in a streak of white light, entrapping them within.

The cultivator surnamed Jian suddenly thought of something upon seeing this and yelled out in despair, “An Ancient Treasure! You’re using an Ancient Treasure!”

Han Li was stunned upon seeing this. An “Ancient Treasure” was in fact a magic treasure refined by ancient cultivators. This type of magic treasure had a single divine ability, but it’s power was immense and incomparable to the power of common magic treasures of the present. The magic treasure refinement methods and the materials of Ancient Treasures were substantially different from those of the present. Their treasures were incapable of being withdrawn into the body and could only be carried physically like a magic tool.

This was also the only method of differentiating the Ancient Treasure from common magic treasures.

Having now seen the abnormality of the flower basket and recalling that the basket had been hanging from his waist at the start, it was impossible for him to not realize the true identity of this magic treasure.

As for the “Heaven Opposing Spears” that were used on the Infant Carp Beast used by the Six United Palaces, they were also Ancient Treasures that had been passed down.

Although Han Li was somewhat startled by the announcement of this ancient treasure, he had many killing moves up his sleeves. Still, he didn’t take the initiative to act as he was convinced the more tricks he kept hidden for later, the easier it would be to effectively deal with the upcoming moments of danger.

In addition, he clearly understood that even if the enemy had an ancient treasure, he wouldn’t be able to easily deal with so many allied Core Formation cultivators. It would suffice to only display the ability equivalent to a common Core Formation cultivator.

With that thought, apart from using the entirety of their control to wrench their magic treasures away from the white Qi, Han Li and Crooked Soul didn’t take any unusual actions and watched on with a detached gaze.

He was confident that someone else would inevitably take the initiative!

As he had expected, Hu Yue and the others revealed a trace of joy upon hearing that the flower basket was an ancient treasure. Since the eccentric had taken the first move, it was only proper for them to loot the treasure after they joined hands and exterminated him.

Thus, after a moment of hesitation, the cultivator surnamed Jian formed an incantation gesture with his hands, causing three streaks of black light to emerge from his storage pouch: three-meter-tall black banners with a murderous aura.

He then opened his mouth, shooting out a thread of black Qi towards the black banners. The banners released a series of ghostly wails, causing the other cultivators to become shaken and overwhelmed.

Meanwhile, Hu Yue bluntly abandoned his attempts to regain control of his flying knives and twisted his hands together, releasing a burst of thunderous azure lightning strikes.

With raised eyebrows, Jin Qing suddenly cast a magic seal towards his magic treasure, causing his white block stamp to release a dragon’s cry and increase in size several times over.

Having seen the three make such great displays of might, Han Li inwardly grinned and reckoned that the eccentric was about to suffer a great blow.

But despite displaying slight surprise upon seeing the three’s vicious attacks, his sneer soon returned. He tore off his short sleeved shirt and revealed his bare upper body.

Han Li nearly bit his own tongue in surprise.

Aside from his shriveled chest, two fist-sized human skulls were biting down on each side of his abdomen. Each of the skulls were jet-black and had long, messy hair. In addition, the skulls wriggled incessantly as if they were alive.

At that moment, the thunderous azure lightning and the three black banners had entered the eccentric’s sight. He lightly extended two of his fingers and started to speak an odd incantation.

The two human skulls began to release low, muffled sobs before flying away from his abdomen and biting off the eccentric’s two extended fingers. They then excitedly charged forward to meet the thunderous lightning and the black banners.

Chapter 422: Sevenglow Lotus

The Spirit Sealing Pillar was actually a huge magic tool used by ancient cultivators to seal the nearby Spiritual Qi and isolate it from the outside the world. This rarely seen magic tool was typically used in one of two ways.

One purpose was to seal extremely rare spirit medicines and spirit herbs, preventing their spiritual nature from weakening due to outside exposure. Another purpose was to suppress particularly formidable ghost spirits or devils and prevent them from escaping. Regardless of which purpose this particular Spirit Sealing Pillar served, its value would prove to be extremely significant to Han Li and company.

Spirit medicines have their obvious uses, but if the Spirit Sealing Pillar was suppressing devils, they would prove to be optimal materials for increasing the strength of one’s magic treasure by subduing and containing them within their magic treasures.

However, they clearly understood that if the Spirit Seal Pillar was used to seal a spirit or a devil it was guaranteed to be difficult for them to subdue it after it was released. There was even a chance that it would cause backlash instead.

Although everyone looked at each other with pleasant surprise, nobody brashly suggested immediately toppling the pillar to see what was underneath.

After a long while of silence, Jin Qing bitterly laughed and muttered, “This is quite the conundrum! But since we’ve spent quite a bit of effort, nobody wishes to turn back, yes?”

“If you want to leave, then leave! I will be staying here! Don’t say that there might not be devils within. We must be ready to attempt to subdue whatever is inside.” Cultivator Jian coldly spoke with his hands behind his back.

Jin Qing smiled in response and turned towards Hu Yue and asked, “How about you, Fellow Daoist Hu?”

After muttering to himself for a moment, Hu Yue gave a resolute answer, “Fellow Daoist, you should know that because us rogue cultivators are unwilling to be restricted by others, our freedom comes at the cost of poverty. We must seize every opportunity we are given!”

Jin Qing didn’t reveal any surprise and turned his gaze to Han Li.

With a raised brow, Han Li indifferently said, “I am indifferent. If a majority wishes to see what is underneath, I will stay as well.” Since he now had seventy-two Bamboo Azurecloud Swords refined from Gold Lightning Bamboo, he had nothing to fear from demons and ghosts.

“Don’t bother asking me. Although I am only a Foundation Establishment cultivator, my father fortuitously gave me a devil repelling magic treasure. Even if I lack the strength to protect myself, no harm will come to me.” Without waiting for Jin Qing to ask her, Shi Die took the initiative to answer after tilting her head.

“Alright! Since everyone is unwilling to return empty handed, let’s push the pillar over. Even so, please be careful!” Jin Qing lightly sighed and spoke with a cautious expression.

“Hehe! There is no need for Fellow Daoist Jin’s warning as nobody here is willing to treat their lives lightly. But still, let’s get the ugly matters out of the way first. If any devils or ghosts appear, then the subduer will have the right of ownership. Fighting over them is forbidden.” Cultivator Jian slowly spoke with a strange glint flashing from his eyes.

“That is obvious. It is only natural to yield in accordance to skill, considering the bounty’s nature,” Jin Qing spoke in agreement.

The others didn’t have any objections.

When cultivator Jian saw this, his spirit was roused, and he revealed a trace of joy.

Shi Die shot him a sideways glance and mysteriously smiled, asking, “Could it be that fellow Daoist has a special method to subdue devils? Is that why you’re so confident?”

“That’s... I won’t conceal this from you all. My cultivation art has a divine ability specialized in dealing with ghosts and devils. I had originally believed it wouldn’t be of much use, and I didn’t expect that I would be able to finally make use of it.” After some slight hesitation, cultivator Jian nodded and gave a straightforward explanation.

“The skulls of the wicked eccentric that Han Li had exterminated seemed to be refined from demons. It seemed that Fellow Daoist Jian had quite a bit of trouble with them?” Shi Die spoke with doubt.

“Sigh, it seems my poor performance has caused doubt. My divine ability requires prior preparation in order to be utilized. That wicked eccentric had caught me unprepared, and as a result, I made for a sorry sight.” Cultivator Jian shook his head and explained with slight embarrassment.

Shi Die nodded and turned her gaze back towards the Spirit Sealing Pillar.

“Since everyone is unwilling to give up, let’s start! It is a bit troublesome to overthrow a Spirit Sealing Pillar as it can only be released after turning it several times with great force.” Shi Die excitedly explained.

When the others heard this, they narrowed their eyes. Although they were cultivators, they didn’t actually possess much physical strength. Even with immense strength talismans, the group wouldn’t be able to physically shift such a huge stone pillar.

Han Li frowned and inwardly sent out a command.

As Crooked Soul walked towards the stone pillar, he said in a deep voice, “Let me do it. I have quite a bit of strength.”

Hu Yue and the others revealed slight amazement. After all, Crooked Soul had yet to speak since arriving here, but now suddenly he took the initiative to solve this matter.

“Then we will have to trouble Fellow Daoist Crooked Soul!” Shi Die said with curiosity.

Crooked Soul continued to walk towards the stone pillar as if he hadn’t heard her. His body first flashed with yellow light before he placed an immense strength talisman on his body. Afterwards, he rolled up his sleeves, took a deep breath, and clasped the stone pillar in his arms.

The ten meter tall stone pillar released a rumbling noise and started to turn bit by bit, much to the delight of the others.

Crooked Soul’s thick, taut arms were completely exposed and shined faintly of red light. After the stone pillar had been turned three times, he used all of his strength to push the pillar to the side before suddenly moving away.

The stone pillar fell to the side with a series of booms, causing the ground to tremble for a moment. From the deep groove it left behind when landing, it was clear that the stone pillar was extremely heavy.

However, the others didn’t pay any attention to the stone pillar, and instead focused their attention on the large hole left behind from its collapse.

The hole was pitch-black and from it blew a cold wind, but it also had a flight of small white stairs that led downward.

“Let’s go!” After looking at the hole for a moment, cultivator Jian decided to take the lead.

After some hesitation, the others followed after him. Now that they’ve made it this far, no one was willing to turn tail.

Han Li stood in his original spot with a single hand grasping his chin with a contemplative expression as he watched the other cultivators climb down the stairs with barely concealed excitement.

He then took out the scroll painting with the sparkling red light and fiddled with it.

He pondered for a moment while he looked at it before putting it away and climbing down the stairs. Crooked Soul closely followed after him.

The tunnel was rather deep. After a quarter hour, Han Li finally reached the bottom.

Their eyes brightened upon seeing a large hall that spanned over seventy meters appear before them. The hall’s roof was embedded with fist-sized luminescent pearls causing the hall to shine with milky-white light. As the walls were sparkling with bits of light, this exceptionally beautiful sight appeared to be caused by magic techniques.

In addition, there were two semi-circle doors to the side of the hall’s entrance that led to an unknown location.

Hu Yue and the others stood motionlessly at the center of the hall. They were all staring in the same direction and occasionally whispered to each other as if they were studying something.

Han Li walked towards them in large strides with great curiosity.

“What’s that?” Han Li revealed astonishment after catching sight of what they were staring at.

There was a flawlessly white skeleton that was reclined at the side of a small pond. An emerald-green, foot-long arrow penetrated its skull and nailed it to the ground, appearing quite strange.

But that had only caught their initial gaze. Afterwards, their focus had been excitedly drawn towards the three-colored lotus floating at the center of the pond’s surface.

Although the colorful lotus had yet to bloom and was still just a bud, it was the size of a bowl and glowed with a tri-colored radiance of azure, red, and yellow.

But what was most inconceivable about it was the exquisite rainbow that appeared several inches above it. Its glistening light was extremely entrancing.

Additionally, the pond water wasn’t ordinary water; it was a dense white paste that strongly emitted a strange fragrance.

“A Sevenglow Lotus! It has to be. I thought that this only existed in legend. That water... is it the legendary thousand year stone milk?” Hu Yue muttered to himself with widened eyes.

“No wonder there were so many formation spell restrictions placed down along with the Spirit Sealing Pillar. With these two items, setting down another dozen layers of restrictions wouldn’t be excessive.” Shi Die stated while mesmerized by the colorful lotus.

Jin Qing woke from his surprise and turned to look at the skeleton. He bafflingly asked, “But what about this skeleton? Could it have been the cave residence’s master?”

“Why does it matter? We’ve struck it rich! Although this Sevenglow Lotus only shines with three colors, it will still sell for an exorbitant price at auction.” Cultivator Jian directly changed the subject with greed filling his eyes.

Chapter 427: Profound Soul Demonification

Han Li quickly took out a blue talisman from his storage pouch and gently slapped it onto his wound. With a flash of white light, the bleeding immediately stopped.

But when he turned his head back to meet Crooked Soul’s icy gaze, Han Li wordlessly emitted an azure light around his body, which reached ten meters in height, and had his emerald swords revolve around him in streaks. It all appeared blindingly bright.

Han Li had already made a firm resolution that if he were going to leave this place, he needed to have these Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords outside his body to protect against any tricks this ancient eccentric may have in store.

To tell the truth, this was the most fearsome, menacing enemy he had encountered since entering the cultivation world. If his reactions were the slightest bit slow, he would’ve already had a hole through his heart. Were his spiritual sense not stronger and his mind not nimbler than a common cultivators, he would’ve undoubtedly met certain death from Crooked Soul’s recent ambush.

The Blood Spirit Drill was truly vicious and sinister. It could hardly be blocked.

But now, Han Li didn’t have to worry about any further attacks from the Blood Spirit Drill. That last attack was the last charge that Crooked Soul had cultivated.

However, Han Li still felt incredibly gloomy.

According to the External Incarnation Technique, he clearly should have refined his spiritual sense fragment and Crooked Soul’s physical body into one. Just how had this old ghost been able to take control of Crooked Soul without his knowledge?

He wasn’t even given the slightest warning. Were if not for his quick wits in hastily retrieving his divided consciousness from Crooked Soul, he feared the shadow would’ve already used it as a method for consuming him.

Han Li now found himself in a truly troublesome situation.

Since the enemy had possessed Crooked Soul, then the green shadow must be deceased and was closer to an evil demonic spirit or primal soul. The shadow possessing Crooked Soul wasn’t necessarily a bad thing, and it may have quite possibly given Han Li the opportunity to exterminate him.

With that thought, Han Li flipped his hand and an exquisitely-crafted small brass bell appeared in his hand: the Spirit Guiding Bell he had kept stored away for so long.

This bell contained the blood essence of Crooked Soul’s physical body. Although he couldn’t count on it to arrest the enemy, it could still be used to create an advantageous opportunity!

At that moment, “Crooked Soul” was stretching and moving his body as if wanting to familiarize himself with it.

Having seen Han Li’s action, he eerily chucked as if the result of the coming battle were laid in stone.

Han Li’s expression darkened, and he no longer hesitated to ring the small bell.

With a series of clear bell rings, Crooked Soul’s red eyes flickered, but no other change occurred from his body as if nothing was wrong.

Han Li’s heart sunk.

“Regardless of what tricks you perform on this Fiend Core Avatar, since I’ve become the master of this body, do you believe that minor restriction will have an effect one me?” Crooked Soul’s rough voice slowly spoke with a mocking tone.

“You know that it is a Fiend Core Avatar?” Han Li’s heart stirred with surprise.

“Hehe! The Fiend Core and External Incarnation Technique were something I had originally passed down to my two traitorous disciples. Did you believe I wouldn’t see through them? You sure are courageous to use them in front of me! Could it be that your master didn’t warn you that so long as this secret technique was used to refine an avatar, that I would be able to easily control it?” Crooked Soul twisted his neck left and right and indifferently said with crossed arms.

Han Li was bewildered, but his face wore a strange expression.

“What master? The avatar creation technique was something I acquired from a jade talisman. Could it have some relation to you?” Han Li asked, unwilling to be a scapegoat for Grandmaster Zenith Yin. Regardless of whether his words were true or false, Han Li still gave a dull explanation.

“Jade slip? Youngster, did you believe that by not admitting to be the apprentice of my two traitorous disciples that I would let you go? After I capture you, I will refine your soul and acquire everything that I want to know.” Crooked Soul didn’t seem to believe Han Li and spoke expressionlessly.

With that said, he beckoned to the skeleton pile nearby without further hesitation, causing it to float in the air. In an instant, it reassembled into a complete skeleton, and flew towards Crooked Soul with a flash of white light.

Although Han Li didn’t know what he intended, he wasn’t going to allow his opponent to smoothly succeed.

He immediately flicked his finger three times, shooting out three streaks of azure swordlight from his hand. The Azure Essence Swordstreaks shot straight towards the skeleton.

“You dare to so presumptuously release those granules of light?” Crooked Soul sinisterly said. He then opened his mouth and spouted out a beam of blood light.

With a series of explosions, the blood light and the azure light struck and scattered into radiance.

Han Li frowned and wore a solemn expression. After being possessed, Crooked Soul’s cultivation was no longer restricted to early Core Formation stage. How truly odd!

But what happened next left Han Li even more aghast!

Once the white skeleton flew in front of Crooked Soul, it merged into his body without the slightest obstruction.

Crooked Soul then loudly roared with his head facing upwards. His body emitted several different flashes of colors: from dark-green otherworldly flame, pitch-black ghost mist, and Crooked Soul’s Divine Blood Light. These three distinct radiances tangled with one another, continuously wandering throughout Crooked Soul’s body and fully covering him within it.

As Crooked Soul roared, a small explosion could be heard from within his body. With his body bowed in pain, his limbs and body began to slowly shrink.

Once this was done, he stood up appearing much shorter, exactly like an ordinary person.

But what caused Han Li to be most shocked was Crooked Soul’s face had changed to that of a youth’s with delicate facial features. Even the flourishing blood-red in his eyes had greatly dimmed. In that instant, Crooked Soul had undergone a transformation into a completely different person.

Han Li was stupefied for a moment before revealing a bitter smile.

Han Li originally wished to used this opportunity to strike his opponent given how audaciously he used magic in front of him, but he didn’t expect that this technique would be performed so quickly that there wasn’t an opportunity to make use of.

After a moment of silence, Han Li dryly asked the youth a bizarre question, “Is this possession? Or complete body seizure?”

The delicate youth mysteriously smiled and glanced at Han Li with narrowed eyes, serenely saying, “ You greatly underestimate my Profound Soul Demonification Technique. It is a secret art that only a Nascent Soul cultivator is capable of performing. So long as it is cultivated, there are no restrictions with body seizure, and profound souls may be added to another body as one wishes. Now that my profound soul has solidified its bones, I will have you be a blood sacrifice so that this Divine Ancestor may rise once again!”

He raised his hands, suddenly turning his fingers into incisive claws with dark green fingernails several inches longs.

Han Li’s expression darkened, and he didn’t further waste his breath. He tossed out the spirit beast pouch that he had been holding since the beginning and released his several thousands of Gold Devouring Beetles. A short moment later, a glowing cloud of gold and silver floated above his head.

Then with a wave of his arms, white lights continuously flickered around him, surrounding Han Li with forty huge ape puppets. Each of them stared at the youth with an icy gaze.

But Han Li didn’t stop there. With his two hands forming an incantation seal, his nine small swords flew out as azure light and converged into a three-meter-long emerald sword. The sword streak endlessly twinkled with faint golden arcs of light continuously sparking from it.

Upon seeing this, the delicate youth’s expression greatly changed, revealing surprise and a grave expression.

After the youth’s gaze flickered several times, he suddenly said, “Flying swords refined from Heaven Lightning Bamboo, insect control techniques, and puppets! It seems you really aren’t the disciple of Zenith Yin and Zenith Brilliance. Since this is the case, then how about we have a proper chat?”

Han Li, who had just prepared his entire offensive, was stunned upon hearing this. But after a moment of silence, he coldly said, “Unfortunately, I really want to test whether or not your esteemed self is capable of receiving my flying swords!”

Without the slightest hesitation, Han Li pointed towards his huge flying sword, and it immediately launched towards the youth in a green streak of light as thick as a python. As it flew, it occasionally rolled with sounds of thunder.

The youth’s face slightly sank upon seeing this, and he lightly waved his claws in front of him. Five crescents of black radiance appeared out of the air and rapidly expanded, blurring several times before quickly chopping towards the green sword streak.

Upon contact, the green sword streak sparked with faint golden arcs of lightning, completely obliterating the crescents of black radiance. They weren’t able to withstand even a single blow!

Although the youth’s expression remained calm, his mind was greatly startled. The power of the Gold Lightning Bamboo was far greater than he had anticipated.

In the blink of an eye, the green sword streak had arrived in front of the youth. However, he was still calm and collected as he indifferently watched the huge sword approach him as if he still had something up his sleeve.

Chapter 430: Wen Siyue

Han Li was startled by her yell and he couldn’t help but look over and examine the woman.

“You’re a disciple of the Exquisite Sound Sect?” Han Li asked with a calm expression.

The young woman appeared to be about twenty years of age and had a face of soft jade with skin as fair as snow. Her flowery expression of pleasant surprise revealed a very sweet charm.

“Disciple Wen Siyue pays her respect to Elder Han!” This lovely young woman hastily flew to Han Li’s side and respectfully gave him a bow. Her body wasn't lacking in neither grace, given her firm chest and ample bottom. In addition to the young woman’s sweet voice, he could detect an intoxicatingly sweet fragrance from her.

Han Li calmly sized her up and slowly asked, “How did you recognize me? Have I seen you before?” Han Li felt slightly puzzled as he was certain that this was the first time he had seen her.

“Although this is the first time Junior has paid her respects to Senior, the sect master hung several of Senior’s portraits in the offerings hall. I’ve seen them every time I passed by.” The young woman respectfully said.

Han Li was stunned and didn’t know whether he should laugh or cry. He didn’t think that those three woman from the Exquisite Sound Sect would actually do something like this. This must be one of their method of disseminating the fact that he had become the Exquisite Sound Sect’s elder.

Despite feeling slightly gloomy, his face didn’t reveal the slightest peculiarity, and he turned his gaze towards the middle-aged man to the side, and spoke with a slight smile, “Brother Wen, I haven’t seen you in so many years. It seems you’re doing well!”

Ever since the middle-aged man saw Han LI, his face had appeared odd. Now, his expression had become even more complicated. When he looked at Han Li, his gaze seemed to contain both admiration and a feeling of self-inferiority.

“I didn’t expect that Senior Han would still recognize me. Although I’ve seen your portrait at the Exquisite Sound Sect, I didn’t dare to believe it given that so much time had passed. Congratulations on Senior’s Core Formation.” He spoke with slight bitterness.

This middle-aged man was actually the youth Wen Qiang that Han LI originally met at Stalwart Star Island.

Although his appearance resembled that of his youth, his hair was now growing white, and his face showed signs of aging. It seemed he was on the verge of appearing elderly.

“There is no need for Brother Wen to call me Senior. After all, we were acquainted when we were still of the same generation!” Han Li spoke with a smile.

Han Li saw that Wen Qiang was only at mid Foundation Establishment and wouldn’t have any hope of Core Formation. Han Li couldn’t help but inwardly sigh upon seeing a youth at his prime had become so elderly.

In truth, even if Wen Siyue didn’t yell for him to stop, he would’ve done so anyways. With his outstanding memory, he would’ve recognized Wen Qiang from a single glance despite not having met him many times. As he had originally given Han Li a good impression, it was only natural for Han Li to lend him aid in passing and not stand by and watch him die.

After hearing Han Li, Wen Qiang stated that he didn’t dare to do so. Han Li could only follow suit.

When the young woman heard the two chatting, her mouth slightly widened from alarm.

Her soft, spirited eyes blinked several times, wanting to ask something. But she was interrupted when Han Li spoke with a cold voice towards the three enemies, “Where do you three think you’re going? Did I say you could leave?”

The three enemy cultivators were panic stricken upon seeing a hostile Core Formation cultivator arrive. But after seeing that Han Li didn’t seem to mind them and was happily chatting, they couldn’t help but slowly fall back and test their luck.

The three turned deathly white upon hearing Han Li. After exchanging a mutual glance, they immediately flew off on their magic tools with defensive magic tools and barriers of all colors at their side.

“Humph! You’re courting death!” Han Li coldly snorted and lightly flicked his finger, shooting out three brilliant streaks of azure light, appearing behind them in a single instant.

Pff. Pff. The three cultivator’s magic tools and defensive barriers were shredded through like paper by the thick swordlights. With three simultaneous miserable screams, their magic tools filled the sky with fluorescent lights before disappearing without a trace.

After the young woman and Wen Qiang watched Han Li’s extermination of the three Poison Dragon Union cultivators, they couldn’t help but look at Han Li with even greater respect.

Han Li inwardly nodded his head. While these three azure essence swordstreaks appeared unremarkable, they actually consumed a significant amount of spiritual power. Regardless, Han Li was quite satisfied as they were able to kill Foundation Establishment cultivators in a single strike. It seemed that the azure essence swordstreaks had increased in power along with his cultivation.

Han Li seemed to have thought of something and asked, “Ah, that’s right. Since you both have the surname Wen, does that mean...”

When Wen Qiang heard Han Li, his face revealed embarrassment, and he replied, “Senior Han jests. Siyue is my daughter.”

Han Li was stunned, but soon burst into laughter, “Then I must congratulate Brother Wen! Fellow Daoist Siyue has reached Foundation Establishment at such a young age. Perhaps she will one day reach Core Formation as well!”

Having heard that, Wen Qiang laughed with a prideful expression, “I won’t conceal this from Senior Han. Siyue is truly my pride. She became Foundation Establishment after only a little more than twenty years. I have high hopes for her. While I won’t be progressing any further, I can only hope for her to travel farther than I ever did.”

Wen Qiang then looked at the young woman with a tender expression, causing Siyue to turn her head away in embarrassment.

Han Li looked at the young woman with a smile and faintly nodded his head. Wen Siyue was gifted with remarkable aptitude.

Afterwards, Wen Qiang and Han Li each spoke about their own experiences.

Although they didn’t have a particularly deep friendship, meeting an old friend after many years of separation was always a pleasant matter.

From their excited chat, Han Li heard a story that was not uncommon to cultivators with mediocre aptitudes throughout the Scattered Star Seas.

Not long after Han Li departed, Wen Qiang’s master had met the end of his lifespan during cultivation. After muddling around Stalwart Star Island for several tens of years, he managed to barely breakthrough to the Foundation Establishment stage. After that, he started to wander through all sorts of islands and accumulated experience. Then after sometime, he met a female disciple from the Exquisite Sound Sect and became one of their external affairs disciples.

From then on, he handled all sorts of miscellaneous tasks for the Exquisite Sound Sect. But shortly after his daughter Siyue was born, his wife died from a strange illness. Due to his deep love for his wife, he decided not to remarry and raised Wen Siyue by himself. Naturally, she had been brought in to be a disciple of the Exquisite Sound Sect.

Having heard this, Han Li inwardly sighed several times and bitterly laughed. In contrast, his own experiences were quite simple. Apart from cultivation, there was practically nothing for him to talk about.

But in the end, Han Li asked the father-daughter pair why they were fighting at this remote place. In response, Wen Qiang appeared furious while his daughter appeared sad.

Han Li was greatly baffled by this.

After some hesitation, Wen Qiang slowly gave an explanation.

When Wen Siyue grew to adulthood, she was to marry a young cultivator with limitless prospects and become his Dao companion. Unfortunately, the young cultivator perished in a fight against other cultivators shortly after they were wed.

As such, the newly available and charming Wen Siyue attracted the eyes of many male cultivators in the sect. But as Wen Siyue was just recently widowed, she didn’t wish to quickly remarry. As such, she turned down her many requests for pair cultivation. Consequently, she unconsciously offended a high ranker in the Exquisite Sound Sect and was assigned to a dangerous and strenuous task: she had to retrieve a precious material from within the Poison Dragon Union’s territory.

With his daughter in such a dangerous situation, Wen Qiang naturally couldn’t stand idly by and instead accompanied his daughter on the journey. However, their secret tasks had been discovered by the Poison Dragon Union at an unknown time through unknown means. As a result, the father-daughter pair had been chased down by three Poison Dragon Union cultivators and were forced to fight with their lives on the line.

If chance had not brought Han Li by them, they were certain to have met a horrible end.

Upon hearing Wen Qiang’s indignant words, Han Li stroked his chin and remained silent for a long while. Wen Qiang’s words implied that he wanted Han Li to seek justice on their behalf.

However, this was only one side of the story, and he wasn’t willing to recklessly involve himself in the internal affairs of the Exquisite Sound Sect over such a shallow friendship.

If you want to remember she ever existed, you'd better remember that she was beautiful.

Chapter 434: Gathering

Fewer and fewer cultivators arrived until many days later when the gradual flow ceased.

However, Grandmaster Zenith Yin and the old Confucian scholar were sitting in silence with solemn expressions. They would occasionally sweep their gaze across the room as if they were waiting for something.

‘Could they be waiting for Man Huzi?” Han Li naturally noticed this and was very curious. As such, he also kept an eye out.

When afternoon arrived, footsteps could be heard from the entrance of the hall. With several flashes of blue radiance, two people walked into the hall one at a time. One of them was an old Daoist with a reddish complexion, and the other was an old man dressed as a farmer with a bitter expression on his thin, dark face.

After these two appeared, the cultivators in the hall became restless. A majority of people looked at the two with a trace of respect.

It seemed these two were quite famous.

Grandmaster Zenith Yin and the old Confucian scholar looked at them with ill intent. Grandmaster Zenith Yin’s expression was particularly harsh.

The two newly arrived experts returned the other party’s hostile gazes upon seeing them. The old Daoist snorted and said, “Old Devil Zenith Yin! You’ve arrived quite early. It seems you of the Devil Dao are quite determined to come out on top during this Heavenvoid Hall.”

“Tian Wuzi [1] ! It isn’t that this Grandmaster arrived early but you hypocrites arrived far too late. As I was of the opinion that your map fragment’s information was false, I wasn’t expecting you to arrive. This also good. This Grandmaster now has the opportunity to surpass you.” Grandmaster Zenith Yin responded with a sinister expression.

“Who is it that you think you’re going to surpass, Zenith Yin? Please, enlighten us!” Without waiting for the old Daoist to strike back, another voice resounded throughout the hall.

When Zenith Yin and the old Confucian scholar heard the new voice, their expressions greatly changed. The taciturn beautiful woman suddenly raised her head and coldly spoke while staring at the hall’s entrance.

“Wan Tianming [2] , you’ve arrived!”

“It seems Lady Wen has also arrived. Why does my appearance surprise you?” After this was said, a blur shot in from the outside and revealed a middle-aged man with a violet robe and jade belt.

This person had a squarish face and a large brow with white shiny teeth. He indifferently glanced at the beautiful woman before turning his gaze towards Grandmaster Zenith Yin. His very presence exuded an imposing aura.

Grandmaster Zenith Yin shut his lips with an eerie expression and remained silent in response to this man’s blunt gaze.

This greatly shocked Han Li. He couldn’t help but closely examine the new arrivals. Han Li bewilderedly guessed that since an early Nascent Soul cultivator such as Grandmaster Zenith Yin was somewhat fearful of them, this person must be a mid Nascent Soul cultivator!

From what he saw, the three new arrivals should be cultivators of the Scattered Star Seas’ Righteous Dao. As for Zenith Yin and the others, they should be of the Devilish Dao.

The earlier restlessness of the hall had been immediately quelled by the middle-aged man’s arrival. Only the faint whispering of “Sect Master of the Myriad Gates of Enlightenment” could be heard.

Obviously, the middle-aged man seemed to have a higher status when compared to the other two.

“Wan Tianming, was my sword attendant injured by one of your disciples?” The beautiful woman surnamed Wen asked this question without restraint as if fearless of this person.

“That is obviously untrue. It was just that my sect’s disciples saw that your sword attendant’s cultivation was quite good and they merely wanted to swap pointers. Could it be that Lady Wen wishes for a violent escalation of hostilities over such a small matter?” Wan Tianming’s eyes narrowed as he spoke with an indifferent expression.

“Swapping pointers? My sword attendant is only at early Foundation Establishment. Your disciples were clearly bullying her and deliberately embarrassing our sect.” The beautiful woman’s face grew cold.

“Humiliate Madam’s sect? I don’t dare! For the sake of the Archsaint’s reputation, I will later have those disciples offer you their humble apologies.” The middle-aged man slightly frowned and spoke without much care.

“What does this matter of mine have to do with my lord husband? If you are unwilling, then how about I use my Virtuous Duality Sword Arts to swap pointers with Sect Master Wan?” The beautiful woman became even more furious at his words.

“Compare notes with Lady Wen? Let’s forget that. If the Archsaint of the Six Paths [3] were to know that I bullied his wife, he would seek my life. I don’t wish to incite a great war between the Righteous and Devilish Dao.” Wan Tianming chuckled as if he found it ridiculous.

When the beautiful woman heard this, her face reddened. After a final glare, she dropped the matter.

While the beautiful woman had let the matter drop with the middle-aged man, the middle-aged man was unwilling to do the same with Grandmaster Zenith Yin. He sneered at Grandmaster Zenith Yin. But just as he though to say something, a rumble vibrated from the passage and faintly shook the entire hall.

Apart from the Nascent Soul eccentrics, all of the cultivators looked towards the entrance with alarm.

Grandmaster Zenith Yin and the old Confucian scholar looked at each other with a hint of concealed joy. However, Grandmaster Zenith Yin’s happy expression seemed forced.

Wan Tianming’s eyes coldly glinted and flashed with sharp killing intent. The old Daoist and the old farmer also seemed to know who was coming and revealed a trace of worry.

The vibrations soon grew stronger and more frequent, eventually revealing an exceptionally tall figure.

A blue-robed eccentric with a yellow curly beard suddenly walked in. It seemed that his every step caused the entire hall to sway as if he weighed over six thousand kilograms.

Under everyone’s amazed gazes, he took note of the people within the hall without any regards before settling his eyes on Wan Tianming and burst into laughter.

“I didn’t think that great Sect Master Wan would come here. It seems it was correct for me to come here. I had always wished to contest myself against Sect Master Wan but it is unfortunate that I’ve never had the opportunity until now.” The eccentric looked at the middle-aged man with a provocative gaze.

“I too have looked forward to witnessing Brother Man’s Heavenbearing Devil Arts, reputed to be the greatest defensive devilish art in the Scattered Star Seas.” Wan Tianming coldly glanced at the eccentric and fearlessly replied.

“Hehe! Well said, well said! I have been looking forward to experiencing Sect Master Wan’s True Heavensifting Arts.” The eccentric widely grinned with unconcealed eagerness.

Unfortunately for him, Sect Master Wan didn’t wish to cause an incident at present. He softly spoke to the old Daoist and the old farmer before the three flew up toward a jade pillar.

Afterwards, the old Daoist spoke to the old Core Formation cultivator on the pillar with a smile. The Core Formation cultivator then vacated the pillar as if he had received a great favor and moved to a different place

When the eccentric saw this, his face held a trace of mockery. After raising his head and looking around, his body suddenly blurred before reappearing on a jade pillar.

As chance would have it, the jade pillar happened to be Han Li’s.

When Han Li saw this, his expression turned to shock.

“Get lost. This place is mine.” Just as the eccentric appeared on the pillar, he icily spoke to Han Li with a cold stare.

Han Li’s expression abruptly turned unsightly, and he involuntarily clenched his sleeved fists with force. He stayed silent, thinking of forcefully staying a moment. But he soon jumped off the jade pillar, followed by the wild laughter of the eccentric.

Han Li’s face was covered in an icy frost. Although it was extremely embarrassing, he could only endure it for the time being.

After all, the hall’s restrictions may be able to prevent cultivators from acting, but he wasn’t sure whether or not these restrictions had as large of an influence on a Nascent Soul cultivator. He didn’t wish to put his life at risk by allowing himself to be overwhelmed with emotion.

Suppressing a bellyful of grievances, he found a clean spot on the floor and sat down. The old Confucian scholar asked the eccentric with a beaming smile, “Brother Man arrived quite late. I had believed that Brother Man had changed his mind. Did you not intend to come?”

“How could that be possible? I had come to the Heavenvoid Hall in hopes of refining life lengthening pills! It was just that a few matters along the way had delayed me. As for Wan Tianming’s arrival, I was quite amazed. Could it be that he knew that the life extending fruit had ripened and also wanted to pick a few of them?” The eccentric stroked his yellow beard and spoke with slight doubt.

“I’m not sure. However, there are countless other exceptional treasures in the Heavenvoid Hall. Who knows what he came here for?” The old Confucian scholar spoke with doubt.

Grandmaster Zenith Yin seemed to have thought of something and worryingly said, “Wan Tianming is among the top leading figures of the Righteous Dao. Does he intend to strive for the Heavenvoid Cauldron?”

“Heavenvoid Cauldron? That’s impossible! If that item were so easily obtained, it would’ve long been taken away by other cultivators before they ever got the chance.” Without waiting for Man Huzi [4] to reply, the old Confucian scholar shook his head like a rattle drum.

ED: Han Li agreed as the main character of the story had only just arrived, so how could the macguffin have already been taken?

Naturally.

[1]. The 悟子Wuzi in his name can mean enlightened one.

[Back]

[2]. Quite suitably, his name 天明 Tianming means dawn or daybreak.

[Back]

[3]. His title, 六道 Six Paths, references the Six Paths of Reincarnation.

[Back]

[4]. His name 蛮胡子 Man Huzi could translate to Rough/Barbaric/Tyrannical Beard.

[Back]

Chapter 435: The Heavenvoid Cauldron and the Heavenmend Pill

“That might not be certain. I heard that the disciples of the Myriad Gates of Enlightenment have spent the past few years searching for Gold Thread Silkworms. But information regarding their search suddenly stopped, possibly from having found them. With the assistance of these exotic insects, it is quite possible for the master of the Myriad Gates of Enlightenment to acquire the Heavenvoid Cauldron.” Grandmaster Zenith Yin frowned and unconsciously looked at Wan Tianming and the others with great worry.

The three Righteous Dao Nascent Soul cultivators were currently sitting down cross-legged on a single pillar as if they had no intention of speaking.

“Humph! Not only is it possible that Wan Tianming possesses Gold Thread Silkworms, I’ve heard that you, Zenith Yin, have acquired two mutant fire pythons from Li Fire Island. Your ambitions for this trip are also quite large!” Man Huzi shot Grandmaster Zenith Yin a glance and spoke without restraint. He appeared somewhat disdainful of Grandmaster Zenith Yin’s stealthy actions.

When Grandmaster Zenith Yin heard this, his expression abruptly changed several times before he recovered his calm. However, he was profusely cursing in his heart. There was no question that his own confidants had divulged this information since it had been heard by Man Huzi.

It seems that in addition to acquiring the life prolonging fruit, Man Huzi wished to keep watch on Grandmaster Zenith Yin’s actions along the way.

Despite feeling annoyed, Grandmaster Zenith Yin spoke with a blank face, “It seems my ineptitude has attracted your ridicule. I have truly acquired two mutant fire pythons, but their skills are shallow. As their odds of success are low, I require Brother Man’s and Brother Qing’s assistance.”

The old Confucian scholar’s heart stirred and he hesitantly asked, “Assist you? Do we get any benefits?”

When Grandmaster Zenith Yin heard this, he revealed a slight smile, choosing to continue with voice transmission rather than speaking, “According to the information left behind by the Heavenvoid Hall’s master, there are several top grade ancient treasures left behind from ancient times. Their power should undoubtedly be unmatched. Apart from the Heavenvoid Cauldron and a Heavenmend Pill, how about we evenly split the other items?”

The old Confucian scholar’s face flashed with greed, but after some consideration, he took a look at Man Huzi before replying with a voice transmission, “I have no problem with this, but it will depend on Brother Man. After all, without Brother Man to pin down Wan Tianming, I wouldn’t be able to brave the risk.”

Grandmaster Zenith Yin wasn’t surprised to hear this. He knew that this old Confucian by the name of Layman Qing Yi [1] was truly an old schemer. If he didn’t draw in Man Huzi, this matter would have no chance of success.

Thus, Grandmaster Zenith Yin turned his head to Man Huzi passed on his conditions to Man Huzi with a voice transmission, “Brother Man, what do you think of my proposal? Are you interested in cooperating? After all, Brother Man should clearly understand that I have no need for the Heavenmend Pill. It serves no other purpose I can think of apart from making up for the deficiency of five elements spiritual roots. Perhaps if Brother Man takes it, his cultivation will greatly progress and he’ll be able to breakthrough the limits of his lifespan!”

Grandmaster Zenith Yin seemed not to mind the unsightly expression he had just shown and spoke excitedly.

“Humph! From your plan to acquire the Heavenvoid Cauldron with two fire serpents, I see that your mind is muddled! An unknown number of Nascent Cultivators have already scoured these halls, but they all returned with disappointment. Do you believe that your plan is so likely to be successful that is it worth braving these great dangers? The danger of the inner halls is far greater than the outer halls. Even if we go in as Nascent Soul cultivators, there is no guarantee we will come out unscathed. Every successive opening of the Heavenvoid Hall doesn’t end with only one or two Nascent Soul cultivators disappearing.” Man Huzi snorted and spoke with derision.

“Brother Man need not worry about this. Just let me ask, if Wan Tianming truly strived for the Heavenvoid Cauldron wouldn’t Brother Man want to go and watch it?” Grandmaster Zenith Yin calmly asked.

Man Huzi’s cold smile gradually disappeared after he heard Zenith Yin’s question.

He narrowed his eyes and a cold glint flashed through his eyes before he slowly said, “If Wan Tianming truly wishes to brave the inner halls then I will travel with you without question. Even if our Devil Dao is incapable of obtaining the Heavenvoid Cauldron, we cannot allow it to fall into the hands of the Righteous Dao.”

“Hehe, that’s good. So long as Brother Man lends a hand when the time comes, my previous proposal will obviously hold. Naturally, if Lady Wen is willing to lend her assistance, she is more than welcome.” Grandmaster Zenith Yin glanced at the beautiful woman with a slight smile.

“My purpose in coming here is to pick some spiritual herbs. The inner halls are too dangerous, so I will not be going.”The beautiful woman surnamed Wen didn’t bother to hear out his conditions and coldly declined.

A trace of disappointment flashed from Zenith Yin’s eyes.

Although the beautiful woman was only at early Nascent Soul stage, her lord husband the Archsaint of the Six Paths was a towering, peerless figure amongst those that tread the Devil Dao. As he was unwilling to act shamefully in front of Man Huzi, he couldn’t persistently ask her and could only wallow in his impotence.

However, he naturally didn’t dare to force the woman along. All he could do was smile and drop the matter. After all, their group of three wasn’t at a disadvantage against the Righteous Dao, and he was unwilling to offend the woman.

After the Devil Dao finished their discussions, Wan Tianming and the other two Righteous Dao cultivators continued openly meditating in silence. It was unknown whether they had finished their plans or if they had prepared countermeasures.

Han Li saw all of this while he was sitting in a corner.

Although he was quite far away and the majority of their speech was in sound transmissions, he could faintly guess from their occasionally malicious glances towards the Righteous Dao. They were likely discussing how to deal with the Sect Master of the Myriad Gates of Enlightenment and the others, much to Han Li’s delight.

So long as the Nascent Soul cultivators were focused on each other, he could take advantage of the ensuing chaos to further ensure his safety. Best of all, Grandmaster Zenith Yin wouldn’t be capable of attending to him!

As Han Li was thinking of what could possibly further increase the chaos, two white clothed old men appeared at the entrance of the hall. Their hair was silver, and their jackets were fluttering about, the exact image one would imagine of an Immortal.

As soon as the many cultivators saw the two and recognized them, their gazes revealed respect.

Their appearance had brought relief to a large portion of the cultivators in the room! As for the old eccentrics of the Devilish and Righteous Daos, they all revealed complicated expressions, containing envy, loathing, and even helplessness.

The old man with the friendlier appearance of the two smiled under the cultivators’ many gazes and kindly said, “The reason why our two sages didn’t preside over this treasure hunt at the Heavenvoid Hall is because they are still in seclusion. Us two enforcement elders will be supervising this grand occasion on behalf of the Star Palace in their place.”

“The rules of this treasure hunt shall be the same as all the others. Those who casually bully the weak or kill others to seize their treasures will be stopped by us, and will be hunted down by our Star Palace. However, our supervision will be limited to the outer halls. We will neither enter the inner halls or be involved with any matters that take place there. Thus, if anyone feels uncertain, do not enter the inner halls . In addition, we will not assist any fellow Daoists with the dangers in the Heavenvoid Halls and will not bat an eye if you perish to them. With this, everyone should understand our intentions.”

With that said, the white-clothed old man quickly swept their gazes past everyone in the hall like lightning. When the others felt their gaze upon them, they each turned their head away, but when Wan Tianming and Man Huzi felt their gaze sweep past them, they directly returned their gaze.

The white-clothed old man were initially startled before frowning. They couldn’t help but mutter, “Why have these two eccentrics arrived? It seems that a bit of trouble is stirring.”

The cold-faced old man at his side also had a change of expression, but after a sneer, his expression returned to normal.

Soon after, these two enforcement elders of the Star Palace sat down cross-legged at the sides of the entrance, not paying any attention to the uproar that had been caused by their words.

All of the other Core Formation cultivators had greatly varying expressions ranging from worry to joy.

When Han Li saw this, he couldn’t help but find this odd. What did the Star Palace hope to gain by acting so benevolently? Could this be a display of the Star Palace’s authority?

At that moment, he heard the voice of the Bone Sage, “Youngster, be careful. The Star Palace aren’t flawlessly virtuous. To the best of my knowledge, when either the Devil Dao or the Righteous Dao obtains too much influence, the Star Palace would suppress the respective offender, denying either of the two sides from gaining too much power. In addition, every time the Heavenvoid Halls opens, quite a number of Righteous and Devil Dao cultivators die from mysterious causes, possibly from the machinations of the Star Palace. Although you don’t belong to the Righteous or Devil Dao, you had best watch yourself. I don’t wish for my plans to fail merely because I couldn’t find another suitable partner.”

Although the Bone Sage’s voice was indifferent, his words stirred great alarm in Han Li.

Well, everyone technically is the MC of their own story.

[1]. His specific title is Householder.

[Back]

Chapter 443: Ghost King (5)

Despite being startled by the strange transformation, Han Li took a quick glance behind him and sneered at what he saw.

A majority of the grey ghost shadow had already been devoured, and the last third of its ruined body was on the verge of being consumed. Han Li reckoned that even if it were to now escape, its origin Qi would be immensely damaged, rendering it incapable of further attacking.

The Gold Devouring Beetles truly deserved their high ranking among exotic insects. Regardless of whether they were devouring spiritual Qi or Yin ghosts, they were immensely vicious. But, they were slightly slower when they were devouring the latter.

As Han Li thought this, the man-faced tiger abomination was at a loss for a short moment before revealing pleasant surprise at being awakened. It looked at Han Li, the ghost shadow being devoured behind him, and then looked at his own body.

It started laughing with an extremely hoarse voice and a freakish smile. The laughter gradually grew louder and continued as if there were no end. The nearby ghost mist eventually started to roil from the laugh’s vibrations.

Han Li didn’t seem to mind this and only focused his cold eyes on the tiger abomination’s movements. But after a short moment, Han Li’s face grew pale, and his expression became grave.

The tiger abomination’s weird laughter not only grew increasingly louder, but it also became more resounding and filled with Qi. Even after using the Great Development Technique to guard his mind, Han Li began to feel dizzy as if countless claps of thunder roared past his ears.

‘Not good!’ As Han Li was carefully observing the abomination, he seemed to have recalled something and his expression greatly changed.

Han Li hastily turned his head to find an alarming scene. The grey ghost shadow had unexpectedly disappeared without a trace, and his thousands of Gold Devouring Beetles were powerlessly lying on the ground, occasionally flapping their wings. They no longer had the vigor to continue devouring ghosts.

In his annoyance, Han Li hastily took out several spirit beast pouches and quickly stored the incapacitated Gold Devouring Beetles into them. While still enduring the deafening laughter, he turned his head to look at the others’ fight.

He was initially astonished by what he saw, but soon grew relieved.

Fairy Violet Spirit and that black-robed man were in a fierce battle against the phantoms. Although the black-robed man’s cultivation was far superior to the ghosts, he didn’t have an overwhelming advantage due to the nature of his techniques and his greatly weakened magic treasure.

As for Fairy Violet Spirit, she had concealed herself away in a glow of radiance by using a stone tablet and was only attempting to defend herself.

Han Li was slightly baffled when the two were unaffected by the strange laughter. But after some consideration, Han Li realized why.

It seemed that the power of the two-headed abomination’s strange laughter was limited to a small area. As a result, it was able to exert such an astonishing amount of power that his incredibly durable Gold Devouring Beetles were incapacitated, causing them to fall off the grey ghost shadow.

Although these exotic insects had yet to reached their full potential, the might of the strange light could clearly be seen.

Were it not for the soul concentrating effect of the Great Development Technique, Han Li feared he would’ve also become incapacitated by the strange laughter, only able to await his inevitable death.

The more he thought of it, the more he became aghast. Han Li had already determined that despite not being at the Nascent Soul stage, it was definitely no weaker than a late Core Formation cultivator. Han Li suspected that this being was a so-called ghost king.

At that moment, the abomination seemed to notice that the strange laughter had no effect on Han Li, who was still steadily standing. It eventually stopped and eerily stared at Han Li with its two heads.

Han Li felt uneasy upon looking at it, but he narrowed his eyes and boldly met its gaze.

At that moment, the badly damaged grey shadow appeared behind the abomination and shot straight towards the two headed abomination without any signs of stopping.

Han Li was at a loss from the sight, and his gaze continuously shifted.

‘The ghost shadow has already transformed. Why wasn’t it hiding from a distance? Why did it come back?’

While Han Li was bewildered, he saw something he was incapable of imagining. The eyes of the abomination strangely glinted and it grabbed ahold of the grey ghost shadow. The black tiger head then widely opened its mouth and quickly swallowed down the grey shadow.

Han Li watched with complete astonishment. But what occurred next immediately dispelled Han Li’s doubts.

As the abomination roared to the sky, another protrusion appeared at its neck. It emerged to reveal a tiger head with a grey human face. The face of the third tiger head resembled that of an average woman.

After a moment of shock, Han Li quickly restored his calm expression.

After the grey tiger head appeared, it narrowed its eyes, and its face became deathly pale as if it were heavily injured. But not long after, it opened its blood-red eyes and stared at Han Li with an expression of deep resentment. When Han Li saw this, his heart trembled, and he felt goosebumps arise all over his body.

At this moment, the head with the man’s face at the center let out a fierce hiss. Afterwards, the abomination started to fearlessly approach Han Li with large strides.

A black light flashed from its body with every step, causing its body to swell. After about a dozen steps, the abomination was as tall as a three story building. The sight caused Han Li to blanch.

Without taking the time to think, Han Li waved his arms, summoning over a hundred huge ape puppets around him. The puppets simultaneously opened their mouths and flooded the sky with beams of various colored light.

Han Li then pointed at the huge azure sword, having it join the assault as a long blur of frightening speed and astonishing pressure.

When the three headed abomination saw this, the middle head revealed a trace of astonishment, but it soon sneered.

The left and right head widely opened their mouths. While the pure tiger head began spouting out orbs of black light, the grey woman’s head filled the entire area with wisps of grey ghost flames.

The combined attack of the flame wisps and light orbs managed to forcibly block the many light beams. Although a few of the beams managed to pierce through, the few staggered light beams were completely ineffective.

Han Li unconsciously frowned. With a cold glint in his eyes, he suddenly cast a sword incantation seal. Shining with even brighter radiance, the azure streak traveled with increased speed.

Under the cover of the huge ape puppet’s attacks, the huge sword instantly pierced through the flame wisps and light orbs with unchallenged momentum. It flew around the waist of the beast and attempted to slash through it with a flash of brilliance.

But what Han Li saw next left him at a loss for words.

The three heads of the abomination simultaneously released a bizarre roar and swiped its two claws at a speed Han Li couldn’t perceive, resulting in the huge sword being trapped in its grasp.

The two hairy tiger claws seemed unaffected by the sharpness of the swordlight. Although the sword continuously swayed in its grasp, it was unable to break free. Han Li wasn’t sure what to do.

Although the Bamboo Cloudsword wasn’t refined for long and didn’t contain much power, it was inconceivable for it to be caught with mere claws. Could it be that their claws had been refined into a magic treasure?

Han Li’s thoughts went off on a tangent.

When the abomination had restrained Han Li’s flying swords, the three heads revealed a malicious expression. The middle head smiled sinisterly before opening its mouth and releasing a dense, black Yin Qi towards the struggling flying sword, gradually whittling away the intensity of its light.

Han Li’s heart dropped upon seeing this.

The abomination’s methods were ruthless, and its cultivation was immense. If he allowed this drag on, it wouldn’t end well. He had to take a risk and end this as soon as possible!

With that thought in mind, Han Li couldn’t help but turn his head towards the other group. The black-robed man and Fairy Violet Spirit were completely focused on fighting the demon beasts and had no time to look in Han Li’s direction.

With that, a strange expression flickered through Han Li’s eyes, and he slowly turned his head back.

The abomination’s left and right heads were still busy dealing with the intense barrage of his huge ape puppets, and the middle head was fully focused on spouting out black Qi to corrupt his Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords.

‘You’re courting death!’ Han Li’s heart soared with killing intent. Without any further hesitation, he formed an odd sword incantation gesture and fiercely pointed at his flying sword.

Chapter 444: Black Robes

Han Li pointed at the huge sword struggling within the abomination’s grasp. It suddenly grew still and started to sparkle with green light.

When the middle-head that was spouting out black Qi saw this, it was stunned. Before it could even react, the flat of huge sword released several tens of arcs of faint gold lightning.

The arcs of lightning were incredibly fast. In an instant, the lightning traveled up from its furry claws onto its huge body, creating a net of golden light around the abomination’s body.

The abomination’s three heads simultaneously expressed shock. But before it could even move, Han Li uttered the word, “Suffer.” The net of lightning covering it immediately ruptured.

A scorching, blinding white light thoroughly submerged the abomination, leaving it incapable of being seen.

In that instant, Fairy Violet Spirit and the black-robed man couldn’t help but look over in surprise. As for their opponents, the Weiwu Ghosts and the two Nightfiends, they appeared to be at a loss for a moment before immediately fleeing away.

The two were alarmed at the scene, but after some hesitation, they merely watched them as they fled.

However, the Weeping Soul Beast took this opportunity to forcefully snort and absorb one of the fleeing spirits into its nose.

As for the blinding white light, it persisted for some time before fading away. The tiger abomination was standing motionlessly in place, and its three heads appeared frightened. However, their expressions were completely still. When a gust of cold wind blew past, its huge body scattered into the sky as grey ash before disappearing without a trace.

All that remained was the huge sword and a fist-sized tricolored pearl floating in midair. Black, green and grey were interweaved in the sparkling pearl.

Han Li let out a long sigh and waved his hand. With a dim cry, the huge azure sword dispersed into eight blades and flew back to Han Li, with four of these blades fading away in mid-flight. The other four blades obediently returned into Han Li’s body and sunk into dormancy.

The previous arcs of lightning cleanly exhausted the swords’ entire accumulation of its Divine Devilbane Lightning. They urgently required long term nurturing.

Han Li glanced at the strange pearl. With several blurs, his body appeared in front of the pearl. After intensely staring at it, he started muttering to himself.

After a short moment, a malicious expression flashed from his face. With a flip of his hand, an azure flying sword appeared in his hand. Han Li fiercely chopped down at the pearl with a flash of radiance.

Pang. The pearl was chopped into two, releasing three streaks of black Qi flying away as if they were fearfully escaping. However, Han Li flicked a finger of his other hand and shot out three egg-sized fireballs towards them.

Puff. Puff. Puff. The three strands of black Qi faintly released miserable wails upon being struck by the fireballs before they were dissolved by the flames.

These demon ghosts were extremely devious. They had hid away within the magic treasure and attempted to lure him into grabbing it. Had he fallen for it, he would have been in an inescapable confrontation for control of his body.

However, this was something he had earlier anticipated when the body of the tiger abomination was exterminated by the Divine Devilbane Lightning.

After all, with the Gold Lightning Bamboo’s grand reputation along with legends of its “Devilbane” characteristics, it would be truly heaven-defying if a full discharge of the four swords were unable to extinguish a demon ghost.

It was because he had this trump card that he so calmly and confidently entered the ghost mist. Despite having felt incredibly baffled when faced against the fused ghost demons, he was able to keep calm particularly because of this.

Naturally, he had originally refrained from using the Divine Devilbane Lightning since the black-robed man and Fairy Violet Spirit were nearby. However, he hadn’t expected the fused form of the tiger abomination to be extraordinarily ferocious. When it had foolishly used its claws to grab hold of his Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, he naturally couldn’t let go of such a great opportunity to use his Divine Devilbane Lightning.

With that, he erased a monster that was no weaker than a late Core Formation cultivator from this world.

Han Li lowered his head to look at the split pearl and lightly shook his head. He then turned around and walked towards Fairy Violet Spirit.

When the black-robed man saw this, his face was full of shock. Although he hadn’t been able to pay close attention to Han Li’s battle, he had caught sight of the ghost demon’s soul possession, transformation, and combined body. It had left him so distraught that he had immediately decided to flee the moment Han Li appeared unable to be its match. The three headed demon tiger had appeared frighteningly powerful.

But he didn’t expect that such a monster would so easily be eliminated with just a burst of dazzling white light. He found it truly hard to believe. Could it be that he possessed a Heaven-Earth Inversive Antiquity from legend? He couldn’t think of any other method that an early Core Formation cultivator like Han Li could use to exterminate the dreadful three-headed monster.

But if this were the case, he could entice Han Li and obtain a great supporter to accompany him through the Heavenvoid Hall. After all, he believed that only Nascent Soul eccentrics were capable of extinguishing such a powerful demon without the slightest injury.

With that thought, the black-robed man’s astonished expression gradually disappeared to be replaced with a complicated one as he looked at Han Li.

As for Fairy Violet Spirit, although she was greatly amazed by these events, she had already guessed that Han Li was an unordinary Core Formation cultivator. She quickly calmed down and looked at Han Li with a smile.

“Senior Han’s abilities are truly remarkable. He was able to effortlessly exterminate such a dreadful ghost demon. It seems I was truly fortunate to have teleported together with Senior!” Fairy Violet Spirit gracefully said.

When Han Li heard this, he insipidly denied, “Effortlessly? That wasn't effortless in the slightest.”

“Senior is truly modest!” Fairy Violet Spirit’s eyes were glowing with humor. It was obvious that she believed Han Li wasn’t being completely honest.

“What did Fellow Daoist use to produce that white light? It was immensely powerful.” The black-robed man spoke for the first time, but his voice was muffled and hoarse, sounding quite unnatural.

This unpleasant voice caused Han Li’s eyes to flicker with a strange expression. He looked at the black-robed man with a smile.

After Han Li’s smile faded away, he indifferently said, “So Fellow Daoist is a female cultivator! There is no need to speak with a fake voice. Fairy Violet Spirit and I have already seen through it.”

Fairy Violet Spirit gave a charming smile upon hearing this.

The black-robed woman was initially startled, but her eyes soon revealed humiliation and anger.

A long while later, she spoke with a delicate, soft voice, “Since you Fellow Daoists have already seen through it, I will no longer hide this. It merely made matters convenient.”

With that said, the black-robed woman hesitated for a moment before removing the hood of her black robe, revealing an astonishingly gorgeous face.

Not only did this woman have incredibly fair and soft skin, but she had long, silky hair that was draped over her shoulder. She wore a dazzling garland on her head that added a mysterious charm, causing her to appear elegant yet unyielding.

Despite also being a woman, Fairy Violet Spirit appeared breathless at the sight of the black-robed woman’s beauty. But something soon came to mind and she stealthily took a glance at Han Li.

What she saw left her feeling somewhat uneasy.

Han Li had been looking at the black-robed woman in a daze. His eyes revealed a strange, unclear expression.

A blush appeared on the black-robed woman’s flawless face. With both pride and gloom in her voice, she coldly said, “Has Fellow Daoist had enough to look at, or is there something something wrong with my face?” With that said, the black-robed woman’s expression sunk.

Han Li didn’t grow angry at the rebuke, but neither did he withdraw his gaze. Instead, he let out a long breath and examined the woman with a mysterious smile. He appeared rather interested.

Not only did she raise her eyebrows this time, but her face also grew cold. Even Fairy Violet Spirit felt apprehensive, doubting whether or not Han Li would act on wicked thoughts.

But after some further thought, her uneasiness had disappeared.

Due to predetermined innate aptitudes, there were far fewer female Core Formation cultivators in the cultivation world in comparison to male cultivators. Thus, a large majority of high grade Dao companion pairs normally consisted of a man with Core Formation cultivation and a woman at Foundation Establishment. As such, the effectiveness of pair cultivation was not ideal for the male cultivator. As for the small number of female Core Formation cultivators, they attracted many suitors that believed themselves to be worthy of them.

It made sense for a female cultivator possessing such beauty and deep cultivation as the black-robed woman to cause Han Li's heart to stir.

Well, that's one way of looking at it.

Chapter 445: Yuan Yao

Just as the black-robed woman was about to grow furious, Han Li’s smile faded and he earnestly said, “I didn’t expect that after a mere hundred years, Lady Yuan would enter Core Formation. You have my sincere congratulations!”

When Han Li addressed her as ‘Lady Yuan’, the woman’s angry, embarrassed expression immediately disappeared. She hastily attempted to refute him with panic, “Lady Yuan? You’re mistaken. My surname is Ruan.”

This situation was the exact opposite of what Han Li had expected. He couldn’t help but stare at the woman’s flickering eyes.

At the moment, the gorgeous woman’s complexion had paled, and her hand was placed on her storage pouch. Her eyes were wide open and carried unmistakable hostility.

The mood suddenly became strained! All of which originated from Han Li addressing her as ‘Lady Yuan’ with a casual tone.

While Han Li wore a slight smile on his face, he actually felt truly puzzled.

As for Fairy Violet Spirit, the current situation was even more of a surprise. Without even thinking, she took a half step closer towards Han Li, making her standing clear. In terms of both familiarity and might, Han Li was the obvious choice.

With an unchanged expression, Han Li slowly said, “It seems there is a misunderstanding! Fellow Daoist Yuan most likely doesn’t remember me. After all, we had only met once before over a hundred years ago.”

“We’ve only met once? Over a hundred years ago?” The woman’s expression slightly relaxed, but her eyes were still vigilant and she expressed doubt.

The tension had been greatly eased!

But after looking at Han Li for a moment, she doubtfully asked, “I’ve taken a good look at you, but I don’t remember ever seeing you. Are you attempting to dupe me?” With that said, the woman’s eyes flickered with cold intent, faintly revealing a trace enmity.

Han Li felt at a loss, not knowing whether he should laugh or cry.

He didn’t bother playing coy and directly asked, “Over a hundred years ago, did Lady Yuan go to the Sky Capital Market at Stalwart Star Island?”

The black robed woman blankly stared for a moment before nodding her head in recollection. After looking intensely at Han Li’s face, she revealed a pensive expression. “Stalwart Star Island’s Sky Capital Market? I’ve been there many times. Could it be that you saw me there?”

She seemed to have recalled something.

“That’s right. At the time, you were together with a beautiful friend. My Martial Uncle Crooked Soul and I met you at the edge of the market city.” When he mentioned Crooked Soul, Han Li unconsciously glanced at Fairy Violet Spirit who was aware that Crooked Soul had been his avatar.

Naturally, when Fairy Violet Spirit heard Han Li mention Crooked Soul as his Martial Uncle, she revealed a mysterious smile. Although she didn’t know the circumstances at the time, she was sure that Han Li must have been playing out an elaborate scheme. She couldn’t help but find it ridiculous! But naturally, she wasn’t going to talk about this matter without cause.

Speaking of Crooked Soul, Fairy Violet Spirit had been wondering for quite a while why his avatar wasn’t present at his side. Crooked Soul would’ve been of great assistance to them.

After blinking her eyes several times, the black-robed woman came to a sudden realization and revealed an expression of disbelief. “Fellow Daoist’s words feel quite familiar to me. Could it be that your esteemed self was at the entrance of the Sky Capital Market and was accompanied by a Core Formation Senior?”

Han Li bitterly smiled.

“Lady Yuan has finally remembered. It seemed that I had given you quite an ordinary impression. Han Li spoke with a chuckle.

The black-robed woman deeply blushed upon hearing Han Li. But now that she recognized him, she completely relaxed and self consciously said, “Please don’t take offense, Fellow Daoist Han! At the time, Fellow Daoist was truly...” The woman found it difficult to continue.

Han Li replied with laughter, “Wasn’t it because my appearance and cultivation were too ordinary? It’s no surprise you two ladies didn’t take note of me!” Han Li was calm and didn’t display the slightest annoyance.

“It seems I’ve made a fool of myself!” Han Li’s attitude had greatly eased the black-robed woman. After all, Han Li’s current abilities were impressive, and she was fearful that Han Li had been offended over being forgotten. With her magic treasure greatly damaged, she was unwilling to casually offend him.

With that thought, she continued, “I must also congratulate Fellow Daoist! In these hundred years, Fellow Daoist also cultivated to Core Formation from Qi Refinement! Your magic power is also so profound that you are actually capable of eliminating the ghost king level fiend!”

Han Li inwardly shook his head in response to the woman’s friendly words. He wasn’t at Qi Condensation stage at the time. He had been at late Foundation Establishment. Had he not refined the “Three Essence Revolutions” along with the “Great Development Technique”, he feared he wouldn’t have entered Core Formation.

However, this woman had truly cultivated from Qi Condensation to Core formation in that timespan. When he recognized the black-robed woman, he was truly shocked!

This woman didn’t possess particularly impressive aptitude, so Han Li inwardly guessed that she must’ve had a fortuitous encounter during those hundred years. Otherwise, it would’ve been impossible for an ordinary cultivator like her to have improved so quickly.

Although he had carefully examined her previously, he was unable to see the spiritual roots of a fellow early Core Formation cultivator as their body’s magic power blocked his sight.

With that thought, Han Li didn’t stare at the woman any longer and turned his eyes towards the ghost mist surrounding them.

Han Li smiled and thought to say something, but Fairy Violet Spirit spoke first with a slight frown, “Fellow Daoists, let us set off! It would be best to not stay here for too long. It would be troublesome if another fearsome phantom were to appear.”

Han Li silently agreed with a smile. The black-robed woman Yuan Yao had no objections, and the three set off into the ghost mist after confirming their direction.

……

There was a place that appeared similar to a garden, but it contained nameless, rare flowers and plants. It had eight pavilions finely carved from jade with thirty cultivators distributed sparsely among them.

A majority of these cultivators had pale complexions and were stained with blood as if they had arrived here after a bitter struggle. However, their faces revealed unconcealable excitement. There were even a few cultivators that were whispering to one another.

Grandmaster Zenith Yin, Wan Tianming and the other Nascent Soul cultivators were at this location. The two factions were meditating at two different pavilions.

As for the two Star Palace elders, they were floating at some place in midair. They were expressionlessly sitting cross legged in meditation, appearing as if they were statues.

A dense, pitch-black ghost fog rolled around vigorously four hundred meters away from where the garden laid. It was obstructed by an invisible wall, appearing as if they were two entirely different worlds.

Suddenly, the fog separated to reveal a male cultivator calmly walking through it.

This male cultivator wore green robes, appeared youthful, and had a refined appearance. But what was most odd was that there wasn’t any abnormalities on his body, and his appearance was serene as if he hadn’t experienced any battles on his way there.

This strange scene attracted the amazement of the nearby cultivators. They looked at him with complicated expressions.

At that moment, Grandmaster Zenith Yin opened his eyes and glanced at the male cultivator before revealing a disappointed expression. He shut his eyes once more and didn’t pay any further attention to the male cultivator.

When this male cultivator looked at Grandmaster Zenith Yin, his face revealed a trace of resentment during a moment of carelessness. However, his calm appearance quickly returned and he walked forward with large strides.

He didn’t enter any of the pavilions to take a seat. Instead, he found a remote corner and stood there with hands behind his back, indifferently examining the cultivators that were there. Seeing that Han Li had yet to appear, his delicate face lightly frowned, but he soon became expressionless.

At that moment, unbeknownst to anyone else, a deep resounding man’s voice could be heard in the youth’s mind.

‘What? That assistant of yours isn’t here? Could he have fallen to a malicious spirit? Hehe! It seems the person you sought wasn’t particularly worthy of note.’ The voice lazily said.

The youth grew angry and he used his spiritual sense to strictly rebuke it, ‘Silence! Don’t casually speak inside my body! There are many Nascent Soul cultivators here. If one or two of them were to hear you, what do you think will happen?’

Chapter 446: Regrouping

‘Humph! If they discover us, at worst, we will just return into the ghost mist. Despite not being able to match Nascent Soul cultivators in direct battle, who can match the escape methods of us Ghost Dao cultivators?’ The resounding man’s voice spoke with rejection.

'What do you know? There are at least four Nascent Soul cultivators here, and they all have magic treasures and divine abilities that are particularly effective in restraining our Ghost Dao techniques. If you want to die, don’t involve me. Else, I’ll be forced to break our agreement and exterminate you here.” The youthful Bone Sage rebuked with an icy voice.

‘There is no need for Old Brother Bone Sage to be so angry! I won’t mention it again. However, you cannot renege on our agreement to find a suitable living body. Why else would I have given you a trace of my soul essence and willingly allowed you to leave the ghost mist!’ This person seemed fearful of the Bone Sage’s rage, but in the end, he couldn’t help but remind the Bone Sage of their agreement.

‘Don’t worry. Since I need your help to deal with my traitorous disciple Zenith Yin, I will get you a physical body before I act. Furthermore, as fellow sufferers that were forced to cultivate the Ghost Dao, how could I possibly renege on our agreement?’ The Bone Sage indifferently said.

‘Hehe! Your words have truly put me at ease.’ After that was said, the resounding voice disappeared from the Bone Sage’s mind.

The Bone Sage sighed with relief and and sat against a small tree before dozing off.

After some time had passed, an increasing number of cultivators left the ghost mist with increasingly heavier damage. Quite a number of them had even sustained great injuries to their Origin Qi that would require many years of dedicated treatment, else their cultivation level would suffer as a result. But even in this sorry state, they all wore expressions of unconcealable happiness. After all, so long as they passed the ghost mist trial, they would still be able to acquire a few rarely seen spiritual medicines.

After about seventy more cultivators arrived at the garden, the rate of new arrivals greatly decreased. In the coming day, only a sparse few cultivators had arrived.

The youth that had accompanied Fairy Violet Spirit at the beginning was amongst them. His clothes were damaged and his face was pale as if he had suffered through hardships on the way there.

Upon entering the garden, the youth swept his gaze past the garden and revealed worry upon seeing that Fairy Violet spirit wasn’t there. His expression was indecisive.

At that moment, Grandmaster Zenith Yin and the Bone Sage both became uneasy upon seeing that Han Li had yet to arrive.

The Bone Sage was the calmer of the two. Although he felt irritation, his face still maintained peacefulness. However, Grandmaster Zenith Yin was unable to endure. He occasionally opened his eyes and gloomily swept his gaze past the ghost mist, unable to calm down.

In truth, this person’s gloomy temperament would’ve normally prevented him from displaying his impatience. However, Han Li possessed something that was vital to his treasure hunt, leaving him in a hopeless situation.

A majority of people didn’t take notice of these actions, but the confucian-robed old man that was meditating nearby had opened his eyes. With a light cough, he slowly asked, “Could Fellow Daoist’s unease be due to concern for someone that has yet to arrive?”

The old man stared at Grandmaster Zenith Yin with doubt.

When Zenith Yin heard this, his expression became calm once more, and he indifferently replied, “It couldn’t be considered concern. It’s just a very interesting Junior that I’ve met once before!”

A strange glint flashed through the confucian-robed old man’s eyes. He said with a mysterious smile, “An interesting Junior? Fellow Daoist Wu must introduce me to him. I too am quite fond of guiding inexperienced Juniors that hold potential.”

‘Old bastard! He is far too suspicious.’ Zenith Yin was extremely annoyed that Han Li had yet to appear, and was unwilling to deal with the old man’s schemes. As such, he bluntly closed his eyes and forced himself to meditate.

At that same time, the resounding voice could be heard once more in the corner of the Bone Sage’s mind.

‘Bone Sage, your assistant still hasn’t arrived? Could he have been devoured by ghosts? Such an assistant would prove too weak to be useful.’ The voice’s tone contained a trace of schadenfreude.

The Bone Sage sighed. Given its temperament, it was truly impossible to keep him silent. It was also impossible for him to kill it as it would prove far too useful to him.

Until now, there also hadn’t been anyone that had glanced at him with a baffled gaze. It seemed that their short talks didn’t arouse any suspicion.

With that thought, the Bone Sage unhappily said, ‘This person is exceptionally mysterious. Although he is young and his cultivation is only at early Core Formation, it is absolutely impossible for him to have fallen to any fierce ghosts. Even if you came across him, you’d turn tail and flee if your soul didn’t scatter first. Do not underestimate him.’

‘Early Core Formation? Isn’t Bone Sage underestimating me too greatly? Against such a cultivator, I’d only have to opened my mouth, and his blood essence would already be absorbed.’ The deep voice spoke with disbelief.

‘Did you enjoy my Devil Extinguishing Arrow? What would you do if he possessed flying swords also made from Golden Lightning Bamboo?’

The deep voice grew silent for a moment before speaking with great skepticism, ‘Flying Swords made of Gold Lightning Bamboo? Are you joking? There was only ever one stalk of Gold Lightning Bamboo, and you refined it into the Devil Extinguishing Arrow. How can there be other Gold Lightning Bamboo magic treasures?’

‘Hehe! You’ll find out whether or not this is true sooner or later. And before you say I didn’t warn you, apart from his Gold Lightning Bamboo magic treasure, he also possesses a few other troublesome techniques. Why else would I, the Bone Sage, join hands with an early Core Formation cultivator?’ With that said, the Bone Sage didn’t pay any further attention to the voice and closed his eyes into oblivious meditation.

The deep voice tactfully kept silent and was pondering whether or not the Bone Sage had spoken truthfully.

Six hours later, the Bone Sage now appeared irritated and wondered why Han Li was taking so long to arrive. At that moment, an area of the ghost mist rolled away and made a path, revealing three people walking side by side.

The three were Han Li’s party. As for the gorgeous woman Yuan Yao, she was back to concealing her breathtaking beauty with her black robes.

Han Li was stunned for a moment after having seen that there were so many people present. He soon glanced at the scene and walked towards an uninhabited area without hesitation. Fairy Violet Spirit and Yuan Yao then gave each other a tacit glance before going their own ways.

At that moment, a silhouette appeared with a blur. A handsome, azure-jacketed youth had rushed over and earnestly spoke to Fairy Violet Spirit, “Great! Violet Spirit, you’re safe! I was so worried.” After this was said, he hastily approached her and carefully examined her for any injuries.

“Brother Li, I’m fine.” When Fairy Violet Spirit saw him, she stopped and forced a smile. Her expression continuously shifted.

After Yuan Yao took a deep look at those two, she went to another location with fluttering clothes.

Han Li, who had found a lone place to stand, turned around to see Yuan Yao following him. With slight surprise, he immediately frowned and said, “Lady Yuan, we’ve already left the ghost mist. For what matter have you followed me?”

Although this woman’s breathtaking beauty had touched his heart, he didn’t have any plans to work together with any strangers and immediately spoke with a cold intent of rejection.

Han Li’s blunt words didn’t cause Yun Yao to become angry. Instead, she sighed and said, “Please don’t take offense, Brother Han. I’ve only followed you because I have no choice! Fellow Daoist should know that my magic treasure had suffered great damage in the fight against the ghost king, and I am not capable of using it any further. And with the great dangers in the Heavenvoid Hall, this woman only knows of Brother Han. Coming here was a stupid decision. Please do not leave me here to die!”

With that said, the black-robed woman’s eyes turned slightly red as if she were about to weep tears. The scene caused Han Li to intensely frown.

“Lady Yuan! Since you’ve said this, I will need to ask some questions. But first, I’d like to make it known that I am not an upright gentleman, nor is my heart filled with benevolence. I am especially unwilling to be ignorantly used in vain.” Han Li calmly spoke as if he hadn’t seen the woman’s sad expression.

“Fellow Daoist Han, please don’t hesitate to ask. So long as the questions don’t touch on any secrets, I will definitely give a satisfactory answer.” This woman felt somewhat annoyed that Han Li hadn’t revealed any pity or sympathy towards the fairer sex. However, there were items that she must acquire and she had no choice but to agree.

After placing his hands behind his back, Han Li unhurriedly asked the woman without blinking, “My questions are quite simple. What is Fellow Daoist Yuan’s objective? Up to which trial do you intend to challenge? Also, from the panic you had shown earlier, it seems you’re hiding something. Do you carry any great troubles on you? I don’t wish to be involved in any of your quarrels by association.”

Preach.

Chapter 449: Ruse

The Bone Sage’s frightening red eyes shifted several times before their radiance gradually disappeared.

After the Bone Sage’s eyes returned to normal, he calmly said, “Correct, the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng really is here. Traces of its pure spiritual Qi can be faintly seen from the surface of the mountain.”

Han Li’s heart stirred. He poured spiritual power into his eyes and examined the small mountain with great attention. However, he was greatly disappointed to have found nothing unusual.

When the Bone Sage saw Han Li’s eye shine with azure radiance, he obviously knew what he was doing. He disdainfully smiled and said, “Don’t delude yourself into thinking you can see the pure spiritual Qi of the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng. Only Nascent Soul cultivators possess a sufficiently powerful spiritual sense to be able to do this. Although my cultivation has shifted to the Ghost Dao, the power of my original spiritual sense hasn’t suffered in the slightest.” The Bone Sage’s words carried a trace of mockery.

Han Li’s face didn’t reveal any change, but under the Bone Sage’s unintentional advice, he started to circulate the Great Development Technique in his body.

After a short moment, Han Li rejoiced. He actually caught sight of extremely faint traces of azure light scattered throughout the mountain.

Not aware that Han Li could clearly see the pure spiritual Qi, the Bone Sage looked down at the mountain and indifferently said, “As I have been here before, I fortunately have a method of acquiring the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng. As a result, I acquired a few particular items from a small island along the way. We will first arrange a trap. Then, we’ll have the Ninecurl Spirit run into it, allowing it to be easily captured.” He then extended his hand towards his storage pouch and took out a dazzling gold item.

“This is?” Han Li looked on with amazement.

The egg-sized golden ball of thread released a faint radiance as if it had been specially refined.

The Bone Sage scoffed at Han Li’s bewildered expression and clutched the ball. With a flash of black light, long golden threads shot out from the ball and quickly wove themselves into a small, exquisite gold net. It was only the size of his palm, but its sparkling shine gave an unusual impression.

The Bone Sage stared at Han Li and solemnly said, “The Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng is something that can only be caught with an object of pure gold. Other magic treasures and tools will be completely ineffective. Take proper care of this. It will be used to catch the spirit ginseng when it tries to flee.”

Han Li raised his brow and pondered for a moment before silently beckoning to the gold net. Woosh. The net flew into his hand, and he placed it into his storage pouch without a further glance.

When the Bone Sage saw this, his eyes smiled. With a flip of his hand, he took out four earth-yellow flags. The small flags were layered with talisman markings that concealed their flickering brilliance.

“Yi!” With Han Li’s current mastery of formation flags, he was startled by the sight of the small flag. After taking a cold breath, he revealed a trace of disbelief.

“What? Han Li, my boy, you recognize these flags?” When the Bone Sage saw Han Li’s astonishment, he couldn’t help but feel surprised.

Han Li didn’t immediately reply and rigidly stared at the small formation flags for a moment more. He then raised his head and solemnly said, “Is that the Celestial Black Tortoise [1] formation tool set? Apart from this ancient formation spell, no other formations are able to form such a powerful earth-attribute formation from four small flags.”

Surprise flashed across the Bone Sage’s face, but he soon regained his calm. “I hadn’t expected you to be proficient in the Dao of Formation Spells. It seems that I’ve found the right person to be my assistant. You’re correct, these Celestial Black Tortoise formation flags were something I had refined on the way here. With this formation, we will be able to restrict the mountain stone in an area of a hundred meters, hardening it into metal and trapping the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng. Since you posses knowledge of formation spells, I’ll let you place down the formation. While you do that, I will be looking around for any solid traces of the Spirit Ginseng.”

Soon after, he calmly handed over the four yellow flags and turned into a black cloud as he silently flew down towards the mountain.

Han Li looked at the flags in his hand and then turned to look at the back of the old devil with an odd expression in his eyes. After a moment, he licked his lips and flew downwards with a sneer.

At the same time, a man’s resounding voice was heard from deep within the Bone Sage’s body.

‘Bone Sage, why did you give him the formation flags? I see that your relationship with is quite shallow. Could it be that you’re up to no good?’ This person spoke as if he greatly understood the Bone Sage.

‘What do you mean? I only had Youngster Han set down the formation flags so that I can capture the spirit ginseng with certainty. After taking advantage of this opportunity, I will kill him.’ The Bone Sage sinisterly spoke with a chilling voice.

‘You’re going to kill him now? Did I hear wrongly? I thought you’d at least wait until Zenith Yin was killed before you acted against him!’ The deep man’s voice displayed astonishment.

The Bone Sage grimly said, ‘That won’t do. This Youngster Han is far too cunning. I fear any more delays will only bring more troubles. In addition, this person understands my methods and will not allow himself to be controlled by me. If he were to by chance betray me to my traitorous disciple Zenith Yin, it would be beyond terrible. Although the possibility of this is low, this Bone Sage refuses to take such a risk! After all, I’ve already suffered betrayal once and will never easily trust others ever again. Also...’

The man’s voice lazily continued, ‘Also, you never intended to give the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng to him from the start!’

‘That’s right! After spending so much thought into acquiring this spiritual item, how could I be willing to give it to another? Even if the Spirit Ginseng had no effect on my cultivation, it would prove equally useful for trade. And with that Gold Lightning Bamboo magic treasure in his possession, he will inevitably become a great enemy for us demon ghosts. The sooner we exterminate him, the better. Besides, what do you think about his body?’ The Bone Sage revealed a sinister expression as he spoke.

The question at the end had startled the male ghost. He grew immensely excited. ‘It would be great! You must help me seize his body! But, how do you plan to deal with Zenith Yin?’ His question was slightly hesitant.

‘When I passed down Zenith Yin’s Profound Yin Art to him, I left behind a flaw that I could use to kill and refine him. So long as he is alone, and with your newly acquired body, we will be able to exterminate him.’ The Bone Sage spoke with great confidence.

‘So that’s how it is! But weren’t you thinking of exterminating the Youngster Han from the start? You still deliberately sought to ally yourself with him despite this? You really are a cunning fox!’ The man seemed to hold the Bone Sage’s cunning in high regard.

‘You overestimate me. Before I came across you, I truly wished to join hands with him to kill Zenith Yin. After all, even if I know the flaw in my traitorous disciple’s cultivation, having an assistant will be far more reliable. But now that I came across an old friend like you, I no longer have need of him. It would be better to kill him as soon as possible and prevent any mishaps later.’ The Bone Sage nonchalantly said.

‘You’ve put on quite the display! I had truly believed your apprehensive appearance at the jade pavilions. I didn’t expect you were already planning to kill this required helper of yours.’ The man sighed and spoke with a complicated tone.

‘Humph! My worry at the time was genuine. However, I didn’t fear the loss of assistance for my revenge but that his Gold Lightning Bamboo flying swords had fallen into someone else’s hands. If such an event came to pass, it would prove to be disastrous to those of us following the Ghost Dao.’

After a moment of silence, the man asked with concern, ‘You dare to so recklessly act against him even though he possess a Gold Lightning Bamboo magic treasure? Are you truly certain of victory?’ As this matter pertained to himself, he naturally wanted to know the finer details.

At that moment, the Bone Sage was flying circles around the mountain at a low altitude.

‘What I originally imagined was that we’d use both the golden net and the Celestial Black Tortoise Formation to seize both the spirit ginseng and that Youngster Han at once. I hadn’t expected that he’d be proficient in spell formations. It was then that I was struck with a clever idea. I would hand the formation flags to him and have my plan become even more perfect.’ The Bone Sage revealed a strange smile and spoke with a mysterious tone.

‘Could it be that you’ve done something to the flags?’ The man spoke with sudden realization.

‘Hehe! You’ll know when the time comes. For now, we’ll find the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng. Otherwise, that youngster definitely won’t be fooled.’ The Bone Sage deliberately omitted the main details, much to the man’s dissatisfaction.

‘Nevertheless, my ghost demon cultivation art was something that you had imparted to me. I had originally thought to use it to search for the spirit ginseng, but I hadn’t expected that my traitorous disciple would betray me. It has become my last hope!’ The Bone Sage’s eyes flashed with cold light.

‘I wasn’t really imparting anything. We were just taking what we needed.’ The man spoke with a deep sigh.

[1]. Specifically references to the constellation, https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Tortoise

[Back]

Chapter 455: Another Surprise

“Humph! Do you truly believe that you get to decide whether or not you can go? If you don’t come with us, this young lord will kill you here. Did you truly believe that our Zenith Yin Island wouldn’t dare to act due to the words of the Star Palace enforcers?” Wu Chou’s small eyes ominously glinted.

Although Wu Chou had been previously warned by Grandmaster Zenith Yin, he still attempted to threateningly pressure Han Li. Wu Chou felt Han Li was truly displeasing to the eye. The malice he felt towards Han Li was nearly innate, born from no particular reason.

Han Li found this feeling mutual. That recent outburst was merely met with an indifferent glance and did nothing to improve Han Li's impression of him. Paying no further heed to Wu Chou, he spoke to Grandmaster Zenith Yin, “For a reason unknown to me, Senior requires this Junior’s spirit beast. But this Junior is also well aware that if a spirit beast’s master dies, their spirit beasts are incapable of recognizing another master. In addition, Junior is capable of ordering the Bloodjade Spider to self detonate during a moment of crisis. Surely, Senior doesn’t wish to see that!”

Han Li clearly understood that Wu Chou was merely playing the part of a paper tiger. As such Han Li was unwilling to tango with Wu Chou and decided to speak with the true authority, Grandmaster Zenith Yin.

However, this action by Han Li caused Wu Chou to fly into a rage from the humiliation. After a hostile expression appeared on his face, he spewed a slew of profanities at Han Li. But he was soon stopped by a wave from Zenith Yin, “Good, I am fond of Juniors with courage and understanding. Since this island lord requires your Bloodjade Spider, I naturally won’t drag you along without payment. Once we arrive in the Inner Halls, I will...”

Just as Zenith Yin was about to list his conditions, his expression suddenly grew sullen and he stopped speaking. He turned his head around to fiercely stare in a certain direction with a malicious look on his face.

“Let this Grandmaster have a look at you, eavesdropper!” Grandmaster Zenith Yin’s voice was shrill and full of killing intent. He appeared extremely angry.

Han Li felt alarmed. He immediately thought that the Bone Sage had been discovered and was unconsciously pondering about how he should deal with this situation.

However, Han Li was surprised to hear an aged voice.

“Old Pal Wu, there is no need to be so angry. I merely encountered you by coincidence. Don’t tell me you’re going to attack?” A hundred meters away in the air floated a Confucian-robed old man covered in an azure glowing light.

It was someone Grandmaster Zenith Yin was quite familiar with, Layman Qing Yi!

“Fellow Daoist Qing! You followed me!” When Zenith Yin saw him, he grimaced, and his killing intent faded.

“What? Follow you? I was merely taking a stroll and happened to see Fellow Daoist Wu and this young Junior having a chat. So I thought I’d come over and say hi. I didn’t think that I’d cause Fellow Daoist Wu to be so unhappy. Sigh , had I known earlier, I definitely wouldn’t have acted so rashly.” The Confucian-robed old man dryly laughed and spoke with a completely unconcerned tone.

He soon grew unconcerned with keeping up his own pretences and turned his gaze from the pale Zenith Yin to the Bloodjade Spider.

“Tch tch. This is a Bloodjade Spider? It truly is a rare spirit beast. From the analysis of earlier cultivators, this is one of the spirit beasts that are most likely capable of acquiring the Heavenvoid Cauldron. Its odds are far greater than your Fire Serpent or Wan Tianming’s Gold Threaded Silkworm.” Layman Qing Yi spoke, shaking his head.

‘Taking a stroll nearby? While invisible?’ After hearing the old man’s shameless excuse, Grandmaster Zenith Yin grew furious. But his expression only grew gloomier upon hearing Qing Yi reveal the secret about the Bloodjade Spider.

After turning his gaze away from the Bloodjade Spiders, the Confucian-robed scholar examined Han Li several times before saying, “So this is the Junior that Old Pal Wu was concerned with earlier. This old man is also quite fond of guiding courageous and insightful youngsters. I am quite interested in taking taking him in as my disciple. How about it? I’ve never taken in a disciple before.” Zenith Yin paled after hearing this.

“Take Junior in a disciple?” Han Li blinked several times. He didn’t know whether he should be excited or cynical.

Zenith Yin’s expression was icy, and threads of black Qi began to surge from his body. He spoke each of his words forcefully while staring at the old man, “Fellow Daoist Qing, what are you planning?”

“Hehe! I was only joking! Old Pal Zenith Yin doesn’t need to be so nervous. If I were to truly take this youngster as a disciple, I fear Fellow Daoist would attack me without restraint. However, if Hu Manzi were to know of this Bloodjade Spider, would he back down?” The old man chuckled. A strange expression appeared within his eyes as he played the matter off.

Layman Qing Yi’s words initially caused Zenith Yin to relax. But upon hearing him mention Man Huzi, he started to feel a strong headache.

Zenith Yin had originally planned to keep the Bloodjade Spider a secret and manipulate the others into driving the Righteous Dao cultivators away from the Inner Halls or have both sides suffer a mutual defeat. He would then use to the fire serpent to put on a display of being incapable of acquiring the treasure while secretly using Han Li’s Bloodjade Spider to secure it. He alone would acquire the Heavenvoid Cauldron. As for his previous promises, he had never intended on keeping them in the first place.

But he didn’t expect in the slightest that his meticulous plan would be thrown into disarray by this old cunning fox. He was uncertain about whether or not he could kill him to shut him up. And even if he were confident, he couldn’t easily act and weaken his own side prematurely. After all, he still had the Righteous Dao cultivators to contend with.

Zenith Yin’s face twitched when the old man mentioned Man Huzi. He had previously experienced just how fearsome Man Huzi’s Heavenbearing Devil Arts were. Even with his newly acquired minor mastery of his Heavenwide Corpsefire, he didn’t hold any confidence in facing that man. If by chance that man were to use the pretext of taking in that youngster as a disciple, then he would insist on taking the lion’s share of the treasure. He wouldn’t have any way to prevent it. Unless...

Seeing that he was no longer able to preserve the secret of the Bloodjade Spiders, Zenith Yin started to think of how he wouldn’t suffer a smaller portion of the treasures.

At that moment, his heart stirred and he looked at the old man with an odd expression, faintly guessing the meaning behind his previous words. The Confucian-robed old man faintly smiled in response to his odd expression and transmitted a message to his ear.

Zenith Yin’s expression started to ceaselessly fluctuate.

The old man’s voice transmission was short and he quickly resumed speaking out loud,“How about this proposal?”

Without taking much time to think, Zenith Yin gloomily said, “Fine, I accept.”

The old man revealed a pleased expression and said,“Good, this is how it should be.” He then glanced at Han Li and unhurriedly said, “Now, between the two of us, who do you think is more suitable to become his master?”

After muttering to himself, Zenith Yin said, “Naturally, he will decide who will become his master. That would be a bit more fair.”

The old man blankly stared for a moment before revealing a strange expression. But after some conderation, he nodded his head in agreement.

When Zenith Yin saw this, he wore a seldom seen smile. He then turned towards Han Li and indifferently said, “You must’ve already heard our chat! Your Bloodjade Spider is something that we require in our treasure hunt, something that we cannot release under any circumstance. If you believe I won’t kill you because you are the master of the spirit beast, then you are gravely mistaken. This Grandmaster happens to know of a convenient method to refine spirit corpses. If worst comes to worst, I will kill the Bloodjade Spider and refine it into a demon corpse. Since the Bloodjade spider’s cultivation will greatly suffer from this, I won’t do this unless I am forced. If you are afraid of any disadvantages that will result from being involved, then you can become either of our disciples and receive our protection. Also, you will acquire a portion of the treasure should we be successful in acquiring it. As you appear to be a smart fellow, you should know what to do!”

Zenith Yin calmly laid out both the carrot and the stick, causing Han Li’s expression to change.

In fact, Han Li was inwardly cursing without end. Ever since the Confucian-robed old man had arrived, Han Li felt ill at ease as if the situation had taken a turn for the worse. He had originally wished for the two eccentrics to fight amongst themselves, allowing him to slip away in the ensuing chaos. But he didn’t expect for the cunning old foxes to reach an agreement after only a few words.

Now, Han Li reckoned there wasn’t the slightest chance that the Bone Sage would appear to help him.

As for using the Bloodjade Spider as a threat, it seemed it wouldn’t have any effect. He reckoned that if he were to truly order the Bloodjade Spider to self detonate, Zenith Yin would rush to refine it. But as his life was hanging by only this thread, he couldn’t afford to damn himself by angering these Nascent Soul cultivators.

It seemed that if he didn’t agree, he would only be met with death.

Chapter 464: Weeping Soul Pearl

Han Li glanced at her and calmly said, “It was but a minor effort! Now that Fellow Daoist Yuan is out of danger, I will be taking my leave.” He then turned and walked away without any intention to stay.

Still shaken by her near death encounter, Yuan Yao turned pale and was incapable of staying reserved. She hastily said, “Brother Han, I still haven’t expressed my thanks for you saving my life.” The gorgeous woman’s delicate appearance would tug at the hearts of any who saw it.

However, Han Li didn’t turn around and responded indifferently, “I don’t need your thanks. I merely assisted you for a moment and cannot help you the entire way through. Do your best, Lady Yuan!”

After this was said, Han Li was already forty meters away, moving at a breakneck speed.

This only caused Yuan Yao’s pale face to become even more panicked. She no longer possessed the strength to resist the scorching heat, let alone any more Ironfire Ants she may encounter. She was unable to give up as Han Li held the string that her life hung upon!

But as a result, her charming pleas were completely ignored as Han Li walked further away.

She revealed apprehension at Han Li’s indifferent response and could only say what Han Li expected to hear.

She gritted her teeth and said, “Please wait! So long as Fellow Daoist Han is willing to protect me on this path, I will bestow a grand treasure to you. Your magic power won’t be used in vain.”

“A grand treasure?” Han Li stayed still, revealing slight hesitation.

Seeing that Han Li appeared interested, she didn’t dare to be negligent. “I still have many Azure Flameblasts that I am willing to give Fellow Daoist.”

“That was the green pellet that you had used a moment ago? It is quite the uncommon item.” Han Li slowly turned around with an expression of deep consideration.

Since he had acted to save the woman, he naturally didn’t intend on truly abandoning her. Besides, he had saved her with another reason in mind; his previous act was merely taking one step back so he could take two steps forward. Now that she had taken the initiative to request his aid, his objective was fulfilled. He reckoned that if he were to demand greater concessions, she would have no choice but to begrudgingly accept.

This beautiful woman clearly understood this. Regardless of whether it was for paying Han Li for his previous rescue or his continued protection, Yuan Yao had no choice but to continue with a helpless expression, “The Azure Flameblasts are firebombs secretly refined by the Devil Dao’s Azure Yang Sect. Not only does each one require a great quantity of rare resources to refine, but it also consumes a great amount of time. Their might is equivalent to a Nascent Soul cultivator’s Yang Essence Flame. I still have three of them and will give all of them to you.” The woman’s expression grew more determined as she spoke. She extended her snow white hand to reveal three pellets shining with a gentle green light.

At that moment, Han Li unhurriedly walked back over and glanced at the three pellets. He calmly said, “These Azure Flameblasts truly are an exceptional treasure, but they aren’t enough for me to take such a large risk. Bringing you through this path will double my magic power consumption at the very least. Does Fellow Daoist Yuan truly think these are worth that level of danger?” Han Li’s words contained thinly veiled mockery.

Yuan Yao’s beautiful expression fluctuated for a long while before settling on a charming smile.

“Brother Han, please don’t hesitate to state your conditions, as this young woman doesn’t wish to continue speaking in circles. Could it be that Fellow Daoist Han wishes for me to give my heart to you?” Yuan Yao turned her hips and puffed up her soft chest, showing off their exceptional plumpness. Her bright eyes were filled with a peculiar haze that was beyond flirtatious.

Han Li was somewhat stunned by the woman’s gorgeous beauty. But he soon narrowed his eyes and sized up her dainty, well-rounded body. The woman blushed at his unrestrained gaze. Her beautiful eyes became increasingly bright and captivating as if capable of enrapturing the deepest depths of a man’s heart.

Han Li stroked his chin and calmly spoke with a radiant gaze, “As expected, Yuan Yao’s charming technique at full power along with her beautiful appearance is without match! However, since it has no effect on me, Fellow Daoist had best save her magic power for survival instead.”

Tearing off her beautiful guise and halting her charming technique, she flusteredly said, “Humph! What a crude, uncultured boor! You don’t hold compassion for women in the slightest.”

Han Li insincerely smiled, saying, “How could Lady Yao say that? If this weren’t a place as dangerous as the Heavenvoid Hall, I definitely wouldn’t have refused your seductions. But, here we are, hehe....”

“You sure like to dream. If it weren’t this place, how else could I have possibly thrown myself into your arms?” Yuan Yao glared at Han Li with a resentful gaze.

“It seems I’ve saved the wrong person. Since this is the case, I don’t wish for Fellow Daoist Yuan to give her heart to me. And there is also no need to express your thanks for my rescue. I’ll be taking me leave.” As if to deliberately anger the woman, he cupped his hands to her appearing as if he was about to set off.

Seeing this, Yuan Yao’s words immediately grew soft and she returned to being lovingly pitiful. “Brother Han! It was my wrong, please don’t be angry. Please don’t hesitate to say what must be done to receive your assistance through the Path of Molten Rock. I will absolutely do as you ask! Could it be that Daoist doesn’t wish to help this poor woman despite being her acquaintance for a hundred years and a fellow companion that accompanied you through the ghost mist? As for treasure, apart from these Azure Flameblasts, I have no other treasures to give you.”

Although Han Li was wearing a mysterious smile, he inwardly felt astonished.

Yuan Yao was a truly fickle person. Standing tall one second, and submitting the next! From her currently powerless pleads, her recent mature, flirtatious charms, to her proud, elegant impression from the very beginning, all of them had given Han Li a distinct, unique impression. How truly strange! As this woman was capable of cultivating to the Core Formation stage from the Qi Condensation stage in only a hundred years, she was by no means ordinary.

With this thought, Han Li started to mutter himself. Yuan Yao revealed a hopeful expression as she nervously watched him.

After a short moment, he looked up and spoke with seemingly great reluctance, “Since Lady Yuan is an acquaintance I had met over a hundred years ago, I would appear truly heartless if I do not protect you. However, I was never someone to work for free. If Fellow Daoist Yuan Yao wishes for me to take her through the Path of Molten Rock, then how about she gives me the Weeping Soul Beast? I am extremely interested in the beast’s soul absorption abilities.”

After walking around so many pretenses and plots, Han Li finally stated what he had wanted from the woman from the very start. With this strange beast, he’d be more confident in working together with the old ghost Bone Sage. From what he had seen, this Weeping Soul Beast was by no means weak.

“You want the Weeping Soul Beast?” Yuan Yao’s eyes widened after hearing Han Li as if she couldn’t believe what he had said.

“What? Will it not do?” Han Li’s expression sunk, and his voice grew cold.

“If I give the Weeping Soul Beast to you, you will take me through the Path of Molten Rock?” Yuan Yao asked Han Li this question word by word as she stared at him with a strange expression.

“That’s right!” Han Li frowned but still spoke with certainty. He faintly felt that that there was something amiss.

“Perfect, then it is all yours.” After Han Li confirmed this, she immediately took a spirit beast pouch at her waist and gave it to Han Li without the slightest hesitation.

Han Li blinked with a nervous heart. Why did it appear that she was actually impatient to give the Weeping Soul Beast to him. Could it be that there is something wrong with the Weeping Soul Beast?

After thinking for a moment, he calmly took the spirit beast pouch into his hand. He swept his spiritual sense inside to see the Weeping Soul Beast soundly asleep.

Han Li nodded his head and put the spirit beast pouch at his waist. Just as he thought to say something, Yuan Yao opened her mouth and spat out a dark grey pearl into her palm.

“This is the Weeping Soul Pearl. It is the item used to control the Weeping Soul Beast. If you refine this like you would an ordinary magic treasure, the Weeping Soul Beast will be forever yours. I haven’t owned the beast for long and haven’t completely refined its pearl. You can forcefully erase the traces of my spiritual sense from it without a problem.” Yuan Yao chuckled and gave it to Han Li.

Han Li looked at the Weeping Soul Peal with interest and didn’t move to take it. This pearl was something that he had known about from Fairy Violet Spirit when he inquired about the Weeping Soul Beast.

He later realized that she was incapable of smoothly controlling the Weeping Soul Beast because she hadn’t fully refined the Weeping Soul Pearl during that time. This had raised his interest in acquiring the strange beast.

But after seeing how she had so quickly given it to him with a delighted expression as if she ridding herself of a demonic plague, Han Li grew hesitant and didn’t hurry to take the pearl.

Chapter 474: The Mantis and the Oriole

[1. Old Chinese Idiom: The mantis stalks the cicada, unaware of the Oriole behind it.]

When Zenith Yin heard Wan Tianming call his words nonsense, a sinister expression appeared on his face, but after hearing what he said after, Zenith Yin forcefully suppressed his fury. He then turned his head to Man Huzi and Layman Qi, and spoke to them in voice transmission.

Not longer after, their discussion was finished. Zenith Yin coldly said, “As per your esteemed suggestion, we will cease fighting for now. We will wait until after the treasure is seized.”

Wan Tianming chuckled, “Good! You’ve made a wise decision. Let us enter together.”

He then walked towards the huge limestone gate closely followed by Tian Wuzi and the old farmer closely.

“Humph!” Man Huzi couldn’t help but snort at their grandiose mannerisms. His gaze then suddenly swept to Yuan Yao and the Core Formation cultivator that Han Li didn’t recognize with an ominous glint in his eyes.

At that same moment, the two paled under Man Huzi’s malicious gaze. They turned into a streak of yellow and red light, rushing towards the stone pagoda.

Man Huzi evilly grinned, “Where do you two think you’re going?”

He rubbed his hands and then waved towards them, shooting out two streaks of gold light in an instant, striking at them from behind.

The male cultivator in the yellow light released a miserable shriek before he tumbled to the ground. He was then swept up by the golden light and was split apart, scattering across the ground as a dismembered corpse.

As for when the golden light neared Yuan Yao’s red light, several bursts of blinding green flames temporarily scattered the golden light. As if spurred on by this, her red light transformed into a scarlet-red bird and became even faster. After shooting past the golden light in a blur, she passed through the stone pagoda’s entrance and disappeared.

“Yi! That’s odd.” Layman Qing Yi softly said with a frown.

Layman Qing Yi and Zenith Yin didn’t care about Man Huzi’s actions, but upon seeing Yuan Yao escape Man Huzi’s attack, they couldn’t help but be surprised.

“Man Huzi, what is the meaning of this? Why did you attack the innocent?” Tian Wuzi turned around and spoke with an angry expression.

Man Huzi gazed at the old Daoist with an uncaring expression and callously said, “I wasn’t in a good mood. What does it matter to you if I kill a few strangers? Could it be that you wish to seek justice on their behalf ,or do you just want to personally test my Heavenbearing Devil Arts?”

“You...”

Without turning his head, Wan Tianming shouted, “Enough, Tian Wuzi! Those two weren’t members of the Righteous Dao. Leave them be! We have more important matters to attend to!”

Tian Wuzi could only hatefully glance at Man Huzi after hearing this and begrudgingly turned around.

Not long after this event, the Righteous Dao walked through the stone gate and entered the Inner Hall.

Zenith Yin glanced at the Righteous Dao cultivators as they left and applauded Man Huzi with a sinister smile, “Brother Man did well in attacking them! We don’t want any annoying rats scurrying around us before the big event. Those two Core Formation cultivators actually wished to enter the Inner Hall and take advantage of the chaos for their own gain. The living are always so impatient. Unfortunately, there is still one person here who Brother Man hasn’t killed.” Having said this, his gaze fell upon the Bone Sage.

The Bone Sage was calm and indifferent, appearing as if Zenith Yin was talking about someone else entirely.

Man Huzi expressionlessly said, “This person has somewhat of a connection with me. As he had done me a favor, it is natural that I do not attack him. You two are also forbidden from disposing of him.”

Zenith Yin narrowed his eyes and carefully examined the Bone Sage, confirming whether or not he recognized this person. He then ambiguously said, “Since he is a junior with relation to Brother Man, it is only natural that we won’t dispose of him. Although, it is quite surprising that Brother Man would accept a favor from someone.”

Man Huzi’s face grew cold and he intensely glared at Zenith Yin, “Hehe! Zenith Yin, you dare to interrogate me?”

“How could I possibly? I was merely a bit curious! If Brother Man doesn’t wish to answer, then so be it. But, it seemed the black robed woman who escaped should have significant origins. Brother Man has best be careful!” Zenith Yin conceded the matter with a chuckle, but his last words seemed to carry a heavy meaning.

Man Huzi was silent for a moment before gloomily saying, “I am not blind. Did you think I didn’t see her use Old Devil Three Yang’s Azure Flameblast? Apart from his most intimate disciples, no other disciples of the Azure Yang Sect could possibly acquire such an item. How else could that young woman have possibly escaped death?”

“Hehe, it seems I was needlessly meddling!” Seeing that Man Huzi’s expression was far from good, Zenith Yin tactfully said nothing else.

“It is no matter. Even if that woman is important to Old Devil Three Yang, Brother Man has nothing to fear, given his cultivation. However, it is currently a crucial period of conflict in the Scattered Star Seas between the Star Palace and both the Righteous and Devil Daos. The Old Devil’s abilities are significant, and despite originating from the Devil Dao, he isn’t aligned to either of the sides involved. As such, we had best avoid having this man become our enemy. Let’s spare the girl!” The Confucian-robed old man smoothed the matter over from the side.

Man Huzi stiffly nodded his head and said no more. It was clear from his actions that he held great fear in his heart towards Old Devil Three Yang.

The stream of events left Han Li with heavy, complicated feelings. All sorts of distracting thoughts began to flood his mind.

A Core Formation cultivator had been killed right in front of him as easily as one would step on an ant, yet how did Yuan Yao manage to avoid such a fate?

Since when did the Bone Sage force a relationship between him and Man Huzi, one of the top figures among the Devil Dao? It was no wonder why he was so calm.

As for Yuan Yao, she seemed to have some sort of relationship with that Old Devil Three Yang, someone who could inspire fear in a hegemon such as Man Huzi.

These thoughts simultaneously bounced around in his head and he was unable to clearly arrange them for the time being.

He could only wordlessly pay attention to what Man Huzi and the others were saying in that hopes that he could gather some information that would allow him to form a dependable plan.

But unfortunately, Layman Qing Yi next words ended the conversation.

“Let’s quickly enter the Inner Hall! The Righteous Dao fellows won’t wait for us. We can’t let them stealthily leave us behind.” Layman Qing Yi glanced at the huge passage beyond the stone gate and wrinkled his brow.

Man Huzi glanced in the direction of the stone gate and sunk into thought for a moment before silently setting off.

Zenith Yin and Qing Yi glanced at each before following after them with relaxed expressions.

Han Li, Wu Chou, and the Bone Sage naturally followed behind.

Han Li and the others slowly entered the passage until they eventually disappeared from sight.

...

Three hours later, the darkened transportation formation suddenly shone with dazzling light, followed by the emergence of two silhouettes from the formation.

They were the Star Palace elders!

At that moment, the two were cautiously looking around. After they saw that no one was around, they wore looks of relief.

One of them spoke with a slight smile, “It appears that they’ve all entered. As cunning as these old eccentrics may be, they couldn’t imagine that our Star Palace had already unraveled this transportation restriction a thousand years ago. We can arrive at this place anytime we want.”

The other spoke with a cold voice, “Let’s go. We must be careful at all times. We cannot allow this secret to be easily revealed, unless they actually manage to extract the Heavenvoid Cauldron.”

“Of course!” The first to speak nodded his head in approval.

With that said, the two shot towards the stone gate as two streaks of white light.

...

Han Li was walking behind Zenith Yin and was unexpectedly beside Wu Chou, much to Han Li’s displeasure.

Possibly due to what Zenith Yin had said to Wu Chou before, Wu Chou acted very cordially to Han Li on the way. He would on occasion talk about some trivial matters with Han Li as to avoid treating Han Li coldly. It was as if his hateful gaze from before had come from an entirely different person.

But the further this fake act continued, the gloomier Han Li felt.

Han Li couldn’t help but bitterly laugh to himself in his mind, “Did Zenith Yin hint to Wu Chou that they would kill me after they acquire the treasure? Is that why Wu Chou is acting so differently?”

Although he was very much worried underneath, Han Li spoke to Wu Chou with a smile, producing a fake atmosphere between the two. Even those over thirty meters away could clearly make it out.

Still, Zenith Yin and the others turned a blind eye to the two as they continued forward. Ever since the three Nascent Soul eccentrics had entered the Inner Hall, they had become solemn in contrast to their relaxed, easy attitude from before.

But what baffled Han Li the most was that even after such a long period of time had passed, nothing had occurred. They had neither encountered any restrictions nor dangers.

Could it be that they had triggered some sort of restriction after entering the stone gate?

With that thought, Han Li couldn’t help but further examine his surroundings.

Chapter 475: Wolf Head Puppets

Han Li and the others were currently walking through a maze-like series of intersecting stone passageways. Each intersection had a stone gate inscribed with strange talisman characters.

These stone gates were identical in size: over thirty meters wide and in the shape of a square. They would always point in the directions of either north, south, east, or west, seemingly at random. However, they all radiated a faint white light. They were clearly affected by some sort of restriction.

Although he would only encounter a crossroads after a long distance, Han Li reckoned that during their entire time in the Inner Halls, they’d already encountered at least eight different stone gates. Each time, they neither changed direction nor entered the stone gates.

They eventually arrived at an intersection that caused Han Li’s expression stir.

The gate there slightly differed from the other ones. Although the talisman characters and structure was the same, it was completely devoid of light as if the restriction on it had been extinguished. As a result, Han Li further studied it with a strange expression.

Wu Chou saw Han Li’s expression and spoke to him with a familiar tone, “Junior Martial Brother Han, this stone gate has already had its treasure seized by others. What is worth seeing? If it weren’t for the fact that each person could only use a single Heavenvoid map fragment before being teleported out, I would’ve also thought to pick a stone gate and hastily see what was within. Once a Heavenvoid Map fragment was used to open a stone gate, one is unable to leave until the treasure is acquired. As Core Formation cultivators we are only be able to acquire treasures on the first floor. Picking a room on the later floors would be the same as suicide.”

‘Junior Martial Brother Han?’ When Han Li heard Wu Chou address him as such in a voice transmission, he felt disgust spread throughout his body.

When Han Li eventually managed to recollect himself, he replied with a beaming smile, “Then why isn’t Brother Wu choosing a gate on the first floor? Would it not be a waste of an opportunity to wait until you’ve arrived at the second floor or higher?”

“ Sigh! I wish I could, but my esteemed grandfather has repeatedly warned me that I must stay by his side on this treasure hunt as I may prove useful.” Wu Chou wore a reluctant expression as he glanced at the stone gate. A trace of greed flickered in his eyes.

Han Li slightly smiled and swept his gaze across the stone gate. So long as he entered and acquired the treasure it contained, he would be teleported outside. He would be keeping this in mind. Who knew whether or not he could use this as a method of escape?

At that moment, the group passed through another intersection and into the passage ahead of them. That same moment, a heavy, muffled thud came from their front. The sound continued as if something huge was slowly heading towards them.

Zenith Yin and Qing Yi’s expressions slightly changed and they halted, staring into the passageway ahead of them with grave expressions. In contrast, Man Huzi chuckled and revealed a trace of excitement. At the same time, his body flashed with golden light and a layer of golden scales suddenly covered his entire body. He had activated his Heavenbearing Devil Arts.

This was the first time Han Li had seen the bizarre appearance of the Heavenbearing Devil Arts up close. He couldn’t help but take a curious look at Man Huzi’s transformation.

Man Huzi keenly felt Han Li’s stare and turned his head around, giving Han Li a sinister grin. The expression on his face covered in small scales made for a frightening sight.

Han Li’s heart dropped, not knowing what he had meant by it. But he still forced himself to return the smile.

Fortunately, after Man Huzi smiled, he immediately turned his gaze back.

The approaching thuds were now only about a hundred meters away.

But as the passage across from them was pitch-black, Han Li wasn’t able to see anything within it. There were still restrictions in place inside the Inner Hall that restrained a cultivator’s spiritual sense.

Still, Han Li noticed the cold glint from the old eccentrics’ eyes. It seemed they were able see what was coming.

Without waiting for Zenith Yin and Qing Yi to act, Man Huzi deeply roared, flying into the passage as a streak of golden light. A series of loud impacts followed afterwards, along with deafening clangs of metal.

When Zenith Yin and Qing Yi saw this, they couldn’t help but look at each other in dismay.

Han Li was at a loss when a huge rumble sounded out as if something had been cleanly split into fragments.

Han Li’s mind stirred and something came to mind.

In the next moment, only the sounds of Man Huzi’s wild, carefree laughter could be heard.

Zenith Yin seemed to have thought of something and couldn’t help but laugh. “Let’s go! It is no longer a problem. We’ve already forgotten that we no longer have the same cultivation as we did three hundred years ago. The guards on the first layer are no longer a threat to us.”

Qing Yi chuckled with a relaxed expression, “That’s right. This old man had nearly forgotten this as well. The last time I came here, I had just entered the Nascent Soul stage, and the guards left far too deep an impression. It was good that Brother Man had taken care of it with his Heavenbearing Devil Arts. Else, we would’ve spent too much effort on them.”

Afterwards, the two began to take the lead with Han Li and Wu Chou closely following after them. The Bone Sage, who had originally been expressionless this entire time, wore a trace of disdain as he calmly followed them in the back.

After walking about thirty meters, Han Li saw Man Huzi in front of them with his hands behind his back. He was standing on something that was shining with silver light.

When Man Huzi saw Zenith Yin, he stretched his neck and indifferently said, “Not bad! This served quite well for a warm up. The Heavenvoid Hall this time around is truly interesting. However, it wasn’t nearly as formidable as rumors had made it out to be!”

“It’s because of the incredible force of Brother Man’s Heavenbearing Devil Arts. Other cultivators had to use magic treasures in such a narrow area, so they had experienced a bit of trouble.” Layman Qing Yi said with a smile. When Man Huzi heard his flattery, he chuckled but said no more. The golden scales on his body quickly faded away, and he indifferently took the lead. It seemed the previous fight had left him unsatisfied.

Zenith Yin and Qing Yi glanced at each other with a smile. Since Man Huzi was so willing to lead the way, they were more than happy to quietly follow after him.

When they walked past the silver item, Han Li stopped and lowered his head to look at it.

‘A mechanical puppet!’ Han Li was astounded. It was indeed a puppet, but what grade of puppet was this to have not been instantly destroyed by a mid Nascent Soul stage cultivator?

Most of what was scattered across the ground were pieces of an unknown silver metal. Apart from this, there was a ruined half of a golden wolf’s head, and several pieces of jet-black, thick and reflectioness blades, as well as an assortment of several other oddities.

As the Bone Sage quickly passed him by, he indifferently said without turning his head, “Don’t bother to look at them. While these items are certainly rare, they cannot be used to refine any magic treasures. Those that entered here long before have already tried.”

Han Li was surprised by this, but he continued to look at the ground as if he hadn’t heard. His gaze fell upon a sparkling, dark-green gem on the ground. Its extremely cold aura gave Han Li a remarkable impression.

After muttering to himself for a moment, Han Li immediately placed these items into his storage pouch with a sweep of his hand before rejoining the others.

Han Li’s thoughts were quite simple. Even if these items were truly useless, he could learn a bit about the ancient cultivator’s achievements in puppet techniques from the puppet’s composition and the refinement techniques used to create them. After all, the highest grade puppets in his Puppet Sutra were grade four puppets, equivalent to only late Foundation Establishment cultivators at false core stage. This was the huge tiger puppet that consumed an entire mid-grade spirit stone with a full powered strike. [1]

The puppet with the golden wolf head was stronger than an early Core Formation cultivator. Although Man Huzi dealt with it like child’s play without using any powerful magic treasures, Zenith Yin’s and Layman Qing Yi’s serious attitudes towards indicated that it was unordinary.

With such good items at hand, it was only natural for Han Li to want to leave and research it. But as things stood, there would be no such opportunity for him to slip away into a stone gate and escape with a treasure as well. He understood all too well that despite walking ahead of him, the three Nascent Soul eccentrics were watching his every move through their spiritual sense. Wanting to stealthily slip away through a stone gate was merely wishful thinking.

With Han Li’s temperament, it felt somewhat intolerable to leave such a treasure trove empty handed. For now, he could could these puppet fragments as a consolation prize from the Inner Halls. As for the treasures of the Heavenvoid Cauldron, Han Li knew better than to have such fanciful expectations!

[1]. Chapter 229: Huge Tiger.

[Back]

Chapter 500: The Starfall Coalition

Han Li spoke with an indifferent expression, “What great event? I only left seclusion a few days ago. Tell me about it!”

The old man locked his fingers together and spoke carefully, “It is only natural for Junior to answer Senior’s questions. However, may I ask for your name?”

After he heard this, Han Li felt somewhat surprised. After he tilted his head and pondered for a moment, he mysteriously smiled and said, “It seems that you’re being quite careful. I am the Exquisite Sound Sect’s Guest Elder Han. Have you heard of me before?”

After he heard of Han Li’s identity, he let out a long sigh of relief and smiled, “So it turns out to be Elder Han. You can’t be considered an outsider then. Our own sect’s Fairy Xuedi is close friends with Sect Master Fairy Violet Spirit.”

Han Li was surprised at his claim that they were on the same side and couldn’t help but laugh.

Han Li’s laugh caused the old man to grow somewhat uneasy.

‘Did I say something wrong?’ The old man thought apprehensively.

Han Li’s smile disappeared. “I don’t involve myself in the matters of the sect, nor do I care if you are lying. All I want is for you to properly answer my question. I won’t make things difficult for you. What major event occurred recently?”

The old man pledged he was speaking the truth with smile, “How could I deceive you, Senior? All of my words are true...”, but when Han Li’s gaze grew icy, he immediately started his explanation, “There were rumors that had suddenly emerged recently in the Scattered Star Seas that the Heavenly Star Sages were on the verge of breaking through to the great success stage of Divine Essencefused Light. The star palace took advantage of this opportunity to start eliminating certain disobedient or uncontrollable powers. This was originally believed to only be a rumor, but not longer after this rumor was spread, the Star Palace issued an official command to powers of all sizes to have their sect leaders and island lords immediately come to Heavenly Star City and pay audience to the Heavenly Star Sages. Otherwise, they will be branded as traitors and be eliminated.”

Han Li blinked before speaking with disbelief, “Have every power pay audience to the Heavenly Star Sages? Did I hear correctly? The Star Palace gave such an obviously insidious command?”

The old man bitterly smiled, “That’s right. The official command stunned many powers upon arrival. Were this at the peak of the Star Palace’s power, there would be no problem with this order. But as of current, it would be surprising for the the powers of the Righteous and Devil Dao to obey.”

Han Li swept his gaze past the group and frowned, asking,“Then all of the cultivators I saw on the way were heading towards Heavenly Star City to pay audience to the Heavenly Star Sages?”

“That’s hard to say!” The old man appeared hesitant.

A strange expression appeared on Han Li’s face. He curiously asked, “Hard to say? What does that mean?”

The old man continued with a helpless expression, “Senior, there are some things I still haven’t said. Soon after the Heavenly Star Palace issued the command, the Righteous and Devilish Dao suddenly formed the Starfall Coalition, in proclamation of smashing apart the Star Palace’s hegemony in the Scattered Star Seas and ending their reign. The Righteous Dao has dispatched their enforcement elder Wan Sangu and the Devil Dao dispatched their towering hero, the Archsaint of the Six Paths, as the two leaders of Starfall Coalition. After the alliance was established, many sects belonging to the Righteous and Devilish Dao began joining under their banner. Unaffiliated powers have also joined them, and several tens of rogue Nascent Soul paragons have been appointed as elders in the alliance. In addition, the Starfall Coalition copied the Star Palace and made their own proclamation with what is known as the Starfall Coalition’s Ghost Crest, proclaiming that any power to respond to the Star Palace will be branded as their enemy without exception. In addition, they claim that they will soon be launching an attack on Heavenly Star City and welcome all powers to witness the battle, and make their allegiances clear.”

Having heard this, Han Li’s expression remained completely indifferent, but his mind was left in a daze. This was beyond imagination! Such a massive event had occurred in the short time he had been stuck in Heavenvoid Hall!

For some time, Han Li was at a loss, but his mind suddenly stirred and he calmly gazed at the old man, asking, “What is the Starfall Coalition’s Ghost Crest? Do you have it on hand?”

The old man was stunned for a moment before enthusiastically replying, “It is in my sect master’s possession, but if Senior desires, I have a record of it on a jade slip that I can show him.”

“Yes! Let’s see it!” Han Li nodded with an indifferent expression.

The old man immediately searched his storage pouch for a yellow jade slip and hastily handed it over to Han Li.

Han Li bluntly took it and quickly immersed his spiritual sense into it. A second later, he felt shocked!

The crest appeared to be the same as the ghost head that the Six United Palaces’ Elder showed Wu Chou long ago. Although there were slight differences in appearance, it held a near exact resemblance. It seemed that the Righteous and Devil Dao had long colluded in secret, infiltrating other powers for many years with meticulous care.

Han Li was amazed and expressionlessly returned the jade slip to the old man.

Han Li casually said, “Since that is the case, you must be drawing close to Heavenly Star City so that you may observe the results of the battle and come to a decision afterwards.”

The old man revealed a trace of embarrassment. “That’s right, Senior. Under the command of our Sect Master, we are to head over and examine the situation. After all, our Three Immortals Sect isn’t a large organization, and can only choose to be pragmatic. However, in this short amount of time, Starfall Coalition has already launched an attack on the Outer Star Islands and has successfully taken them over. There were even islands that defected to the Starfall Coalition. It seem that the Inner Star Islands will soon be attacked as well. There are also a few scoundrels that have taken advantage of the situation to stir up havoc. Many rogue cultivators have ended up dead in the wilderness and no small number of small sects have ended up thoroughly exterminated.” The old man’s worrying words explained why so many cultivators had been so cautious as they traveled.

Han Li was very satisfied with the old man’s answer and calmly said, “So it was like that. Alright, since you have answered my questions, you may leave.”

“Then us Juniors will hastily set off.” The old man rejoiced at Han Li’s words and respectfully said his farewells before hastily leading the group away.

Although he saw that Han Li wasn’t an evil and vicious character, he couldn’t help but feel apprehensive in the presence of an unfamiliar Core Formation cultivator.

Han Li stood motionlessly in place as he muttered to himself.

A huge war has erupted between the Star Palace and the alliance of the Righteous and Devilish Dao. On the bright side, this war would certainly take up the Nascent Soul eccentrics’ attention. As they were aligned to either side, it would be impossible for them to avoid participating in the war. As such, he would be far safer as they wouldn’t be able to dedicate their time to tracking him or the Heavenvoid Cauldron down.

Conversely, the war would make it rather troublesome for him to return to Heavenly Star City. At the very least, the cultivators entering the city would be thoroughly inspected, especially a Core Formation cultivator such as himself. Furthermore, if a battle were to erupt in the city before he returned, he would be unable to enter. The Star Palace would likely bar any cultivators from entering during that time.

With that thought, he let out a sigh.

In the following few days, he intercepted several more low level cultivators and asked them the same questions, only to receive similar answers.

As a result, Han Li was now floating above the sea, blankly staring off into the distance with a face of hesitation.

He raised his head to look at the blue sky and flipped his hand, causing a small azure bottle to appear.

Han Li helplessly looked at the small bottle. Using the Myriad Year Spirit Milk so soon seemed like an immense waste, but if he didn’t hurry, the Starfall Coalition would launch an attack. His plans of entering Heavenly Star City and escaping to the Outer Star Seas through their transportation formations would then become null.

After a long while of contemplation, Han Li eventually opened the bottle with gritted teeth and carefully poured several drops of thick, transparent liquid into his mouth.

Afterwards, he placed the bottle away and put on his blood-red cloak before suddenly shooting through the sky and disappearing from sight. Half a month later, when Han Li had nearly exhausted his magic power, he took another few drops of spirit milk and continued to hurry on his way through the use of the blood-red cape. As a result, Han Li was able to travel at a speed similar to that of common Nascent Soul cultivators, and greatly reduced his travel time.

Along the way, the few Core Formation cultivators that he came across had mistaken Han Li to be a Nascent Soul expert and steered clear of his path.

As expected, there weren’t any cultivators that dared to even think of bothering a Nascent Soul expert.

Chapter 505: Ling Yuling

Han Li felt somewhat astonished upon hearing the person’s voice.

The sea beneath him rippled and flashed with white light before revealing a cultivator slowly flying out from the sea.

The new arrival wore the white attire of the Star Palace, possessed long black hair, and had an emerald-green headband embedded with jade.

Upon being able to clearly see the person’s appearance, Han Li revealed slight amazement.

The person had flawless white skin, thick dark eyebrows, delicate red lips, pointed eyes, and a thin nose. The Star Palace cultivator was undoubtedly beautiful, but what shocked Han Li was that he couldn’t tell whether the person was a man or a woman.

If this person was a woman, one might say that her mouth formed a natural smile and that her every movement carried a trace of confidence and ease. If one were to say the person was a man, then one might say that his beautiful appearance held an unconcealable charm, one that proved fatally attractive towards other men.

“Although I do not know your esteemed name, I am grateful for your rescue. I am the Star Palace’s External Affairs Enforcer, Ling Yuling.” While the person’s voice was pleasant, it was neutral in pitch. This caused Han Li to frown and feel apprehension.

This person reminded him of the Harmonious Bond Sect’s Young Master Tian [1] from the Heavenly South Region’s Devil Dao. But after some more thought, he felt that they were completely different. While Young Master Tian may have been extremely gorgeous, his mannerisms and voice were clearly that of a man. [2]

As for this Ling Yuling fellow, although “his” actions were that of a man’s, he held an indescribably effeminate aura. Moreover, with the deep magnetism in his voice, it was even more difficult to differentiate him as a man or woman.

“I am Han Li. My previous actions took but a slight effort. Had they not forced my hand, I wouldn’t have attacked them.” Although he still felt shocked, he didn’t reveal any hint of it on his face.

“Regardless, I am still very grateful towards you.” Ling Yuling smiled sweetly, casually producing a flirtatious charm.

Han Li felt his heart coldly tremble. As he still didn’t know whether or not he was a man or a woman, he could only turn a blind eye toward Ling Yuling’s beauty.

Ling Yuling retrieved his smile with eyes flickering in thought. He then solemnly said, “Is the reason why Fellow Daoist is in a hurry because he wishes to go to Heavenly Star City? The city should’ve already been locked down, and it would be quite difficult to enter. If Fellow Daoist is willing, I would be happy to take you into the city as compensation for your rescue.”

When Ling Yuling said this, Han Li felt somewhat surprised. But after some thought, he realized that he had already displayed his lack of association with the Starfall Coalition when he killed two of their cultivators.

As such, Ling Yuling took the initiative to make him an offer he couldn't refuse. Han Li slowly replied with a bright expression, “My cave residence was setup in Heavenly Star City, and I was in a hurry to return because of it. I must thank Fellow Daoist Ling for the trouble. Else, I may have been unable to enter the city.”

Ling Yuling beamingly smiled in response with bright, seductive eyes. “You’re too kind. Since Fellow Daoist was able slay those two without hesitation, you naturally won’t need any identification to enter the city. Our Star Palace welcomes you! However, those two weren’t the only cultivators in pursuit of me, nor were they the strongest. We had best hurry on our way.”

Han Li remained silent and nodded in response. The two then flew off towards Heaven Star City as streaks of light.

Along the way, Han Li curiously examined the other cultivator.

As Ling Yuling’s white clothes were slightly loose, Han Li wasn’t able to make out any female or male characteristics from the outside. Upon closer inspection, he discovered that Ling Yuling didn’t have a protrusion from his throat. [3] However, this wasn’t enough to to definitely prove that he was a woman. To the best of his knowledge, there were a few peculiar cultivation arts that reversed one’s Yin and Yang, altering portions of one’s gender characteristics.

‘This person wouldn’t be cultivating such a technique, right?’ Han Li strangely thought.

Having noticed Han Li’s gaze, the beautiful person charmingly smiled towards Han Li, causing him to turn his head away in embarrassment.

“Fellow Daoist possesses two ancient treasures, and seems to be favored by the Heavens. Although I’ve had the fortune to see many magic treasures, I’ve never seen one with abilities such as your copper bands. I wonder what are their origins.” As Ling Yuling flew in a streak of light, he casually mentioned Han Li’s ancient treasures for some reason.

Han Li replied vaguely, “It’s nothing. I have merely had more opportunities than ordinary cultivators.” There was no way he would so easily divulge the truth.

“Hehe, but Fellow Daoist did kill two similar grade cultivators by himself and can’t possibly be a common character. Would you be interested in joining our Star Palace? I can give you a recommendation.” Seeing that Han Li didn’t want to answer, he didn’t push the issue and casually changed the subject to recruiting him instead.

When Han Li heard this, he couldn’t help but frown. This Ling Yuling was quite difficult to handle. They had yet to arrive at the city and he’d already started to raise some serious questions. Any cultivators that joined the Star Palace now would become cannon fodder, but if he refused, would he still be granted access into the city? His own words would ensnare him.

After a moment of thought, Han Li sighed and spoke with deliberation, “Although I’ve looked up to the Star Palace for quite some time, the Exquisite Sound Sect has treated me exceptionally well. I’m afraid I cannot leave my post as the Exquisite Sound Sect’s guest elder in the coming years. I am truly sorry!” Han Li shamelessly used the Exquisite Sound Sect as an excuse to refuse.

“It is no matter. I feel much admiration towards Fellow Daoist Han’s exceptional loyalty. However, our Star Palace will always be willing to welcome individuals such as yourself into our ranks.” Ling Yuling didn’t reveal any dissatisfaction at Han Li’s tactful refusal. Instead, he faintly smiled and started to chat with Han Li about a few hidden rumors and interesting stories of the Scattered Star Seas. He tactfully avoided re-mentioning any matters pertaining to the Star Palace and Starfall Coalition.

Han Li was quite happy at Lin Yuling’s quick change in attitude, allowing him some time to relax.

As they idly chatted on their way, they eventually spotted Heavenly Star City and rejoiced. But before they managed to get close to the island, a squad of five cultivators appeared before them from seemingly out of nowhere.

Their leader was a sallow-faced middle-aged early Core Formation cultivator. The other four cultivators were all at Foundation Establishment.

“We pay respects to Enforcer Ling!” Upon recognizing Ling Yuling, the four Foundation Establishment cultivators flew forwards and respectfully saluted him.

It seemed this androgynous person held quite the reputation in the Star Palace.

The sallow-faced cultivator revealed pleasant surprise and asked, “Junior Martial Brother Ling, are you alright? Senior Martial Brother was quite worried upon hearing that Southclear Island had been ambushed. Hm? Who might this Fellow Daoist be?” The sallow-faced cultivator then turned his sights on Han Li and suspiciously examined him.

Ling Yuling spoke with a serene expression, “I was pursued by two Starfall Coalition cultivators along the way, but thankfully, Fellow Daoist Han came to my rescue. As Fellow Daoist Han’s cave residence was established in Heavenly Star City, I’ve brought him back here. There should be no problem in allowing Fellow Daoist Han into the city, yes?”

Not knowing whether it was due to fatigue from the rush to the city or some internal injuries, Han Li saw that Ling Yuling’s face had grown somewhat pale, causing him to appear somewhat fragile.

“Since he is someone who saved the life of Junior Martial Brother Ling, this will be no problem at all. Junior Martial Brother Ling, are you injured?”

When Han Li saw the sallow-faced cultivator’s extremely concerned expression, his heart stirred.

“It is nothing. Although they struck me with a magic treasure, I had the protection of my Heavenly Fragrance Chain, and didn’t suffer much damage.” Ling Yuling’s beautiful face faintly blushed, but his expression still remained calm.

After a moment of hesitation, the sallow-faced man took a small bottle from his body and politely passed it over to him, “I have a Heaven Spirit Pill that was refined from a secret formula. Junior Martial Brother Ling, please take it and prevent any lasting damage to your vital energies.”

When Ling Yuling saw this, his expression sank as if he were about to become angry. But he soon thought of something and instead smiled with passionate eyes, saying, “Then Junior Marital Brother must thank Senior Martial Brother for the medicine. I must first head into the palace and report on Southclear Island. I’m afraid I must ask Senior Marital Brother to help Fellow Daoist Han into the city. As he is my saviour, Senior Martial Brother must treat him properly.” Ling Yuling then smiled, taking the bottle with his slim, flawless hand in a very graceful manner. In that moment, it appeared he was undoubtedly a woman.

The sallow-faced cultivator revealed excitement as if he were honored to hear Ling Yuling’s pleasant words. “It is not a problem. Since Elder Wang is on duty, he won’t make things difficult for Junior Martial Brother,” he then slapped his chest and pledged, “Please don’t hesitate to leave Fellow Daoist Han with me.”

When Han Li saw this, a strange expression flickered from his eyes.

Was this person a woman or not?! Why else would the sallow-faced man appear so infatuated with Ling Yuling?

Han Li’s heart was in great turbulence.

[1]. The ‘gorgeous man’ first introduced in Chapter 257: Blood Sacrifices and a Glamorous Male.

[Back]

[2]. TL Note: Since there are no gender neutral singular pronouns in English, Ling Yuling will be addressed as ‘he’, despite having an indeterminate gender.

[Back]

[3]. Commonly known as an adam’s apple.

[Back]

Chapter 506: Requirements for Access

For a long while, the sallow-faced cultivator gazed in the direction that Ling Yuling had flown off in. He eventually turned his gaze back to Han Li and calmly said, “Although Fellow Daoist did assist Junior Martial Brother Ling, there are still a few questions I must ask you. As these are trying times, I hope Fellow Daoist will cooperate!”

Han Li calmly replied, “If Fellow Daoist has any questions, please don’t hesitate to ask.”

The sallow-faced cultivator nodded his head and said, “Good. First, tell me your identity. I will be verifying whether or not it is true.”

Han Li smiled upon hearing this. “I am an elder of the Exquisite Sound Sect. This is my badge, and this is the restriction control medallion to my cave residence in the city. I’m sure that Fellow Daoist will know whether it is genuine or fake.”

“Exquisite Sound Sect? Take a look and see if the Exquisite Sound Sect has an elder named Han.” The sallow-faced cultivator bluntly took both of the medallions, and gave an order to those behind him without turning his head.

“Yes!” When the dainty female cultivator heard him, she hastily rummaged through her storage pouch before taking out a jade slip and immersing her spiritual sense within it. Afterwards, she glanced at Han Li several times before speaking with a respectful tone, “Enforcer Zhao, the Exquisite Sound Sect does have an elder named Han Li and his appearance is exactly the same as is recorded.”

When the sallow-faced cultivator heard this, he expressionlessly nodded his head, “Oh! These two medallions are genuine as well. There seems to be no problem with your identity!”

The sallow-faced cultivator tossed the medallions back to Han Li, “Alright, you four continue on your patrol. I will be bringing this Fellow Daoist into the city.”

The four behind him shouted in acknowledgement, “Yes!”

Afterwards, the sallow faced cultivator wordlessly beckoned to Han Li and flew off toward Heavenly Star City. Han Li closely flew after him as a streak of azure light.

Not long after, the sallow-faced cultivator brought Han Li to the high walls of the city before flying up towards a city gate.

Although there was no further interrogation, Han Li released his spiritual sense to examine his surroundings, discovering at least six hidden cultivators along the way. Although they were mostly Foundation Establishment cultivators, there were two Core Formation cultivators that remained unseen.

Although his face remained calm, his heart trembled. It seemed the attack on Southclear Island had prompted Heavenly Star City to introduce greatly increased security as he had expected. Had he not been given a referral, he feared it wouldn’t have been an easy task to enter the city.

The city gates appeared quite desolate. Apart from the tens of white clothed cultivators standing guard outside of it, there was no one else present. In addition, as Han Li came closer to the city, he discovered that the walls and the gate were glowing with faint white light as if they were under the effects of a restriction.

After the sallow-faced cultivator landed on the gate, he headed straight towards an old man that was reclining in a bamboo chair. He had a short beard and whiskers all over his face.

He saluted the old man and spoke with a respectful tone, “Enforcer Yu! This is the Exquisite Sound Sect’s Elder Han. I’ve already inspected his identity and command medallion, and I’ve found no problems. I must trouble Enforcer Yu to explain the procedure for entering the city. I cannot stay much longer as I must continue on my patrol.”

Han Li’s gaze fell onto the old man and he immediately put his guard up. It was no wonder that the sallow-faced cultivator was so polite to him. He was a mid Core Formation cultivator.

The old man slowly opened his eyes as if he were still half asleep, “Exquisite Sound Sect?”

After a moment of hesitation, he somewhat reluctantly added on, “That’s right, and he righteously assisted Junior Martial Brother Ling as well.”

A cold glint flickered in the old man’s eyes, faintly revealing a spirited energy before it immediately disappeared. Then with a powerless voice, he lazily said, “Oh, that is strange. Alright, I understand. Fellow Daoist Zhao may return.”

The sallow-faced cultivator seemed to not mind the old man’s mannerisms and saluted him before flying off, paying Han Li not the slightest heed.

Han Li calmly stood in place and silently looked at the old man.

“I’ve seen the Exquisite Sound Sect’s Young Girl Violet Spirit many times before. She truly is a fine beauty. I’ve heard of you, Exquisite Sound Sect Elder, but unfortunately, I’ve never had the chance to meet you before. It seems from your youthful appearance, that you also cultivate a technique that halts the aging of your appearance, much like our Fellow Daoist Ling. To the best of my knowledge, these cultivation techniques are all extreme Yin in nature. There are little benefits if a man were to cultivate it.”

With serene calm, Han Li asked, “Do your words mean that Fellow Daoist Ling is a man? As for my appearance, that is the result of a Face Setting Pill that I took long ago, not a cultivation technique.”

The old man let out a muffled chuckle before speaking with an impressive lack of speed, “Even our Star Palace is unsure of whether Fellow Daoist Ling is a male or female, let alone me. However, it is undoubtable that he cultivates a technique that halts his appearance. Haha, it seems Fellow Daoist Han’s luck is quite good to come across an opportunity to consume a rare medicine pill.” Han Li felt astonished.

The old man continued, “Alright, I won’t dwell on the matter. Since your identity has already been examined, this old man won’t bother to do so. However, as the times are unordinary, the rules will be as well. Fellow Daoist, listen well to what I have to say.”

Han Li raised his eyebrows and remained silent.

The old man’s expression grew sullen and he said with an icy tone, “Right now, Fellow Daoist has two options. You can join the Star Palace for the time being if you are willing to assist us in our fight. In this case, your movements will be unrestrained within the city. And each time you carry out any missions, you will be heavily rewarded. There is no way we would allow anyone’s efforts to be in vain. If you are unwilling to fight in the war and wish to stay idly in the city, we won’t force you to fight, but as the city is currently under martial law, no one is allowed to casually leave their residence unless it is during a specified time. Our enforcement squads in the city will slay anyone who does not follow these rules. Fellow Daoist Han can now tell me his choice.”

A strange expression flickered from Han Li’s eyes. For a time, he silently sunk into contemplation.

When the old man saw this, he didn’t rush Han Li. He only narrowed his eyes, revealing a slightly crossed expression.

After muttering to himself for a moment, Han Li solemnly asked, “After I enter the city, would I be able to use the Outer Star Seas transportation formation?”

“Originally, it would’ve been fine so long as you paid the spirit stone toll. However, it will no longer do. If you wish to go to the Outer Star Seas, you will have to do something for us.” The old man didn’t appear surprised as if he had already anticipated Han Li’s question.

Although Han Li already guessed what it would be, he still frowned and asked, “What would that be?”

The old man faintly smiled, and lightly said, “It’s quite simple! As soon as the battle starts, you will get an assignment from the Star Palace to eliminate a Starfall Coalition cultivator at the same rank of cultivation as yourself.” His smile seemed to resemble a smirk.

Having heard this, Han Li bitterly laughed in his mind. It seems the upper echelons of the Star Palace intended to coerce cultivators that wished to leave the city. Even if the Star Palace couldn’t control them, they would be required to spill the blood of Starfall Coalition cultivators. On the one hand, it would weaken the might of the Starfall Coalition. On the other, it would prevent those cultivators from ever joining the enemy.

Using a single breath, Han Li quickly said, “I’ve already killed similar ranked cultivators on my way back with Fellow Daoist Ling. Does that count?”

“You’ve already killed one?” The old man appeared quite moved.

“That’s right,” Han Li nodded his head without hesitation.

“Unfortunately, that won’t count. It must happen after the battle has started. There is no point if you kill any of them beforehand.”

Han Li stroked his chin and pensively asked, “When does Fellow Daoist reckon that the battle will break out?”

The old man was slightly surprised by Han Li’s question and took another look at Han Li before calmly replying, “It should be as soon as the next few days, I imagine. The Starfall Coalition isn’t planning on attacking the inner island, but rather is aiming to take over Heavenly Star City in an ambush in the quickest time possible!”

Without further deliberation, Han Li calmly said, “I will enlist. I’ll be wanting to use the Outer Star Seas transportation formation after I kill a cultivator of the same rank.”

The old man patted down his body before fishing out a sparkling yellow ring. He then indifferently handed it over to Han Li and said, “Good! Put this ring on. It represents that for the time being, you will be a member of the Star Palace. When the battle comes, the ring will give you an assignment.”

Chapter 510: Blackmail

The person Han Li was requesting a spot from was the shriveled man.

“What did you say?” Alarm flickered across the shriveled man’s face, soon to be replaced with anger.

The others glanced at each other, not knowing what Han Li intended.

Han Li calmly said, “Be at ease, Fellow Daoist, I won’t allow you to do this in vain. I have two grade five demon beast cores. Take it as payment for your spot. Surely Fellow Daoist won’t turn his back on me.” He then searched his robes and took two shining blue globes out of nowhere. From their emitted spiritual Qi, they were genuine grade five demon cores.

The shriveled man looked at the two demon cores with a trace of greed, but he soon thought of something and coldly snorted, “Humph! Does your esteemed self think that I will give up my place for a measly two demon cores?”

Han Li didn’t grow angry. Instead, he strangely smiled and his lips trembled several times, sending several voice transmissions to him in everyone’s presence. The shriveled man suddenly paled after hearing them.

Han Li then spoke to him with a leisurely tone without using a voice transmission, “With this, there should be no way Fellow Daoist could possibly refuse this trade. Am I correct?”

When the shriveled man heard Han Li, his nervous face became lined with cold sweat. After fiercely glaring at Han Li for a moment, the shriveled man’s face twitched as he clenched his teeth and said, “Fine! Since Fellow Daoist can say that, I will hand over my spot to you!”

Those words came as a shock to the other six.

The embroidered-robed man’s expression sank and he stared at the shriveled man. He coldly said, “Fellow Daoist Zhang, what are you saying? Didn’t we say that we were going together? Why did you...”

The shriveled man bitterly laughed and helplessly said, “I am truly sorry, but I fear we must part for the time being. You should all go first. I will join you if there is another opportunity.”

The embroidered man spoke no further, nor did the rest of the party. It was now apparent that something was being used against their Fellow Daoist Zhang in order to force him to relinquish his spot. Hence, there was no point in continuing the discussion. Fortunately, a lack of one person didn’t make too much of a difference in their plans.

The bald old man frowned and imposingly glared at the shriveled man, “Humph! Who said you could exchange people as you wished.”

“Senior Gu, I...” The shriveled man was startled and thought to mutter an explanation, but he couldn’t come up with anything.

But at that moment, Han Li produced two jade boxes with a flick of his hand, tossing one each to the bald old man and the scholarly man at his side.

When the two saw the jade boxes, they unconsciously caught them and calmly gazed at Han Li.

Han Li spoke with a serene appearance, “The boxes contain two treasures that Junior unexpectedly acquired. Please take them Seniors.”

The two gave each other a mutual glance with curiosity in their eyes. From their examination of the boxes, it seemed that they contained no tricks. They then carefully opened the boxes by a sliver to release several rays of red light.

The two unconsciously revealed pleasant surprise upon seeing what was within.

With a moved expression, the scholarly man said, “Does Fellow Daoist Crooked Soul truly wish to hand these two treasures over to us?”

Han Li faintly smiled and said, “Junior understands that although the items are precious, they are of no use to him at his current cultivation. Junior wishes even more to head out to the Outer Star Seas so that he can continue his peaceful cultivation.”

The bald old man couldn’t contain his joy and without any discussion with his partner, he hurriedly agreed, “Hehe! Good. Since Fellow Daoist Crooked Soul has given us such a grand gift, we won’t be unreasonable. You can use the transportation formation with the other six.”

Although Cultivator Qian appeared unhappy, he was also tempted by the item in his hand and didn’t say anything in opposition.

This scene shook the hearts of the Foundation Establishment cultivators, causing them to feel a huge desire to see what those boxes contained. However, the boxes were quickly closed by the two Star Palace cultivators. As they didn’t dare to use their spiritual sense to pry, they were left helpless.

However, when the embroidered-robed man took another glance at the two jade boxes, a trace of amazement flickered in his eyes. Although he couldn’t see what the boxes contained, from what they had said, he couldn’t help but think of the words “magic treasure”. Could it be that this person had truly given them magic treasures? Despite being just a guess, he couldn’t help but feel amazed.

Before the embroidered-robed man could finish his thoughts, the two Star Palace cultivators turned around to the transportation formation behind them and began to chant an incantation with their hands grasping a white jade medallion.

The Foundation Establishment cultivators didn’t see anything odd about this, but Han Li let out a long sigh of relief.

“Lucky... The transportation formation has a trick to it. Had I charged in without knowing this, I would find myself in a difficult situation. It seems taking out a few undesirable yet somewhat valuable magic tools was quite an incisive move.”

The jade boxes each contained a flying knife magic treasure that sparkled with red light. These two flying knives were taken from Hu Yue after the Bone Sage had killed him.[1]

Although these magic treasures weren’t particularly amazing, they were exceptionally precious to ordinary Core Formation cultivators.

Even if the magic treasure couldn’t be linked to one’s consciousness, it could be directly used at seventy percent of its strength without the need of investing a large amount of time or resources. This was something that ordinary Core Formation cultivators could only dream of acquiring.

Although many magic treasures have been passed down throughout the years, a majority of them had been destroyed in battle. Even with the remaining magic treasures, most of them would fall into the hands of Nascent Soul Cultivators or exceedingly powerful Core Formation cultivators. Though, they would occasionally fall into the hands of a few nameless cultivators and minor powers.

Huge superpowers like the Star Palace obviously acquired many magic treasures but conversely, they also had an exceedingly large number of Core Formation cultivators.

If these two early Core Formation cultivators didn’t earn any merits, they wouldn’t be bestowed any magic treasures. As such, they were wild with joy to find a magic treasure unexpectedly falling in their grasp. After refining them, their strength would receive a massive increase.

As such, the shriveled man could only obediently hand over his place. Han Li had a full grasp over the situation.

When Han Li saw the shriveled man’s expression on his return to the residence, he grew suspicious and infiltrated his room. Although there didn’t exist any magic techniques that could completely control a cultivator’s consciousness, Han Li was able to put him into a half conscious daze. With a combination of bewitchment techniques along with his immense spiritual sense, he was able to force out the shriveled man’s deepest thoughts.

Although the shriveled man only spouted out intermittent phrases during this state, Han Li ended up quite lucky, acquiring information that the shriveled man and the two Star Palace cultivators had deliberately raised the price to squeeze the other Foundation Establishment cultivators for all they had.

With this information to blackmail him along with the enticement of the two demon cores, the shriveled man meekly submitted to Han Li; his heart filled to the brim with apprehension to the point of near panic. He couldn’t help but think, ‘Did the Star Palace cultivators deliberately set me up?’

As the incantations reverberated throughout the hall, the transportation formation began to glow with white light. Following a clear ring, the white glow suddenly disappeared.

After seeing that the restriction had disappeared from the formation, the bald old man turned to the party of Formation Establishment cultivators and bluntly said, “Normally, these is another manager of the hall, but as luck would have it, he was sent to the Star Palace Hall to handle emerging affairs in the past day, otherwise you would’ve had to pay far more. Alright, come and hand over your spirit stones.”

When that was said, each of the cultivators immediately took out a storage pouch they had prepared ahead of time and handed them over to the bald old man.

As for Han Li, he took out another two demon beast cores and handed them over, arousing a trace of astonishment from the old man’s face.

After examining each of the payments, the bald old man nodded with satisfaction. Seeing this, the scholarly middle-aged man took out a stack of talismans and began to pass them out amongst Han Li and the others.

He pointed to the transportation formation and coldly said, “These are displacement talismans. You can leave after placing them on your body.”

The others were hesitant, but Han Li walked into it without a word.

It wasn’t that he was displaying courage, but that he had found nothing wrong with the transportation formation after quickly sweeping it with his spiritual sense.

The stone tablet in front of the transportation formation read the words “Wondrous Depths”.

Han Li didn’t have any particular impression towards this name. From his last experience, it seemed that the islands’ names didn’t hold much significance.

[1]. Hu Yue was killed in Chapter 425: Congealed Yang Birds, and his magic treasures were taken in Chapter 429: Ruined Map Reconstruction.

[Back]

Chapter 516: Demon Echo Grass

Forgoing any needless pretensions, Han Li bluntly asked, “Does Fellow Daoist Gu happen to know about Thousand Leaf Dew?”

“Thousand Leaf Dew?” Gu Yu paused for a moment before quickly replying in a mutter, “This name has a bit of an impression on me. Had you asked me about it a few years ago, I would’ve had no idea. In the past two years, this Junior obtained an ancient record that happened to mention it. This Junior happens to have a duplication of it on a jade slip. Would Senior like to take a look at it?” Having said that, Gu Yu revealed a somewhat cautious expression.

Han Li rejoiced and couldn’t help but reveal excitement in his eyes.

Suppressing the excitement in his heart, Han Li smiled and said, “It is even better that you have the records. If I do find it, then I must truly thank you.”

Gu Yu was also quite pleased. Being able to receive the favor of a Core Formation cultivator was a truly fortunate matter.

He quickly patted down his body before taking out a yellow jade slip and presenting to Han Li with both hands.

Gu Yu respectfully said, “This is the jade slip. Please examine it, Senior!”

Han Li bluntly accepted the jade slip and quickly immersed his spiritual sense into it.

In a mere moment, Han Li’s expression changed from excitement to doubt and then contemplation.

Li Xun carefully watched Han Li’s every movement. Upon seeing Han Li’s expression change several times, an indescribable emotion flickered from his eyes.

Gu Yu was particularly apprehensive, fearing that the Thousand Leaves Dew that was mentioned in the jade slip wasn’t the item Han Li was searching for.

Han Li eventually recalled his spiritual sense from the jade slip and slowly said, “Yes, this is the item.” However, the excitement in his eyes had greatly faded.

After the old man’s gaze flickered he probed, “What is it? Is there something troublesome about the Thousand Leaves Dew?”

Han Li bitterly smiled. “I didn’t expect that this item would be so troublesome to acquire. It’s closely related to grade eight demon beasts.”

Li Xun shockingly glanced at Han Li with an expression of disbelief, “Grade eight demon beasts?”

Han Li sighed and helplessly explained, “That’s right. The Thousand Leaves Dew is actually an extract of Demon Echo Grass. To be more exact, from Demon Echo Grass that grows close to grade eight demon beasts.”

Li Xun was left speechless by Han Li’s words.

He naturally knew what Demon Echo Grass was. It was something that often grew near demon beast nests as it required long years of exposure to demonic Qi to grow and sustain itself. However, Demon Echo Grass found near the den of a grade eight demon beast was an entirely different matter altogether.

Although it was rumored that grade nine and even grade ten demon beasts had been sighted in the Outer Star Seas, at the end of the day, they had only appeared in rumors. As for the old man, the highest grade demon beast he had seen at Blackrock City was a grade seven demon beast, let alone a grade eight demon beast.

Li Xun saw that Han Li’s gaze held a trace of astonishment and discouragement. Just what kind of precious medicine pill did he plan on refining, to actually require such an incredulous material?

After toying with the jade slip in his hand, he revealed a trace of hesitation before saying something to Gu Yu that surprised him, “This jade slip has some records that I may need to further examine in the future. Would it be acceptable for Fellow Daoist Gu to give this jade slip to me?”

Gu Yu paused for a moment and then frankly said, “If Senior has a use for it, then please feel free to take it!”

Seeing that Gu Yu was being quite agreeable, Han Li nodded his head and flipped his hand, summoning a small bottle and a talisman with a drawing of a small yellow sword on it.

“As your Senior, I naturally can’t let you come out of this empty handed. The bottle has some medicine pills that can increase your cultivation, and this is a treasure talisman. Go ahead and take them.” Han Li then casually tossed the items over to him.

“Many thanks for Senior’s generosity!” After receiving the items, Gu Yu was unable to contain his joy and repeatedly thanked Han Li. To a Qi Condensation cultivator like himself, these items were truly precious.

“Since Senior Crooked Soul has already bestowed treasures upon you, you may leave for the time being, Gu Yu.” Li Xu was quite shocked at Han Li’s display of generosity, but he still remembered to dismiss Gu Yu with a calm expression.

In the blink of an eye, they were once again the only two people in the room.

“Is there anything else that I may assist you with apart from that matter? Please don’t hesitate to ask.” Li Xun spoke in an exceptionally forthright manner.

“Since that’s the case, there is one other thing that I wish to trouble you with. Might you be selling the horn of an Agate Beast?”

“Hehe, Fellow Daoist came to the right place! Although Agate Beast Horn is an exceptionally rare material, I managed to purchase two such horns last month. If Fellow Daoist desires it, I can sell one to you right away.” The old man clapped his hands with a smile and immediately gave the order for it to be delivered without a moment of pause.

Pleasant surprise appeared on Han Li’s face as he repeatedly expressed his thanks.

Not long after, a young servant entered the room while carrying an exquisite wooden box on a silver plate.

“Fellow Daoist, take a look. Does this Agate Horn fulfill your expectations?”

Han Li solemnly nodded his head and reached out to the wooden box. As soon as he opened the box, blue light was released, revealing a half-foot-long spiral horn. The sharp horn shined with a strikingly brilliant blue light.

Han Li then closed the wooden box with a satisfied expression, “Not bad! This will be quite suitable. Could Fellow Daoist tell me how many spirit stones this will cost?”

Li Xun pleasantly smiled and said, “This store acquired the horn for five thousand spirit stones. Since Fellow Daoist requires it, you only need to return the cost.”

Naturally, Han Li wasn’t going to haggle over the price. He immediately expressed his thanks and took out the equivalent in mid grade spirit stones before handing it over to the old man.

The old man received the spirit stones with a wave of his sleeve and then asked with a wide smile, “Does Fellow Daoist Crooked Soul have any plans in mind following his arrival on the island? Although Fellow Daoist’s magic power is profound, the demon beasts here are truly hard to handle. No small number of Core Formation cultivators have been seriously injured by tackling the seas alone. How about I introduce you to a few similar grade cultivators? It would be considerably safer if you were to set out to sea together.”

Han Li smiled upon hearing this. The purpose of the old man’s courteous and friendly behavior from the beginning was for drawing him in.

“Many thanks for Fellow Daoist Li’s kindness. However, I must soon prepare to refine a few medicine pills. And after I consume the pills, I will have to enter seclusion for some time. I won’t be heading out to hunt demon beasts in the near future.” Han Li gave a smooth refusal with an embarrassed expression, but in truth, he was absolutely unwilling to travel out to sea with unfamiliar cultivators.

Although a trace of disappointment flickered across his face, he immediately continued without a care, “That is fine too. It is considerably safer to first increase one’s cultivation and one’s familiarity with the region. However, if Fellow Daoist Crooked Soul does later wish to find companions, please don’t forget about me!”

Han Li naturally agreed and further chatted with the old man for a moment before taking his leave.

The old man saw Han Li off at the building’s exit before returning inside.

Just as the old man sat down, he suddenly heard a voice calmly say, “How about it? Will this person be useful to us?” A vague silhouette soon emerged from the landscape painting on the wall, bringing forth another person into the room.

The white-clothed man remained in the air while covered in azure light, making for a rather mysterious display.

The old man confidently said, “There is no need to worry. Although we only chatted for a short moment, from his strange appearance, that cultivator Crooked Soul should be a vagrant cultivator that travels alone. So long as he witnesses the dangers of travelling the depths alone, he will come to know the advantages of my offer. He will come back sooner or later.”

The white-clothed man coldly refuted, “Humph! That isn’t guaranteed.”

Li Xun shook his head, “What? An early Core Formation cultivator can roam the depths and hunt demon beasts alone?”

The white-clothed cultivator grew silent before solemnly saying, “He isn’t an ordinary Core Formation cultivator. When you were chatting in the room, I was able to feel someone watching me for some unknown reason. Although he didn’t glance in the direction I was hidden, I suspect that he was aware of my existence and only chose not to disclose it.”

The old man was stunned. He then bewilderedly said, “Are you not mistaken? Your concealment technique is something that even higher grade cultivators are incapable of uncovering. Don’t tell me that this Crooked Soul fellow is actually a late Core Formation cultivator.”

The white-clothed man doubtfully said, “That’s hard to say! It is quite possible that he cultivates an unusual cultivation art or possesses some peculiar treasure.”

After circling the room several times, the old man eventually frowned and said, “Leave it be. Regardless of whether this cultivator is exceptional or ordinary, we’ve already tried our hardest to befriend him. It was the correct decision either way!”

The white-clothed cultivator nodded in approval and spoke no further.

Chapter 525: A Fearsome and Resounding Reputation

“Brother Qiu, do we attack? It seems like he’s really alone.”The fierce-looking man’s voice held a trace of nervousness.

The gaunt old man stared at him with a doubtful expression, but didn’t reply.

When the three saw the youth take out a black alms bowl and start to extract the Vivid Glass Beast’s soul, their expressions greatly changed with a trace of fear appearing within their eyes.

The cultivator surnamed Min saw the old man’s hesitation and couldn’t help but frown. He probingly said, “This person is quite odd. How about we leave him be? There is no need to provoke any mysterious characters.”

As the three had managed to survive in the Scattered Star Seas for such a long time, they were naturally very cautious people. The scene before them was, without a doubt, indescribably strange. It even caused Cultivator Min to recoil!

The old man’s gaze wandered for a long while before he bitterly smiled, and listlessly said, “Leave him be? This is no longer a matter of choosing to attack him, but rather, how we will leave here alive.”

These words caused the fierce-looking man and Cultivator Min to freeze. They were fully aware of the old man’s temperament and knew that he wouldn’t say something like this without reason. As such, they soon revealed astonishment.

The old man licked his lips and spoke with an agonized whisper, “You two might not have noticed, but doesn’t this person resemble the recent rumors of that devil?”

“Devil? Then could he be...?”

“So it was him!”

The two immediately let out a cry of alarm. Their faces were aghast!

The old man solemnly muttered as if he were speaking to himself, “Absolutely. He appears young, can release several flying swords, and moreover, his sword light is azure. Just like the rumors!”

The fierce-looking man’s complexion turned white. He said with a trembling voice, “Wasn’t that person also well-known to use a swarm of flying insects? He hasn’t revealed them since we’ve arrived. That can’t be a coincidence!” It appeared he had been shaken stiff by the old man’s words.

Cultivator Min turned slightly green and sent out a voice transmission in a whisper, “Brother Qiu’s words are correct. This devil ordinarily reveals himself to be at early Core Formation and is fond of extracting the souls of demon beasts. The reason why he hasn’t release his flying insects should be that he didn’t feel the need to!”

“You’re saying that this guy is the rumored ‘Insect Devil’? Then why are we still here? If we face him, we’re certain to perish.” The fierce-looking man appeared to be panic-stricken.

The old man managed to regain his calm and said, “Don’t lose your head! Even if it truly is the Insect Devil, his attention was occupied with the Vivid Glass Beast when we arrived. As a result, we had remained undiscovered. Now that he has killed the demon beast, we will expose ourselves if we act rashly.”

The other two glanced at each other and saw the sense in the old man’s words. As such, they didn’t dare to act impulsively.

As the large man stared at the youth extracting the demon beast’s soul, something suddenly came to mind. He whispered with a doubtful expression, “I heard that four years ago, the Insect Devil contended for a grade seven demon beast against a group of nine Core Formation cultivators. He managed to kill eight of the Core Formation cultivators by himself, but a single late Core Formation cultivator was fortunately able to escape. Could those rumors be true?”

Cultivator Min dryly swallowed a few times before whispering, “They should be! The man who survived was an expert from the Jade Cloud Sect, and the ones who died were his fellow Sect Members. That fight caused the Jade Cloud Sect, once renowned as one of the five great powers of Wondrous Depths Island, to lose an entire third of their forces. The Jade Cloud Sect’s Chief Elder, Daoist Master Swift Crane, was enraged by this and personally scoured the seas several times by himself in search of the insect demon. However, he returned unsuccessful each time. Many people believed even if he found the Insect Devil, nothing would come of it. After all, from the abilities he displayed, it is quite possible that he is actually a newly ascended Nascent Soul Expert. It is said that the other factions of Wondrous Depths Island have already taken note of the Insect Devil and wish to recruit him.”

After a moment of silence, the old man shook his head and said, “Nascent Soul Stage? Not necessarily. I’ve heard that there is nothing exceptional about the insect demon’s cultivation; all of his fearsomeness comes completely from his strange insects. It was said that on the day of that battle, he hadn’t used any magic treasures and merely released countless flying insects, devouring the many Core Formation cultivators alive without even lifting a finger. That was how he received the name of Insect Devil.”

Cultivator Min persisted, “However, Brother Qiu also saw that he didn’t use his insects and was able to kill Vivid Glass Beast in a single strike. Even late Core Formation cultivators would find it difficult to replicate this feat. Surely he must be a disguised Nascent Soul eccentric.”

The old man still disapproved and thought to further speak when the fierce-looking man at the side interrupted him with a helpless tone, “Fellow Daoists, it makes no difference for us whether or not he is a Nascent Soul cultivator. It is almost certain that he would be able to kill us with great ease. Even we are fearful of his evil reputation; it is said that all cultivators who encountered the Insect Devil were all devoured by his insects. The number of cultivators that have fallen by his hand is no less than a hundred. In the last two years, this devil has already become a topic of fear.”

Cultivator Min appeared even more unsightly after hearing this. His gaze fell onto the blue-clothed youth and he let out a long breath before saying, “The Insect Devil is truly vicious and bloodthirsty. It should be true without a doubt. There were no small number of cultivators that had been killed for their treasures, and all claim it to be the work of this devil! And to think we came knocking on his door!” His voice was filled with regret.

When the old man heard this, his face also became unsightly, but he spoke no more. He was also greatly fearful toward the evil reputation of the Insect Devil.

In the following moments, the three ceased to use voice transmissions and silently watched the youth’s every movement. They wished for him to quickly finish dealing with the demon beast so they could get away as soon as possible.

At that moment, the blue-clothed youth finished drawing out the soul of the Vivid Glass beast into the black alms bowl. He then rummaged through the demon beast’s corpse for a white demon core.

At that moment, the youth suddenly raised his head and glanced around.

When the three saw this, they all held their breaths and kept their bodies perfectly still.

However, the situation developed contrary to their wishes.

The youth’s gaze suddenly turned to the direction that the three were hiding in. With a slight sneer on his face, he coldly said, “You three Fellow Daoists have been watching me for quite some time. Have you had enough to look at? How about you come out and show yourselves?”

Having heard this, the three suddenly felt a chill run down their spines!

“Run!” It was unknown which of the three shouted this, but they immediately flew off as streaks of light and split off in three different directions in a panic-stricken manner.

The blue-clothed youth frowned and muttered, “I haven’t even finished speaking yet. Why did they flee with such fear? Did they fear that I would eat them?” A trace of confusion appeared on his face.

But soon after, the youth waved his arms with a sullen expression, and sent three spirit beast pouches into the air, filling the sky with a torrent of tri-colored beetles.

This youth was obviously Han Li, who had just returned from the far seas.

The old man stealthily peeked his head around only to find a scene that left him aghast, causing him to unconsciously speed up.

At that moment, a series of soft sounds leisurely left Han Li’s mouth.

When the tri-colored beetles heard him, they gathered towards the sky and instantly condensed into three huge lances spanning about three meters each. Then with a sharp and loud whistle, the three lances blurred with brilliant light and separately shot out with miraculous speed.

In an instant, the lances tore through the sky, disappearing into the horizon and chasing down the three cultivators that had fled.

Han Li stood in place without any intention of chasing after them. Instead, he started to leisurely skin the translucent Vivid Glass Beast with a streak of azure light.

The hide of the Vivid Glass Beast was a top-grade material for refining armor. He naturally wasn’t about to give it up. Then after turning the rest of the remains to ashes, Han Li retrieved the Rainbow Skirt Grass and his spell formation setup tools from the coral island.

Just as he finished this, three flashes of light appeared on the horizon and flew in Han Li’s direction. After they grew closer to him, he was able to clearly see that they were the three cultivators that previously fled.

These three cultivators all had tri-colored collars around their necks. Their pale faces wore expressions of crestfallen resignation.

Han Li grasped his chin as he saw this, but he secretly smiled in his heart.

After the three meekly fell before Han Li, he smiled and asked them with an exceptionally friendly tone, “May I ask you three Fellow Daoists, why you so flusteredly ran away from me? Could it be that you three recognize me?”

Alternative Title

Chapter 533: A Gift

After looking through the slips with tool refining and spell formation information, the young woman was quickly sweeping through a jade slip that introduced medicine pill formulas and demon beasts. After she was done with it, she moved on to the next jade lip on the table. Immediately after immersing her spiritual sense into it, she was stunned.

It contained a cultivation art known as the “Golden True Arts”. Out of curiosity she read through it for a moment before her attention was completely drawn in. She read the jade slip for no less than an hour before withdrawing her spiritual sense in a daze. She wore an expression of fear on her face.

This Golden True Arts was the precious top-grade cultivation art of a sect. Why was its cultivation incantation so casually placed on a table without any restrictions guarding it?

Although the young woman knew the cultivation art’s value, she still reluctantly put it back in its original place after some hesitation. Now she was even more interested in looking through the rest of the jade slips on the table.

Half a day later, the young woman had finished browsing through all of the jade slips on the table. A vast majority of the jade slips contained teachings about either formation spells or medicine pills. Only a small number contained cultivation arts, but there wasn’t a single one present that wasn’t top grade. There was one particular cultivation art, the “Coiling Jade Arts”, that left her particularly tempted.

The Azure Spirit Sect was only a tiny sect in the Scattered Star Seas. Its main cultivation art, the Azure Spirit Arts, was merely a standard cultivation art. It couldn’t possibly compete in terms of might with the Coiling Jade Arts.

After glancing through the jade slips, her mind wandered for a moment before recalling that there were still other places that she had yet to explore. She left the stone room and walked back to the large hall.

Of the remaining three arched doors, there were two that were guarded by puppets, leaving her with only one that she could enter. As a result, the young woman entered the only unguarded door.

After entering, she was left stunned and remained motionless for quite a while.

There was a sixty meter wide hall with a thirty meter wide spell formation placed at its center. The spell formation released a barrier of translucent, faint-red light. The light fluctuated and sparkled intermittently, revealing a magnificent sight.

The light barrier contained dozens of variously fashioned swords, spears, and other such items. There were a few that released a clear ring, and some that chased after one another, but all of them appeared to possess intelligence.

Outside of the light barrier, there were two layers of crude wooden racks lining the walls. Each of the racks held a variety of magic tools. Although they didn’t have a light barrier blocking them, they each flickered with brilliant light and contained vigorous amounts of spiritual Qi.

Although the young woman hadn’t seen any of them before, she was able to tell that the items contained inside the light barrier were like the magic treasures from legend with the intelligence that they displayed.

The young woman had always yearned to look at such magic treasures, but unfortunately there were just far too many before her. Eyes filled with amazement, she couldn’t bring herself to believe what she was seeing.

A long while later, she finally came to her senses. After further looking at the light barrier with a strange expression, she hesitantly walked towards the wooden racks. She casually took a pitch-black ruler and examined it, discovering that the unremarkable item was actually a high grade magic tool.

But having already experienced far too many surprises before this, she hardly revealed any shock at the discovery.

She then began to look through each of the magic tools on the racks, all of which were either high or top grade. There was nothing of inferior quality present.

Had the young woman managed to acquire one of these magic tools in the past, she would’ve been immensely excited. Now after glancing at the many magic treasures and hundreds of magic tools, the young woman left the room with empty hands, after recalling that she was now but a cultivation vessel.

Two days later, inside the stone room with the jade slips, the young girl was sitting down on a round stone block. She was concentrating on the contents of the jade slip in her hand.

“The Coiling Jade Arts are quite suitable for a female cultivator, though they were acquired by male cultivator, namely me.” A man’s gentle voice suddenly came from the doorway.

The young woman felt her heart tremble and quickly withdrew her spiritual sense. She then flusteredly turned around.

She saw a blue-robed youth with an ordinary appearance standing by the door. He was looking at her with a smile.

Gongsun Xing hesitantly asked, “You, you’re Senior?”

Although his voice was somewhat similar, this gentle-faced youth was truly too young. It was completely different from what she had imagined.

Having experienced so many astonishing things, the young woman had come to expect the Senior to be an old man with profound, mystical abilities. She even apprehensively guessed that he was a tempermental eccentric!

“What? Am I not as expected?” The youth was Han Li who had just left seclusion. He walked into the room with a faint smile.

“Senior, these cultivation arts, I...” For some unknown reason, she inwardly felt relieved upon discovering that Han Li was the owner of that expert’s voice. However, she still stuttered trying come up with an explanation.

Han Li indifferently said, “It doesn’t matter. Since I didn’t forbid you from entering, I was allowing you to chose a cultivation art.”

“Many thanks to Senior!” The woman expressed unconcealed happiness with delightful charm.

Upon seeing the young woman’s excitement, Han Li unconsciously felt a tinge of emotion.

Han Li smiled and casually asked, “It’s been a while since I’ve been to the outside. Would Lady Gongsun happen to know anywhere in the seas that one might be able to trade?”

The young woman’s smile vanished as if she had thought of something. After quickly taking a peek at Han Li, she lowered her head and softly said, “If one wishes to trade... about half a month south, there is a barren island with a market city. The nearby cultivators conduct trade there. I heard that there were several Core Formation cultivators that joined hands to keep the peace there. Does Senior require a map?”

Han Li confidently said, “I must make a trip there. Naturally, a map would be good.”

The young woman flusteredly took out a jade slip from her storage pouch and handed it over to Han Li with a red face.

Han Li smiled and reached out to take the jade slip. At the same time, a strange expression flickered from his eyes when he saw the young woman’s flushed, tender face. He suddenly reached out to touch her soft, luscious hair.

Gongsun Xing’s heart trembled with slight fear, but she didn’t shrink back. She only unconsciously turned her head away.

At that moment, Han Li’s soft voice entered her ear, “Don’t be afraid. Come to my bedroom tonight. Don’t forget.”

After he said this, he left the room without further hesitation.

When Gongsun Xing heard these dubious words, she felt her heart jump and her face turned crimson, revealing an adorable appearance of complete embarrassment.

When night arrived, she arrived outside Han Li’s bedroom in a complicated mood. She entered the stone room as she nibbled on her lips, but she was left surprised by what she saw.

The bedroom had no one inside. There was only a stone desk with an unfurled scrolled on it.

After a moment of hesitation, Gongsun Xing walked over puzzled and lowered her head, reading, “Your filial behavior is quite laudable. I give all the remaining treasures in the cave residence to you. Don’t show them to others, or you will attract calamity upon yourself. Do your best!”

There was nothing else after that, leaving the young woman at a complete loss. She could only feel blank confusion along with an indescribable emotion.

At that moment, Han Li had already flown five hundred kilometers away from the small island in a streak of azure light.

Smiling, Han Li leisurely thought, “I’m sure that girl must be completely baffled. Anyone going through such an unpredictable experience should be left amazed for at least half a day!”

When he had left the sea mist, he had stripped the cave residence of everything apart from the jade slip containing the Coiling Jade Arts, numerous unwanted magic tools, along with a few medicine pills and two looted magic treasures that he left behind specifically for the girl. These items would surely allow the young woman to tread to future heights that are rarely reached on the path of cultivation!

This rare showing of immense generosity wasn’t due to a sudden feeling of tenderness towards the fairer sex. But rather, the young woman’s resolve to sacrifice herself for her father had deeply moved Han Li.

If Han Li had any regrets before setting foot on the path of cultivation, it would be that he was unable to fulfill his filial duties to his parents after reaching adulthood. Although he had secretly made arrangements with the Seven Mysteries Sect Master for his family, it didn’t offset the sense of loss he felt deep in his heart.

Additionally, the young woman’s appearance had reminded Han Li of the last he had seen his little sister when she had gotten married.

As such, he had deliberately used the pretense of having the woman as a cultivation vessel in order to give her a few benefits. Of course, the magic tools and treasures that Han Li had left for her posed little to no value to him.

Since the items would remain useless on him, it would be better for him to take the opportunity to give them to the girl, providing her the assistance to tread farther on the path of Immortal cultivation. The woman’s spiritual roots were also inferior, just like his own had been.

As for Han Li’s cave residence, he had already decided that he would abandon the island the next time he left, long before these people had arrived.

Chapter 535: Trade Gathering

When Huang Mingli heard Han Li’s desire to depart, he agreed with an embarrassed smile. He then flew off to the east on his magic tool while Han Li leisurely followed after him with a calm expression.

As Huang Mingli flew, he turned his head to steal a glance at Han Li’s face, and carefully asked, “Senior’s face is quite unfamiliar. Have you been in secluded cultivation for a long time? Junior might’ve heard of your name before!”

Han Li casually said, “My surname is Li. I’ve remained in my cave residence for secluded cultivation until recently, when I finally formed my core. It isn’t surprising that Fellow Daoist Huang hadn’t heard of me before.” Of course, Han Li didn’t give his real name.

The small old man didn’t notice anything amiss from Han Li, and could only speak words of congratulations despite still holding a few doubts in his heart.

Huang Mingli was quite tactful and didn’t further inquire about Han Li. Instead, he took the initiative to tell Han Li about a few of the recent confrontations between cultivators and demon beasts. However, from his deep sighs, it seemed the old man didn’t hold much hope towards humanity’s future in the Outer Star Seas.

Although the endless conversation was almost entirely one-sided, Han Li had gained a much greater understanding towards the current circumstances of the Outer Star Seas.

Nothing strange occurred in the following half month, allowing Han Li and the small old man to eventually spot a small, peaceful island in the distance. This island was only about fifty kilometers in area and possessed sparse amounts of spiritual Qi. Apart from a small growth of vegetation, the island only consisted of bare grey rock and appeared like any other desolate island.

It was an optimal location for a secret city. But even in that case, about half a day out, Han Li and the old man concealed their flight and approached the island under the guise of concealment techniques.

This, of course, was a requirement for entering the secret city.

When Huang Mingli beseeched him to conceal himself, Han Li silently complied without any complaint. This was a great relief to Huang Mingli as Core Formation cultivators weren’t always particularly easy to deal with in his experience.

Huang Mingli flew a circle around the small island before landing on a heap of rocks.

When Han Li saw this, a strange expression flickered from his eyes. If he wasn’t mistaken, there shouldn’t be any restrictions there. Could it be...?

As Han Li continued to mull this over, Huang Mingli stepped towards a large rock beside him and knocked three times on the stone with practiced familiarity. A short moment later, the huge rock suddenly split open to reveal a three meter wide hole.

Huang Mingli immediately stepped into the hole and softly said a few words into it. He then turned to Han Li and shouted, “Senior Li, it’s right here. Let’s go in!”

Han Li indifferently looked down and descended from the sky.

The hole led to a set of slanted stone stairs. To the side of the stairs stood a grey-robed, white-haired old man with a late Foundation Establishment cultivation.

Upon seeing Han Li enter, the old man smiled at him and spoke in a manner that was neither arrogant nor humble, “Senior, welcome to our market city. I hope Senior will be able to find what he needs.”

“I hope so as well.” Han Li calmly replied as he climbed down the stairs.

Han Li realized that in order to prevent any demon beasts from detecting spiritual Qi, formation spells couldn’t be established. As such, the only option left to maintain secrecy was building everything underground.

After walking down the stairs for a short time, Han Li’s eyes brightened.

There was an expansive underground world before him. The ceiling was twenty meters high with occasional pillars of transformed grey stone supporting it. There were many small square buildings at the center of the cavern, each sporting their own sign. There were over a hundred cultivators trading amongst these stone buildings.

At Han Li’s side, Huang Mingli pointed to a set of descending stairs beside a stone pillar and said, “Senior Li, this floor is only for trading ordinary items. If Senior wishes to acquire rare materials, it would be best to go down to the next floor.”

Han Li glanced at the stone stairs, but didn’t move. He asked with a deep voice, “If I wanted information on the whereabouts of a high grade demon beast nest, where could I find it?”

Huang Mingli was obviously startled upon hearing this. A trace of confusion flickered from his eyes before he answered with great familiarity, “It would depend on what grade of demon beast Senior requires information about. If it’s grade five or six demon beasts, Senior can head over to the Wind Whisper Pavilion. They specialize in selling the whereabouts of difficult to acquire treasures and high grade demon beasts, allowing one to acquire them based on their own skill. However, they won’t have any information on demon beasts of a higher grade. In that case, your only option would be to ask other Core Formation Seniors. After all, the whereabouts of demon beasts of that grade aren’t easily divulged. Senior could participate in the trade gathering specifically for Core formation cultivators. Perhaps that is where Senior can find what he is looking for.”

“Trade gathering?” Han Li’s expression revealed a trace of excitement.

Huang Mingli carefully explained, “That’s right! Normally, only other Core Formation cultivators have the materials and treasures that a Core Formation cultivator would need. As a result, every time the market city opens, the city lord will hold a meeting where Seniors gather together for a private, small-scale exchange, where they can trade for what they wish. The city lord would also take out several rare items for the meeting as well.”

With a faint smile, Han Li slowly asked, “When does this trade gathering take place?”

The small old man promptly replied, “Senior Li will likely have to wait a few more days. I reckon around halfway through the opening of the market city, Senior will receive an invitation to join.”

When Han Li heard this, he narrowed his eyes and wore a pensive expression as if he were thinking about it.

A short moment later, he glanced at Huang Mingli and spoke without restraint, “Fellow Daoist Huang, I plan on going the rest of the way alone so we’ll be parting ways here. I no longer require your assistance.” Han Li didn’t wish to have someone following him around while he was searching for the Thousand Leaves Dew.

The small old man wasn’t particularly surprised by Han Li’s words. With a beaming smile, he said, “Senior’s words suits Junior’s intentions as well. Junior happens to want to go buy a few materials. Then I will bid you goodbye. If Senior requires any further assistance, then please do not hesitate to find me.” Huang Mingli respectfully saluted Han Li and bid his farewells. He then headed into a nearby materials store. It seemed he wished to first sell off those demon breasts corpses from before.

Han Li was quite satisfied with how tactful and quick-witted the old man had behaved.

He swept his gaze past the nearby stores and walked into the store across from him with his arms behind his back. The first store he entered had piles of all sorts of medicinal ingredients.

……

Inside a quiet room, Han Li was resting with eyes closed. He felt somewhat gloomy.

During his first day in the market city, he had browsed both floors of the market city and found plenty of Demon Echo Grass but none that had grown near a grade eight demon beast. In addition, the Wind Whistle Pavilion didn’t have any information on demon beasts of grade seven or higher. He could only wait for when the trade gathering convened and see if any other Core Formation cultivators had relevant information.

In the following two days, he had no intention of heading out and rented a quiet room specifically to cultivate and see whether or not he could break through his current bottleneck.

In the end, he had achieved nothing.

Thumps came from the door of his room. Although Han Li had anticipated this he still indifferently asked, “What is it?”

A woman’s pleasant voice respectfully said, “Senior Li! Junior is under orders to invite you to the trade gathering. Would Senior be interested in participating?”

Han Li slowly replied, “Yes, of course I am!” He then opened the stone door and walked out of the room.

There was a white clothed woman standing outside with a lowered head, respectfully waiting for him. When she saw Han Li appear, she immediately raised her head and revealed a charming face.

When Han Li saw the woman’s beautiful face, he felt his heart tremble. After staring at the woman’s face, a flicker of astonishment appeared within his eyes.

‘How could it be her? What is she doing here?’ Han Li thought, astonished.

The woman saw Han Li staring at her, causing her to blush. She then lowered her head and uncomfortably asked, “Senior, is something wrong?”

Han Li quickly regained his bearings and calmly said, “It’s nothing. Lead the way.”

The white clothed woman faintly felt that something was amiss, but she respectfully agreed and walked away with calm steps.

Gazing at the woman’s silhouette, Han Li unconsciously frowned and wore a face full of confusion.

Passing through the plaza of the second floor, the woman brought Han Li to a remote stone wall.

The woman gently pressed her hand against the wall, creating ripples of white light and revealing a stone door covered in talisman characters.

Chapter 540: Concubine

The island had several mountains that rose above three hundred meters, and were lush with verdant forestry and filled with many trees.

Han Li circled around the mountains before descending onto one of them with Wen Siyue in tow.

Under the woman’s astonished gaze, Han Li released his flying swords and carved a small cave residence into the mountain after a few hours. Although the cave residence was less than half the size of his cave residence in the misty island and was far more crude, it still had a bedroom, and seclusion room, along with a tool refinement room, medicinal garden and so on.

Han Li appeared quite satisfied and placed down several formation spells around it before bringing Wen Siyue inside.

Han Li brought Wen Siyue into the bedroom and sat on a hurriedly carved stone chair. After examining the woman, he leisurely said, “You will be living here from now on. I will tell you the incantations for the spell formations. This place is quite secluded. If you diligently cultivate, there is a chance you’ll enter Core Formation.”

“Many thanks, Senior Li!” Wen Siyue blushed underneath Han Li’s gaze, appearing to be at a complete loss about what to do.

Han Li smiled, “Senior Li?”

Wen Siyue hastily hung her pretty head and hesitantly said, “Sorry... Should I call you...?”

Having just become his concubine, she didn’t know how she should address him.

Han Li rubbed his nose and indifferently said, “You can call me Mister Li!” Han Li had yet to reveal his true appearance. He had still assumed the form of a middle-aged man.

After a moment of hesitation, Wen Siyue obediently replied, “Yes, Mister Li!”

Han Li nodded his head with satisfaction and thought about what he should say. He then softly asked, “When did Fellow Daoist Wen arrive at the Scattered Star Seas, and how did Lady Fan become the Exquisite Sound Sect’s Sect Leader? According to my knowledge, Fairy Violet Spirit should’ve been the sect leader.”

“Yi! Mister Li seems quite knowledgeable of the sect’s past.” Wen Siyue was quite amazed that Han Li had made inquiries about the Exquisite Sound Sect instead of hurriedly asking about the demon beast nest.

But after some thought, she opened her almond lips and explained, “The Exquisite Sound Sect was entirely managed by the Young Sect Master before we teleported to the Outer Star Seas. But while she was out at Heavenvoid Hall, a startling change occurred when we returned to the sect. The Envoy of the Left disappeared without a trace and all of the power in the sect fell into the hands of an outsider and the Envoy of the Right, Lady Fan. I later discovered that this cultivator was a Devil Dao cultivator and that the Exquisite Sound Sect had already become a vassal of the Devil Dao. In order to establish herself as sect master, Lady Fan immediately gathered together a large number of disciples and sent us through Heavenly Star City’s transportation formation. At the time, I had been coerced into travelling along. Since then, our sect has handled this hidden city. The disloyal female disciples have been mysteriously disappearing over the past few years and those that have been given away were never seen again. Were it not for Mister Li saving my life earlier, I fear I would’ve become a cultivation vessel.” Wen Siyue dimly said.

Han Li’s expression stirred. Hiding his intentions, he asked, “What did your Sect Master Fan do in the Outer Star Seas? It can’t be that she only managed the hidden city!”

“I am not too sure about this. However, Lady Fan and that Devil Dao cultivator surnamed Yun were gathering all sorts of information with the assistance of the hidden city as if they were looking for something.” Wen Siyue spoke with uncertainty and an expression of doubt appeared on her face.

When Han Li heard this, he ceased asking questions and started to mull over what she had said. It seemed a violent usurpation had occurred while he and Fairy Violet Spirit were trapped in Heavenvoid Hall.

With the successful usurpation of power, Lady Fan immediately brought large quantities of disciples to Wondrous Depths Island. Afterwards, the Starfall Coalition had launched an attack on Heavenly Star City. It seemed that regardless of how the Devil Dao took over the Exquisite Sound Sect, it was clear that the influence of the Starfall Coalition was immense. Otherwise, they wouldn’t have been able to take over the sect at such an opportune time.

By the time Fairy Violet Spirit returned from Heavenvoid Hall, she would’ve discovered that her sect was gone.

As for the Devil Dao powers, they were drawing support from the Exquisite Sound Sect to find someone or something in the Outer Star Seas. This was yet another mysterious aspect that had nothing to do with Han Li. Hence, he was disinclined to further ask about it. Furthermore, he had already become irreconcilable enemies with Daoist Master Swift Crane, and it seemed the current Exquisite Sound Sect had a relationship with him. As such, Han Li was even more unwilling to be tied down by them and had refused Lady Fan’s proposal.

As for returning to the Inner Star Seas, Han Li wasn’t even considering the matter until after he broke through his bottleneck. While it was true that demon beasts were running amuck in this land, with the greatly desired Heavenvoid Cauldron in his hands, the Inner Star Seas might not necessarily be safer.

Han Li repeatedly mulled over Wen Siyue’s words in his mind after a short moment. He found nothing that sounded incorrect; to the best of his knowledge, she was telling the truth.

It was only natural for Han Li to be this careful, as he possessed the famed Heavenvoid Cauldron. Who knows how many Nascent Soul Eccentrics wanted to lay their hands on it. Even since ancient times, countless men had suffered from the wily tricks of beautiful women. Han Li didn’t wish to become one of them out of a moment of carelessness.

But of course, the odds of this woman attempting to deceive him were next to nothing. He had suddenly appeared before her as a person that nobody recognized and brought her to an unknown place. He was also under the effect of a secret technique that even early Nascent Soul cultivators couldn’t see through.

At that moment, Wen Siyue saw Han Li’s expression fluctuate, and she unconsciously revealed a trace of restlessness.

Having finally collected his thoughts, Han Li noticed the beautiful woman’s peculiarity. He faintly smiled and said, “I’ve already brought you away from the hidden city, and I’ve even arranged this location for you. How about you tell me about the location of the demon beast nest? After you tell me, I’ll immediately head off and you’ll never see me again.”

Wen Siyue blankly stared for a moment before revealing surprise, “Senior doesn’t intend on taking me in as a concubine?”

Han Li calmly said, “I am used to travelling alone. I don’t need anybody following after me.”

After a moment of silence, her beautiful face wore a complicated expression and she gently shook her head. After a strange emotion flickered within her eyes, she serenely said, “Many thanks for Mister Li’s kindness! But since I’ve already decided to become your concubine, I don’t have any thoughts of reneging on it. Senior, please be at ease, Siyue will keep her promise without complaint.”

Han Li clearly understood the woman’s apprehension, and he couldn’t help but mysterious smile, saying, “I don’t know what Fellow Daoist Wen intends, but my words hold firm. If Fellow Daoist truly wishes to settle the matter and become my wife, I won’t further decline. When that happens, Fellow Daoist Wen had better not regret it!”

He was certain that Wen Siyue didn’t want to become anybody’s concubine. The conditions raised in the hidden city were most likely raised out of helplessness.

Although being a concubine was far better than being a cultivation vessel, there weren’t any Foundation Establishment woman that would be willing to become someone else’s concubine. This only happened in desperate circumstances or under coercion.

Although Han Li felt quite tempted by Wen Siyue’s exceptional beauty, he clearly understood that he was at a crucial point in his cultivation. He couldn’t afford to keep a Foundation Establishment woman by his side. It would be far better to let her go free and drop the subject!

“I...” Doubts began to surface after Han Li explained his words. Hesitation appeared on her face.

A trace of amusement appeared within his eyes. Han Li softly said, “What? Don’t tell me that Fellow Daoist still wishes to become my concubine?”

“No!” Wen Siyue’s hurriedly refused and after a moment’s pause, she bit her lip and saluted Han Li, saying, “I... I must give many thanks to Mister Li! Junior Wen Siyue will never forget your kindness!” Her expression was filled with anxious fright.

“Since that is the case, let’s drop the matter of being a concubine. There is no need for Fellow Daoist Wen to take it seriously.” Han Li had no intentions of deliberately making this difficult.

“Many thanks, Mister Li!” Wen Siyue was joyfully surprised! Her expression relaxed and her flowery beauty blossomed, producing an emotionally stirring scene.

Upon seeing this, Han Li felt a ripple of emotion, but he quickly buried this emotion at the bottom of his heart.

After calming himself, Han Li serenely asked, “Fellow Daoist Wen, how about telling me about the Wind Breaker Beast!”

Wen Siyue’s smile disappeared. She said with a worried tone, “Mister Li, the Windbreaker Beast’s nest is somewhat dangerous. It is near the edge of the depths. Please clearly consider it for a moment before heading out to the nest.”

“The edge of the depths?” Han Li frowned. It seemed this would prove quite troublesome.

The current depths were beyond dangerous!

Chapter 554: Rush to the Exquisite Sound Sect

At Han Li’s current cultivation, even without using either the blood-red cloak or the Thunderstorm Wings, he was capable of flying at an astonishing speed. In less than half a month, Han Li arrived at the desolate island that had once been the location of the Exquisite Sound Sect’s hidden city. After sweeping his spiritual sense across the island, he didn’t find a single soul. It seemed he would have to search for humans elsewhere and acquire the information from them.

Han Li glanced around before casually choosing a direction, and disappearing in a streak of azure light.

Since the Exquisite Sound Sect had moved after establishing their city on this island, they shouldn’t have moved far away. Additionally, the nearby seas should be an area where some of the surviving human cultivators have gathered. Han Li was confident that with his vast spiritual sense, he would be able to find some human cultivators without much effort. As expected, about half a day later, Han Li discovered traces of many human cultivators on a medium sized island.

Looking down from the sky, he saw many male and female cultivators being besieged by two grade four demon beasts from the nearby seas.

When Han Li spotted a few familiar faces among them, he faintly smiled.

Soon after, he used the appearance exchange art to assume the form of a dark-skinned, middle-aged man. He then casually launched two azure swordstreaks at the demon beasts with a wave of his hand. With a flash of light, a hole appeared through the heads of each of the demon beasts as they fell to the ground.

This sudden display had alarmed the many cultivators below, and they immediately turned their heads towards the sky to discover Han Li. An uproar arose among the cultivators at the appearance of the newly arrived expert.

After consulting amongst themselves, a large man with an embroidered robe eventually flew towards Han Li.

“Many thanks for Senior’s assistance. Is there anything that us Juniors may help you with?”

Although the large, embroidered-robed man spoke with a respectful tone, a trace of unease could be seen on his face. Just why did this Core Formation cultivator suddenly appear at this island?

Han Li didn’t immediately respond upon seeing the embroidered-robed man, Yi Jing, who had teleported with Han Li to Profound Depths Island. Han Li narrowed his eyes and swept his gaze past the rest of the cultivators, only to recognize the scar-faced man Xu Yun. None of the other cultivators that had arrived at Wondrous Depths Island along with him were present.

As for Yi Jing and Xu Yun, it seemed they had failed at forming their cores, as they were still at the late Foundation Establishment despite the many years that had passed.

Yi Jing grew somewhat nervous upon seeing Han Li continue looming in silence. After a moment of hesitation, he was about to speak again when Han Li cut him off, “I am looking for the Exquisite Sound Sect’s hidden city. Do you know the next time it will be open and where it will be?”

With an indifferent expression, Han Li gazed intently at Yi Jing.

When he heard Han Li’s question, Yi Jing’s expression relaxed and he tactfully replied, “Senior, the Exquisite Sound Sect’s city will be opening in about a month, and is set to open at Twin Peaks Island. It is several days west of here, and if Senior wishes to go, Junior can bring him there.”

Han Li shook his head and mildly said, “There’s no need for that. It’ll be fine if you just give me a map.” He had no interest in reminiscing about times long past with this person.

The man was quite lucky. He had managed to survive the Beast Torrent, but the others likely hadn’t shared the same fate as him, causing Han Li to feel a slight sadness.

“Yes! Senior, here is a map of the sea and the location of the hidden city.”

Yi Jing revealed slight disappointment, but he still hoped to forge a friendly relationship with the Senior before him. With each passing day, the Outer Star Seas became increasingly dangerous for human cultivators. It would be greatly advantageous for him to be acquainted with a Core Formation cultivator.

But after taking another glance at Han Li’s detached expression, he could only drop the matter and take out a jade slip from within his robes. He recorded the location of the Exquisite Sound Sect into the jade slip and offered it to Han Li with both hands.

Han Li received it with a nod and took a quick look through it with his spiritual sense. Then without the slightest intention of staying, Han Li rushed through skies in a streak of azure light.

The low grade cultivators that were left behind gazed at him with envy. Nowadays in the Outer Star Seas, cultivators at Foundation Establishment and lower didn’t have the freedom to stray too far from their cave residences.

Han Li wasn’t about to meekly wait for another month as he feared that if he didn’t leave as soon as possible, Feng Xi would come knocking at his door. As a result, he was prepared to pay the Exquisite Sound Sect a significant sum to quietly teleport back to the Inner Star Seas. Of course, if they refused or became too greedy, he wasn’t going to shy away from using force.

Several days later, Han Li arrived at Twin Peaks Mountain. The island was quite expansive and had two huge mountains that were nearly the same in height.

After flying around of the mountains several times, he found the entrance to the hidden city as described on the map. After a moment of hesitation, Han Li changed his appearance back to what he had used when he had last visited the city. He then descended at the center of the mountain and took several steps towards a tree that was ten meters wide and about a hundred meters tall.

He expressionlessly glanced at the huge tree and couldn’t help but scoff. He lightly flicked his finger, sending three orbs of white light to directly knock against the tree’s bark.

A short moment later, azure light flashed and an opening appeared within the tree bark. A white-clothed old man at late Foundation Establishment walked out. He was the same gatekeeper that was in charge of the city entrance the last time he was here.

The old man recognized Han Li at a glance.

After all, there were very few Core Formation cultivators that had attended the meetings of the hidden city. Additionally, he had caught a few rumors during the last opening of the market city about how this cultivator had managed to single handedly suppress over ten Core Formation cultivators. It was very likely that the person in front of him was a Nascent Soul cultivator.

Upon seeing Han Li, the old man lowered his head and hastily gave him a deep salute, “So it was Senior Li. I hope Senior won’t take offense, but may I ask what is your business for coming? There is still another month before our hidden city convenes. There are no treasures for Senior to browse.”

The old man spoke with a respectful tone, but his eyes appeared puzzled.

Han Li examined the old man and raised his head before speaking in a deliberately arrogant manner, “I haven’t come for the hidden city. I’ve come to meet with either Sect Master Fan or Elder Yun.”

“You wish to see the Sect Master or Elder Yun?”

The old man paused for a moment before revealing a trace of hesitation.

“What? Is there a problem?” Han Li’s tone was void of emotion and his expression grew eerie.

When the old man saw this, he shivered and immediately smiled, saying, “Of course not!” A trace of cold sweat could be seen on his brow.

After some thought, the old man sincerely said, “Were it anyone else, it wouldn’t do. But since Senior personally arrived, then it must be about something important. This little old man will report back. As it just so happens, Sect Leader Fan recently arrived to take care of the arrangements for the hidden city. Senior, please wait for a moment!” He decided to hand off this troublesome matter to those above him. He couldn’t afford to offend such a fearsome character!

Han Li was happy to find that Lady Fan was present and his expression relaxed. He then said, “Then please be quick about it. I don’t have much time.”

The old man felt relief and hastily replied, “Yes, Junior will use a voice transmission talisman to inform the Sect Master. It will only take a moment!” If Han Li decided to force his way through, he would only be able to watch helplessly. There was no way he would throw his life away to try to block him. As a result, he took out a sound transmission talisman in front of Han Li and sent it into the tree’s opening.

After seeing the the sound transmission talisman disappear, Han Li expressionlessly asked, “Where is Elder Yun? Why isn’t he with your Sect Master?”

The old man’s expression grew unsightly. He hesitated for a moment before muttering, “This... Junior truly doesn’t know about the whereabouts of Sect Leader Yun. Matters regarding this recent market city have all been handled by the Sect Master alone.”

Upon seeing the old man’s expression, Han Li was sure he knew what the old man had meant. With a cold chuckle, he no longer continued asking the old man any questions, much to his relief.

A short moment later, the white clothed cultivator received a sound transmission talisman. After quickly examining it with his spiritual sense, he respectfully said, “Senior Li, our Sect Master invites you inside for a chat. I will lead the way.”

Han Li indifferently replied, “Go ahead.”

The city below the tree was largely the same as the last hidden city with two floors making up a large underground expanse. But this time, apart from the many low grade Exquisite Sound Sect disciples preparing the city, there were no others inside.

The old man quickly brought Han Li to a stone wall that was attended by two outstandingly beautiful female cultivators.

The two female cultivators both respectfully bowed to Han Li with flushed complexions and charmingly said, “We pay our respects to Senior Li. The Sect Master welcomes you and is honored by your presence.”

Chapter 555: Exposed

Han Li glanced at the two women’s expressions and stroked his chin in thought before wordlessly nodding his head.

One of the women reached out to the stone wall with her hand and summoned a stone gate in a flourish of azure light.

“This is as far as I can lead Senior. I will be taking my leave.”

The old man took the opportunity to hastily withdraw.

Han Li didn’t pay him any mind and walked inside. After passing through a short passageway, Han Li arrived within a large hall.

Wearing light green robes and a slight hint of make-up, Lady Fan respectfully awaited Han Li at the center of the hall with a beaming smile.

The woman deferentially bowed to Han Li and said, “I hope Senior hasn’t taken offence that I didn’t personally welcome you.”

She then pulled out a chair and offered him a seat. He glanced at the chair with a raised eyebrow and sat down without the slightest restraint. Afterwards, his gaze fell onto the woman’s beautiful face and he serenely said, “It seems Lady Fan isn’t worried that I came with the intention to harm your sect.”

Lady Fan walked to the side with light steps and took a seat at Han Li’s side. She covered a smile with her hand and said, “Senior jests. With Senior’s cultivation, how could he trouble himself over a Foundation Establishment Junior?”

At that moment, Lady Fan was only a meter away and her fragrant scent assailed his nose. Han Li faintly frowned, but otherwise his expression remained normal. However, when the woman took a seat, she unconsciously revealed a trace of astonishment. Afterwards, she examined Han Li with a strange expression.

With a cold glint passing through his eyes, Han Li thought to inquire about her actions, but at that moment, a dainty young woman walked over and placed a cup of fragrant tea in front of them before standing behind Lady Fan.

Lady Fan appeared indifferent to this, but a scowl had momentarily appeared on her face.

When Han Li glanced at the two women, his mind began to stir.

Lady Fan took a sip of the tea in front of her and pursed her lips. She then calmly asked, “Does Senior require something from our sect? We will do our utmost to assist if possible.”

“Since Lady Fan mentions it, I won’t drag this on. Did your sect already complete the transportation formation to return to the Inner Star Seas? I wish to use it.” Han Li casually spoke of the matter as if he had mentioned a trifling thing.

“Transportation formation?” Lady Fan paused for a moment, and her beautiful eyes blinked before revealing a mysterious smile. “I’m afraid I must disappoint you. The transportation formation has yet to be completed. However, it is possible that it will be completed soon. If you’d wait a while longer...”

Han Li didn’t wait for her to finish and callously interrupted her, “How much longer?”

Senior Fan hesitated for a moment before placing the cup back down onto the table. She explained, “It’s hard to say. Senior should already know that we lacked the Phantasm Stone for the spell formation. Elder Yun and the other Seniors went to retrieve more of the stone, but they alarmed the demon beasts in the region. A huge battle erupted and they were only able to acquire a meager amount of materials at the cost of many Seniors. Helpless, Elder Yun could only make a plan for future action. In fact...”

The female cultivator standing behind Lady Fan let out a small cough.

A sullen expression momentarily appeared on Lady Fan’s face, but she soon stopped speaking as if a problem had arisen.

A trace of surprise appeared on Han Li’s face, but after coldly gazing at the female cultivator behind Lady Fan, the woman fearfully lowered her head.

After a moment of thought, he stood up and said, “Since the transportation formation can’t be used in the near future, then there is nothing to be said. I will be taking my leave.”

When Lady Fan saw this, a complicated expression flickered within her eyes. She hesitated for a moment before saying, “Although we cannot help you with regards to the transportation formation, our sect has always held Core Formation Seniors in high esteem! How about Senior retires here for the night and sets off tomorrow?”

“Spend the night here?” Han Li thought to refuse her, but after looking into her eyes, he changed his mind, “That’s fine. I’ll set off the morning after then.”

Lady Fan smiled with an odd expression, “Hehe! Our sect will be sure to properly entertain you. Servant, bring Senior Li to our best room.”

A young woman promptly entered the room. Without speaking any unnecessary words, Han Li followed her outside.

However, when he was about the leave the hall, he thought to verify something and shot a deep glance behind him before calmly leaving.

After Han Li left the hall, the young woman that stood behind Lady Fan said, “Sect Master! Why do you intend on having him stay? Isn’t that rash? This Senior Li rejected our enticements the last time around.” Her voice was pleasant, but it contained an indescribable allure that was far superior to what her pretty appearance would grant her. Although her tone would still be considered respectful, it contained much doubt.

“Yun Qin! You’re growing quite bold! I was merely attempting to forge good relations with a cultivator who possesses astonishing strength. Since when did you take charge of the Exquisite Sound Sect?”

Lady Fan grew sullen.

“I don’t dare. This disciples was merely following the orders of Elder Yun before he departed. I hope Sect Master won’t perform any actions that will make it difficult for me.” The young woman spoke with a humble tone, but displayed no intention of backing down.

“Humph! I will naturally inform Tian Yunxiao of this when he returns. As I still have duties to perform as Sect Master, I hope you’ll forgive me for not keeping you company!” Lady Fan’s expression grew icy and with a wave of her sleeve, she departed without looking back.

Only the young woman remained in the hall, wearing a complicated expression.

...

Inside a comfortable room, Han Li was lying down on a wooden bed, pondering as he stared at the ceiling.

He didn’t have any worries about spending the night at the market city. He had already swept his immense spiritual sense across the city and found that of those in the city the highest cultivation were at late Foundation Establishment. There were no Core Formation cultivators here, let alone any Nascent Soul eccentrics. Apart from any startling surprises, there was nothing to worry about.

However, he was now pondering whether or not he should spend the many years to fly back to the Inner Star Seas.

Suddenly, he heard a few knocks on his door.

“Come in.” Han Li said as he remained motionless on the bed. It seemed like he knew who was there and had been expecting them.

A sweet laugh came from the other side of the door and the door was pushed open to reveal Lady Fan. She walked into the room with lithe footsteps, fully displaying her thick black hair and extraordinary beauty.

Carrying her fragrant scent, she sat on the side of Han Li’s bed without the slightest discomfort and smiled at him, saying, “Senior still hasn’t slept despite the late hour. It seems he already knew that I was coming.”

With his eyes still shut, he calmly said, “Sect Master Fan was obvious enough during our meeting. So, what matter did you need to discuss with me in secret? I’ll let you know ahead of time that if it has nothing to do with the transportation formation, I am not interested.”

“Of course. With so many Nascent Soul eccentrics currently pursuing him in the Outer Star Seas, it is only natural for Elder Han to wish to return.”

Han Li’s body stiffened and he opened his eyes. He attentively stared at the woman before him and coldly asked, “What? Who is this Elder Han?”

Lady Fan stared back at Han Li with a calm expression and leisurely said, “I am naturally speaking of my sect’s own Elder Han.” She didn’t appear flustered in the slightest.

After a moment of silence, Han Li sat up and recovered his calm before slowly asking, “How did you recognize me? With your cultivation, you shouldn’t be able to see through my true appearance.”

With her slender white hand, she pulled back her hair and replied with a crafty expression, “I didn’t see through you. I smelled it.”

“You... smelled it?”

Han Li paused for a moment before wearing a confused expression.

Lady Fan pursed her lips and smiled, explaining, “Ever since I was small, I have been somewhat different from most. I was able to clearly tell people apart by smell. Additionally, whenever I remembered a smell, I would never forget it. Just as it so happened, I grew quite interested in Elder Han and I memorized his scent. But the last time the hidden city opened, Han Li was far too close to Wen Siyue and there were many people in the room. As a result, I was unable to clearly catch your scent. But having come so close to you today in the hall, I was able to identify you without problem.”

At that moment, Lady Fan gazed at Han Li with moist eyes and smiled at him with pursed lips.

Translator's Thoughts

If you enjoy the translation, please consider supporting the novel on Patreon! Patrons can receive up to ten chapters! With enough support, I will be able to translate full time and release 14 chapters a week.

Chapter 558: Enticement

After returning to Twin Peaks Mountain, Han Li assisted Lady Fan in exterminating the remaining cultivators that were loyal to Yun Tianxiao. Afterwards, he calmly awaited Yun Tianxiao’s return to the city.

Five days later, Han Li was sitting in the area behind the city’s hidden hall with closed eyes. Lady Fan was sitting beside him with a fluctuating expression.

At that moment, a streak of fire flew through the door and Lady Fan’s eyes brightened as it flew into her open hand.

The fire released a woman’s flustered voice, “Sect Master, it’s terrible! Elder Yun brought Daoist Master Swift Crane with him. They’ve already arrived at the entrance of the city. Sect Master, please make preparations!”

“What? The old monster Swift Cane arrived with him?” Lady Fan crushed the sound transmission talisman in astonishment and wore an extremely unsightly expression.

“The Jade Cloud Sect’s Swift Crane?” Han Li opened his eyes with a startled expression, but soon regained his calm.

“If it isn’t that old Daoist, then who else could it be? It is too late to stop our plans since Yun Tianxiao’s subordinates have already been cleanly exterminated. He will notice something is amiss in the city after being there for just a moment.” Lady Fan’s expression grew pale, but when she saw Han Li’s calm expression, she felt slightly hopeful.

When Han Li saw her silently staring at him, he couldn’t help but roll his eyes at her and sourly said, “What is Lady Fan looking at me for? Don’t tell me that you expect me to stake it all in a battle against a Nascent Soul cultivator?”

Even though he said this, Han Li didn’t feel particularly flustered in the slightest. Since a threat on the level of Man Huzi and Wan Tianming hadn’t arrived, he could make himself scarce without much of a problem. He was confident that he could escape from the hands of an early Nascent Soul cultivator with ease, especially with the miraculous abilities of his newly acquired Thunderstorm Wings. Of course, if it were possible, he still wanted to return to the Inner Star Seas with the transportation formation. As a result, Han Li was thinking of an alternative plan despite his previous words.

But when Lady Fan heard Han Li, her expression turned pale and she blankly stood in place. She was at a complete loss about what to do.

A short moment later, a cold glint flickered within Han Li’s eyes. He licked his lips and asked with a serious tone, “Does that Swift Crane have a close relationship with Yun Tianxiao? If I were to suddenly kill Yun Tianxiao, would he take revenge on me?”

Lady Fan was startled when she heard Han Li, but hastily replied with delighted surprise, “Relationship? Yun Tianxiao merely used our Exquisite Sound Sect to form a loose connection with the old Daoist by giving our disciples over to him as cultivation vessels. He doesn’t care about the matters of our Exquisite Sound Sect. However, you must kill Yun Tianxiao before he can cry for help. Otherwise, the old Daoist might truly intervene out of obligation.”

“That’s fine,” Han Li then calmly ordered, “Drag that Yun Tianxiao into one of the neighboring rooms alone. I will kill him there in an instant. He won’t have the time to call for help from Swift Crane. So long as you are in charge of the sect, the old Daoist won’t be able to say anything. Afterwards, win over his favor by using some good conditions.”

Displaying staunch decisiveness, Lady Fan gritted her teeth and agreed, “Yes! Since matters have reached this point, we can only do our utmost. Senior must exert his complete strength and kill Yun Tianxiao as quickly as possible! Please wait in the room farthest away from here for the time being. I will bring him over.”

When Han Li saw this, he immediately walked to the hall’s side door that led to a hallway with many variously sized rooms.

When he arrived at the door, Han Li thought of something and suddenly stopped. He turned around with a gloomy expression and icily said, “Sect Master Fan! After I kill Yun Tianxiao, don’t get any ideas of revealing my identity to curry favor with old Daoist Swift Crane. With my current abilities, I can easily escape from Swift Crane’s grasp despite not being able to fight against him. If that happens, Lady Fan should know what would happen to her! These words are only a warning to help you avoid doing something that wouldn’t benefit either of us during a moment of panic.”

When Lady Fan heard him, she was startled for a moment. Her expression shifted several times before settling on a bitter smile. “Senior jests, I would never do such a wretched thing! Also, I am fully aware that Senior Han is far from a common Core Formation cultivator. Please be at ease, Senior. So long as you eliminate Yun Tianxiao, I will definitely follow through with our agreement.”

Han Li took a deep glance at the woman before heading off to the farthest room in the hallway without further hesitation. Apart from the somewhat smaller size, it was the overall the same as the other rooms in the hallway.

Han Li blurred and reappeared on a sandwood chair within the room. Afterwards, he closed his eyes and thoroughly restrained his Qi, preventing himself from being discovered by either Swift Crane or Yun Tianxiao.

With his late Core Formation cultivation, Han Li was confident that he could conceal himself from the spiritual sense of early Nascent Soul cultivators, but in the end, this was still only a guess. He could only try his hardest despite the slight doubts that he held in his heart.

In the main hall, Lady Fan was greatly on edge.

While she had spoken to Han Li as if she was completely confident in him, the woman was also completely unsure as to whether Han Li could kill Yun Tianxiao in an instant.

Although Han Li had nearly killed Yun Tianxiao at the previous trade meeting with but a raise of his hand, that was likely due to catching Yun Tianxiao off guard. But as Lady Fan was an extremely shrewd person, she forcefully suppressed the distracting thoughts in her mind and poured herself a cup of tea.

As she slowly sipped the tea, she quickly regained her calm.

At that moment, footsteps came from the hall’s entrance. Soon, a middle-aged Daoist wearing a white crane embroidered robe and a Confucian-robed man entered the hall.

“Senior Swift Crane, Elder Yun!” Lady Fan deliberately cried out with a surprised expression. She then quickly placed down the tea cup she held at her lips and saluted Daoist Swift Crane.

Swift Crane indifferently nodded his head and remained silent as if he belonged to a realm beyond hers. But when Yun Tianxiao entered, he unconsciously frowned and his face revealed a trace of confusion.

Yun Tianxiao returned her salute and angrily said, “Why isn’t Yun Qin attending to the Sect Master? Is she slacking off? I will have to properly discipline her.”

“Yun Qin! She...” Lady Fan revealed hesitation and glanced at Swift Crane.

Yun Tianxiao paused for a moment before speaking with an expression of annoyance, “Sect Master, Senior Swift Crane cannot be considered an outsider! Go ahead and speak.”

Lady Fan wore a similarly displeased expression and responded, “Since that is the case, then I will say it. Yun Qin is attending to a vagrant cultivator who is in possession of some Phantasm Stone and wishes to sell it. Yun Qin was steadfast in wanting to personally deal with the person, so I had no choice but to remain here.”

Yun Tianxiao was about to say something to Swift Crane, but when he heard the words ‘Phantasm Stone’ his body trembled and he revealed delight. “What? Phantasm Stone?”

Likewise, Swift Crane’s eyes grew bright upon hearing these words and his eyes narrowed.

Appearing as if she were wronged, she coldly spoke with a grimace, “Humph! Elder Yun’s close disciple insisted on handling the matter alone, refusing to allow this Sect Master to participate.”

Yun Tianxiao dryly coughed and said, “Yun Qin had truly overstepped herself. However, I’m sure this wasn’t done deliberately. Sect Mater, where are they? I don’t feel entirely at ease.” He then turned to Swift Crane and respectfully said, “Senior Swift Crane, please wait for a moment. There is something that I must deal with first. How about we continue our discussion later?”

Swift Crane smiled and casually said, “Since Fellow Daoist Yun has some matters to attend to, I’ll just sit here for the time being.”

Yun Tianxiao immediately revealed delight and turned towards Lady Fan.

Lady Fan reluctantly said, “Follow me, Elder Yun. I’ll bring you there.” She slowly walked to the side door as if she was unwilling.

With his mind feverishly occupied by thoughts of the Phantasm Stone, all of his suspicions of Lady Fan’s actions had been wiped clean and he hastily followed after her.

Swift Crane casually glanced at the two from behind before finding a chair and aloofly took a seat.

Yun Tianxiao excitedly followed Lady Fan to the room at the very end of the hallway where the door was tightly closed.

“It’s right here! Have a good chat. In any case, this sect master is simply incapable of interfering with this deal!” Lady Fan snorted and walked back to the hall with dissatisfaction.

When Yun Tian Xiao saw this, a cold smile momentarily appeared on his face. He then opened the door without any hesitation and directly entered the room.

Chapter 559: Sudden Developments

Upon entering the room, Yun Tianxiao spotted a male cultivator sitting at the room’s center. He appeared to be fiddling with something sparkling in his hand. Yun Tianxiao then swept his gaze across the room and astonishingly found no sight of Yun Qin. Startled, his heart trembled as he grew vigilant.

He stared at the man and slowly said, “Who is your esteemed self and where is that girl Yun Qin?” The magic treasure in his body was already stirring restlessly inside body.

Han Li chuckled and raised his head, “Could it be that Brother Yun has already forgotten about me?”

“It’s you?!” Yun Tianxiao was greatly shocked when he clearly saw the man’s appearance. Without any further thought, he fled in a streak of light.

“Too slow!” Just after Han Li emotionlessly said this, a light pulsed from his hands.

Then with a flourish of radiance around Yun Tianxiao, five copper bands of varying colors appeared around his limbs and neck. These bands released a low hum before tightening and restraining him.

He screamed out of fright and hastily thought to release his magic treasure. However, his magic treasure didn’t move in the slightest as if it were shackled.

Yun Tianxiao was frightened out of his mind and couldn’t help but panic, loudly screaming, “Senior Swift Crane, please save me!”

But just as he shouted this, Han Li opened his mouth and spat out an azure streak of light. It revolved once around Yun Tianxiao before cleaving off his head. Then, without the slightest hesitation, Han Li snatched the storage pouch from the corpse and recalled his Five Element Bands.

The chain of events had concluded at lightning speed. But at the same moment Yun Tianxiao’s storage pouch entered Han Li’s grasp, he heard a loud explosion from within the room.

The room’s wall had been smashed open and Daoist Swift Crane flew inside the room through the cloud of ash.

The old Daoist gloomily glanced at the beheaded corpse on the ground and turned his gaze to Han Li. With killing intent shining within his eyes, he shouted, “You’re courting death!”

He then flicked his hand and a streak of blinding, scorching white light arrived in front of Han Li in an instant.

With pupils contracted and a trembling heart, Han Li wildly enlarged the Five Element Bands in his hand, covering his body in a multi-colored cylinder. At that same moment, he took a red and yellow jade scepter out with a turn of his hand.

Since this was the first time Han Li had blocked a Nascent Soul cultivator’s attack since reaching late Core Formation stage, he naturally had some interest in testing whether or not his incisive treasures could receive the attack. However, despite his calm exterior, he felt completely perturbed and uncertain.

Bang! White and rainbow light collided.

Han Li felt as if he was struck by a heavy hammer, and was sent flying before striking the wall behind him. His head was left spinning from the impact.

“Huh?!” While Han Li was still in a daze from the strike, Swift Crane let out an astonished shout.

With yet another white light appearing before his eyes, Han Li took a cold breath and resolutely waved his jade scepter. A red and yellow barrier of light appeared around his body from within the rainbow cylinder.

As a result, he was able to receive the next attack much better than the first. He only staggered a few steps away before regaining his bearings.

Han Li then steeled his heart as his mind began to stir, and a pair of silver white wings emerged from his back.

Leaving a roll of thunder behind, he instantly disappeared, dodging the next streak of white light. A moment later, he reappeared at another corner of the room.

Han Li had now identified the true form of Swift Crane’s white light. It was a small, jade hammer covered in sparkling white light and the oval head was covered in talisman characters. Although it was only the size of a palm, it released astonishing spiritual Qi.

After Swift Crane’s strike had missed, his face stirred and he extended his arm. With a rustle of wind, the small hammer returned into his sleeve.

A trace of astonishment flickered from Swift Crane’s eyes as he said, “I didn’t expect that a Core Formation cultivator would be in possession of so many ancient treasures. What is your name?”

Han Li pursed his lips and was about to say something when the door of the room suddenly opened as Lady Fan excitedly entered the room.

Lady Fan gave Swift Crane a formal bow and spoke to him with an exceptionally respectful tone, “Senior Swift Crane! This is Senior Li who I specially invited in order to deal with the traitor Yun Tianxiao. I hope Senior will be at ease. I am willing to double any conditions that the traitor may have raised.”

When Swift Crane heard this, he frowned and turned his gaze to the corpse on the floor. His expressioned wavered.

Fortunately, Han Li only had to silently stand in place. However, Lady Fan appeared quite nervous as she watched Swift Crane’s expression.

Swift Crane eventually relaxed and said, “Alright, since this is an internal matter of the Exquisite Sound Sect, this old Daoist won’t meddle. But don’t forget what you just said, Lady Fan.”

Lady Fan felt her heart swell with relief as she pledged with a beaming smile, “Please be at ease, Senior. I won’t dare to break my word!”

The old Daoist nodded his head and glanced at Han Li with suspicion.

After a moment of silence, he suddenly asked, “Where did Fellow Daoist Li cultivate? Your appearance is quite unfamiliar!”

Han Li’s heart trembled and he pondered for a moment. When he opened his mouth to dispel Swift Crane’s suspicions, he was only able to utter, “Junior...” before his face pulsed with azure light and underwent a massive change.

The wind spirit energy within his body had suddenly flared.

From its violent eruption, it was clear that Feng Xi was close by.

With fury and alarm, Han Li suppressed it with the entirety of his magic power. After forcefully suppressing the wind spirit energy, he felt cold sweat lining his body.

Han Li let out a breath of relief after saving himself from the crisis, but when he turned his gaze to Swift Crane, he saw a trace of astonishment. It then turned into a strange expression of delight.

Han Li suddenly thought of something and grasped his face. He instantly paled. The flare of Wind Spirit Energy had caused him to revert back to his original appearance.

A malevolent expression appeared on Daoist Swift Crane’s face as he shouted, “Han Li!”

Han Li let out a stream of curses in his heart. Without taking the time to think any further, he flapped his wings and suddenly disappeared with a flash of lightning, leaving only thunder behind. At that same moment, the old man flung his sleeve and disappeared in a streak of light. The only one left inside the room was Lady Fan who was left in a bewildered daze.

A flicker of silver light appeared above Twin Peaks Island, accompanied by the sudden appearance of Han Li. In the following moment, a streak of white light violently flew up from the island and quickly pursued him.

Han Li’s expression sank and he immediately imbued the Thunderstorm Wings within his body with Divine Devilbane Lightning. An instant later, he reappeared a hundred meters away. These flashes continued, each time with thunder left in his wake.

In the blink of an eye, Han Li had already been reduced to a small, black dot on the horizon.

When Swift Crane saw this, he couldn’t believe what he was seeing. He then came to the conclusion that the wings were certain to be a treasure from the Heavenvoid Cauldron and his heart grew wildly fervent.

With a shout, he transformed into a streak of blinding radiance and set off in hot pursuit of Han Li, tearing through the skies with booms left in his wake.

In an instant, the black and white dots could no longer been seen from the island.

In the lead, Han Li was slowly increasing the distance between him and Daoist Swift Crane with the incredible speed of the Thunderstorm Wings.

It wouldn’t take Han Li much longer until he shook off the Daoist Swift Crane with his current speed. But at that moment, the wind spirit energy flared once more within his body and continued to flare in regular intervals.

Han Li was forced to periodically stop and use his magic power to suppress the backlash of the wind spirit energy. However, this delay had given Swift Crane the opportunity to latch his spiritual sense onto Han Li, allowing him to ceaselessly pursue him.

However, this wasn’t Han Li’s biggest worry. The flares of wind spirit energy were growing increasingly violent, displaying just how close Feng Xi was to him.

Helpless and on the edge of despair, Han Li steeled his resolve and rushed towards the small island with the transportation formation. He hoped Lady Fan had truly given the order to complete the transportation formation and that they had managed to complete it by the time he arrived. So long as he was able to reach the island, he would have the opportunity to escape pursuit from Swift Crane ad Feng Xi.

Although the Thunderstorm Wings were astonishingly fast, it consumed a significant amount of Divine Devilbane Lightning. As a result, after he gained enough distance from Swift Crane, he swapped the wings for his blood-red cloak.

Translator's Thoughts

Edited: Barbant

Proofread: Vare

Chapter 567: Heavenly Omen

Yuan Yao looked at the sky before turning her head to Han Li. In a sincere tone, she said, “In four hours time, the Yin Qi will be at its strongest. That’s when I’ll begin to use the Soulrise Technique. The entire process will take three days so during that time, I will have to trouble you to guard me.”

Han Li nodded and looked around the valley. He frowned, asking, “Apart from the illusion formation, there seems to be nothing else. Won’t it be dangerous if a strong enemy were to fully occupy my attention and leave you vulnerable?”

Yuan Yao bit her lip and spoke with a hint of helplessness, “I know, but I don’t possess anymore powerful spell formation tools, and didn’t I have much time to prepare. So it’s a risk I have to take.”

Han Li crossed his arms and held his chin in his hand, before saying, “In that case, leave the spell formations to me! I still have a few sets of spell formation tools that hold decent strength. Although they are by no means exceptional, it’s still better than leaving you undefended.”

Since he had already decided to help, he may as well do his best!

When Yuan Yao heard him, her eyes shined delight as she said, “Brother Han, you’re proficient in the Dao of Formation Spells? Since that’s the case, I will feel much more at ease when I’m undergoing the ritual. Thank you for your troubles!”

Han Li silently smiled in return and then took off to the skies and examined the valley’s surroundings.

He slowly descended back onto the island a short moment later as he thought thought, ‘Since time is short, I should start putting down the formations right away!’

With that, Han Li began to wave his arms and produced slivers of consciousness, summoning over a dozen huge ape puppets at his side. He then took out many sets of spell formation tools and handed them to the puppets. Han Li stood there and used his spiritual sense to control the puppets and had them start laying down formations around the valley.

Yuan Yao curiously gazed at the puppets’ movements for a moment, but then began to hurriedly make her own preparations. The Soulrise Technique was no trivial affair! To fully employ the technique, it required extremely careful preparations. Additionally, one needed to test the formation on the ground to avoid any mistakes from occurring part way through.

Elsewhere on the island, Han Li managed to place down five moderately powerful spell formations within two hours with the aid of his ape puppets. Although they wouldn’t be able to withstand persistent attacks from a Core Formation cultivator, they would be more than enough to deal with any Foundation Establishment cultivators.

At the heart of the valley, Yuan Yao finished placing down all of the spirit stones for the spell formation, and struck the crux of the formation with an incantation seal, activating the spell formation. In response, the spell formation began to hum and flicker with a jet-black light. Eerie strands of black Qi suddenly began to appear around the formation, converging towards the glacial jade coffin at the center.

Yuan Yao revealed satisfaction at the sight and hastily struck the formation with another incantation seal, stopping the spell formation.

Yuan Yao walked out of the spell formation and turned to Han Li, while happily saying, “There doesn’t seem to be any problems. The spell formation is working as expected.”

After seeing her cheerful smile, Han Li slowly said, “Fellow Daoist Yuan! Have you thought this through clearly? After shattering your core, your path to immortal cultivation will cease. It will be nearly impossible to climb back up to Core Formation stage.”

Yuan Yao’s smile disappeared and after a brief moment of silence, she calmly said, “If it ends, then let it end. The only reason I was able to live until now was so I could accomplish this.” Yuan Yao then combed a strand of loose hair from her face to the side and emotionlessly said, “Brother Han doesn’t know what relationship I had with my Senior Martial Sister. I grew up with her ever since I was small and for tens of years, we lived together, ate together, and cultivated together in our sect. We may as well have been true sisters. When we killed the Azure Yang Young Sect Master, she blocked a retaliatory strike aimed at me and perished as result. As such, it is only right that I suffer from the Soulrise Technique for her. So long as Senior Martial Sister’s primal soul doesn’t perish and she regains her fleshly body, a shattered core is a trivial cost.”

An odd expression momentarily appeared on Han Li’s face. After muttering to himself for a moment, he nodded his head and no longer tried to dissuade her.

Yuan Yao returned to the center of the spell formation and sat down in front of the glacial jade coffin while waiting for the optimal time to start.

Not a word was spoken until she eventually looked at the skies and slowly stood up.

“It’s time. Let’s start! Regardless of whether or not the Soulrise Technique succeeds, I will always remember your kindness, Brother Han, and will be forever grateful.” Yuan Yao gracefully saluted Han Li before activating the formation beneath her without any reservations.

Han Li sighed and slowly walked out of the valley. A moment later, the surrounding Yin Qi began to flow towards the formation. Even with his current cultivation, he didn’t wish to be near such a vast quantity of Yin Qi.

Han Li stopped once he left the valley and turned around.

Yin winds began to gather around the spell formation and a faint layer of black light had begun to cover the area as ghostly wails filled the air.

Han Li then expressionlessly sat down outside the valley entrance and began to slowly release his spiritual sense, keeping the entire island and the nearby seas within his sights. As he remained motionless, he frowned and revealed a bitter smile.

At that moment, Han Li realized why Yuan Yao had requested him to act as her protector. Her previous description of the Soulrise Technique’s external impact during the ritual was a vast understatement!

Han Li came back to his senses with something of a headache.The Yin winds had already obstructed most of the valley from view while sand and stones filled the air as they blew all over. Ghostly sobs reverberated throughout the valley. The heart of the formation was shining with blinding black light and was surrounded with Yin Qi so dense that the very sight of it inspired fear.

What Han Li found most shocking was the black cloud that had appeared five kilometers in the air at some unknown time. It roiled with Yin Qi and released startling claps of thunder as it started to take the form of a cone pointed downward at the valley.

This was clearly the sign of a heavenly omen. Any cultivators living in the nearby seas were certain to be shocked. After all, this astonishing scene wasn’t normally accompanied by a treasure, but by a human performing a heretical act that defied the Heavens. Such a scene would arouse a great curiosity in anyone who saw it.

Furthermore, who knew whether or not this would provoke a fearsome character?

As Han Li inwardly considered this, his expression stirred while he gazed into the distance.

Eight streaks of light were approaching the island from the southwest. In an instant, they had stopped five kilometers away from the island, revealing a group of male and female cultivators. They were led by an old grey-haired Foundation Establishment cultivator, while the rest of them were youths that were only at the eighth layer of Qi Condensation at most.

From their matching blue robes, they appeared to all be from the same sect.

The old man in charge gazed at the heavenly omen with a doubtful expression as his expression fluctuated.

A twenty year old female cultivator saw that the old man that was gazing at the island in silence and couldn’t help but quickly propose, “Martial Uncle Zhao, let’s quickly see what’s happening on the island. Maybe a treasure has emerged!”

The old man glanced at the woman and rebuked her, “Hui Ling, you are far too rash. Look at the signs. Even if a treasure emerged here, it would be devilish and cursed. Moreover, it is quite possible that an expert is either refining something or employing a devilish technique. If you were to rush in there and cause disturbance, you’d only be seeking death.”

The woman revealed a trace of dissatisfaction, but didn’t dare to further speak.

One of the older male disciples glanced at the black clouds above the small island and asked, “Martial Uncle! What are we waiting around for?”

“Be at ease. With such a large disturbance, it’s all but certain for others to be around. Action will only be taken after the situation is fully understood. Remember, our Grand Sun Sect has only lasted until now due to the cautious discernment of its inner disciples. Never make any rash decisions. Even with such potentially gargantuan profits before us, we must also consider whether or not we can preserve our lives.” The old man lectured the disciples behind him as he stared at the small island.

The rest of the young disciples naturally agreed.

Not long after the old man spoke, a green and a yellow streak of light approached the island from a different direction. They discovered the old man’s party and stopped about three hundred meters away from them.

The light faded away to reveal a black-robed man that appeared about forty years of age with a stiff face, and an elegant woman beside him that appeared to be in her late twenties. With a pleasant voice, the woman warmly asked the old man, “So it’s the Grand Sun Sect’s Fellow Daoist Zhao. Do you know what is going on at the island? Why has a heavenly omen appeared?”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 571: Disciple of Archsaint Six Paths

After Han Li’s spiritual sense was repelled, he naturally concluded that these arrivals weren’t ordinary cultivators. With the sneaky white silhouette easily dealt with by his Gold Devouring Beetles, Han Li could now focus the entirety of his attention on the newly arrived late Core Formation cultivator.

Han Li turned his gaze back into the valley and saw that the spell formation had become covered in an impenetrable barrier of pitch-black Yin Qi. He reckoned that Yuan Yao was at a crucial moment of the Soulrise Technique. If she were to be disturbed at this point, not only would Yan Li doomed to forever be nothing more than a disembodied soul, but Yan Yao would also receive terrible a backlash and injury.

Han Li frowned and turned his head around with a pensive expression.

Although he didn’t know where this youth had suddenly appeared from, he didn’t dare to underestimate him. Of course, Han Li wasn’t afraid of him in the slightest, either. Confident in his fantastical magic treasures, Han Li viewed no Core Formation cultivator as a threat.

He then pondered about whether or not he should take the initiative to eliminate him. After all, the new arrival appeared to be a rather problematic individual and if he were to join hands with other cultivators, it could prove extremely troublesome. With a sudden change of expression, Han Li immediately stood up with narrowed eyes.

The man had departed the carriage and was now flying towards Han Li with the beautiful young woman in tow.

Han Li’s expression grew solemn and raised his hands, releasing over ten of his huge puppets to protect the valley while he was gone. He then stamped his foot without any further hesitation and flew towards the man and woman in a streak of azure light.

If he had a confrontation with cultivators near the valley, it could disrupt Yuan Yao’s ritual. From how strong the enemy appeared, he reckoned it would take some time to kill him. As such, he could only take the opportunity to approach him and force him to stay away from the valley.

The elegant youth didn’t fly particularly fast and after a moment, Han Li met him at the edge of the island.

Han Li had already changed his appearance long before assuming the role of protector. As a result, he had no fear of being recognized as the one who had seized the Heavenvoid Cauldron.

With about four hundred meters separating them, Han Li expressionly gazed at the elegant man and the beautiful woman following him. A trace of astonishment flickered within his eyes after he examined them.

Although the golden light glowing from his forehead was eye-catching, it merely showed that his cultivation art was somewhat peculiar. However, Han Li couldn’t help but look at the astonishingly beautiful woman at his side in awe.

For some unknown reason, Han Li felt a trace of familiarity towards her as if he had seen them somewhere before, especially with her clear eyes.

However, Han Li was positive that this was the first time he had seen the gorgeous young woman. Had he seen her before, she definitely would’ve left an impression.

At that moment, both of them were glancing at Han Li.

Wen Tianren held his arms behind his back and a strange expression flickered within his eyes. He then smiled and said, “Might I know your esteemed name? Is the one performing the heaven-defying technique your Dao Companion?”

When Han Li heard this, he felt his heart tremble. The elegant man obviously knew the origins of the heavenly omen, revealing that he was far more fearsome than he had imagined.

“My name isn’t anything important. However, I must insist that you Fellow Daoists turn back! Since you already know that the heavenly omen isn’t a sign of a treasure emerging, then why have you two come to this island?” Han Li emotionlessly asked.

The young man indifferently said, “I’m not here for the heavenly omen, but for you!”

“For me?” Han Li frowned. This was beyond what he had expected.

A trace of hostility appeared on Wen Tianren’s elegant face as he icily said, “That’s right! If your esteemed self is unwilling to tell me your name, then I won’t demand it. However, I do have some knowledge of the Core Formation cultivators in each sect, and from your unfamiliar appearance, it appears that you are a vagrant cultivator. Since that is the case, I will give you and your Dao companion two choices. You either enter the coalition, and become an enforcer of my Divine Dove Hall, following all of my commands. Or you will die here by my hand.”

“Listen to your orders? Enter your coalition? You’re a member of the Starfall Coalition?” When Han Li heard him, he was stunned, but soon reexamined the man with gaze of doubt.

The young woman said with a neutral tone, “Young Master Wen is a brilliant student of the Starfall Coalition’s Archsaint Six Paths. It wouldn’t be considered a disgrace if you were to swear allegiance to him. Additionally, with Fellow Daoist’s cultivation, you will be placed in an important position within the coalition.”

“You’re a disciple of Archsaint Six Paths?” Han Li’s expression stirred. Although he knew the man’s identity had to be unordinary, he hadn’t expected it to be shocking to this degree.

When Wen Tianren saw Han Li’s shock, his expression remained the same despite a trace of pride appearing in his eyes. He happily enjoyed the amazement he saw from Han Li when he heard of his identity. He didn’t feel any shame in using his identity as Archsaint Six Paths’ disciple, as he considered one’s identity to be a resource.

However, Wen Tianren’s spirits quickly fell when Han Li’s expression turned into a sneer.

Using a derisive tone, Han Li said, “So it turned out to be a young master of the Starfall Coalition. I apologize for my lack of manners! However, I don’t possess the slightest intention of entering your esteemed coalition, nor do I have any intention of dying. Rather, I have another proposal. How about I take Young Master Wen’s life instead?”

From Wen Tianren’s overbearing manner, he clearly understood that this man wasn’t benevolent in the slightest. Not only did he feel a trace of killing intent from his spiritual sense, but he faintly felt that the young master planned on killing him regardless of whether or not he surrendered. Since Han Li was going to end up fighting him either way, he saw little reason to bother entertaining him. Others might hold the enormous Starfall Alliance in fear, but Han Li held it in little regard. After all, with the Heavenvoid Cauldron in his possession, he may as well be a fugitive from everyone in the Inner Star Seas.

“Good, very good!” Wen Tianren furiously smiled and stared at Han Li with an increasingly icy gaze. In the instant, he finished speaking, he spat out a streak of blue light.

Just as the blue light left his mouth, it burst with dazzling light and disappeared from sight.

Han Li’s face grew stern, and he unconsciously waved the jade scepter in his hand, causing a barrier of red and yellow light to instantly cover him.

In the moment the barrier appeared, the blue light had struck the light barrier with a muffled thump.

Han Li’s expression faintly changed after being pushed back ten meters by the strike.

At that moment, he clearly saw that the blue streak was a peculiar awl that was several inches long. It crackled with blue light and had talisman characters winding around it.

Without any further thought, Han Li flicked his fingers, sending ten streaks of azure sword Qi in the direction of the blue awl.

Without any further reservations, Han Li slapped his storage pouch and took out his Five Element Bands. They immediately shined a rainbow light and hummed. With his other hand, he flung out over twenty flying swords in the direction of Wen Tiannren.

Wen Tianren didn’t appear surprised in the slightest at having his attack blocked. Instead, he calmly pressed his hands together and summoned a small flag. The four-inch long flag flickered with purple light and possessed an astonishing spiritual Qi.

At that same moment, he glanced in front of him to see a swarm of flying swords and revealed an expression of surprise. He didn’t dare to be negligent and quickly waved the purple flag in his hand, causing countless purple clouds to be spurt out. They completely enveloped him and hid him from view.

A trace of annoyance appeared in Han Li’s eyes, as he had wanted to use the Five Element Bands to restrain Wen Tianren. Instead, he had the bands combine into one huge ring and protect his body. At that same moment, he formed an incantation gesture with his hands, activating the Swordshadow Phantasm Technique.

The twenty four azure swords suddenly blurred and multiplied into a swarm of ninety-six azure streaks, piercing though the azure cloud in an overbearing assault.

When the gorgeous young woman saw this from a distance, she revealed astonishment and her expression paled from shock and disbelief. Soon, a complicated expression flickered across her face.

The azure streaks of light were like countless wasps as they continuously pierced through the clouds. However, their countless strikes passed through the cloud as if nothing were there.

When Han Li saw this, he unconsciously frowned and his expression turned grim. Although he knew that he wouldn’t so easily rid himself of Wen Tianren, this person had yet again exceeded his expectations.

With that thought, he pointed to his flying swords and had them revolve once more around the azure clouds as they hummed, transforming into ten-meter-long swords that emitted a suffocating pressure.

At that same moment, Han Li slapped the spirit beast pouch at his waist.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 572: Bitter Battle

Countless Gold Devouring Beetles rushed out from Han Li’s storage pouch before instantly forming into a huge tri-colored cloud. The beetle swarm was about a hundred meters wide and emitted an astonishing pressure.

“Yi!” A distant yell of fright was heard in response.

Han Li’s eyes coldly glinted as his gaze fell onto the gorgeous, young woman.

The woman was covering her small, delicate mouth while her eyes revealed astonishment. Han Li was surprised when he noticed that her expression seemed to hold an inexplicable hint of joy.

Han Li was momentarily distracted by her inexplicable display when two massive rumbles erupted and tore his attention back to the battle at hand. He hastily turned his gaze back to the purple clouds in alarm. An ancient copper shield that glowed with white light had left the azure clouds and easily blocked the strikes of his two huge swords.

Han Li inwardly sighed at this, as he still hadn't taken much time to temper the flying swords. He had relied on the extraordinary quality of materials of the swords to overwhelm the magic treasures of common cultivators. But now that he had reached late Core Formation stage, the might of his magic treasures had clearly fallen behind those of his peers. Even when merging them together, his flying swords didn’t pose much of a threat to cultivators of a similar grade.

As these thoughts surged through his mind, he had his two flying swords continue to strike the violet cloud regardless of their efficacy, but the ancient shield was able to block every strike with ease.

At that moment, Han Li released a series of low-pitched whistles, causing his Gold Devouring Beetles to hum for a moment before swarming towards the purple cloud en masse. Although he didn’t know what the purple cloud was made of, it would still be consumed by the Gold Devouring Beetles all the same.

Seeing that huge cloud of insects suddenly appear, Wen Tianren couldn’t help but coldly snort in disdain, “Humph! Insect techniques? You’re courting death!”

When Han Li heard this he immediately felt a surge of joy. If Wen Tianren treated his Gold Devouring Beetles as common insects, then when the swarm of beetles arrived at the purple cloud his death was practically assured.

Han Li inwardly sneered, but just as the insect swarm arrived at the purple clouds, Wen Tianren suddenly shouted, “Go!”

An astonishing scene then occurred!

A golden light suddenly burst forth from the purple cloud and countless gold threads shot out. The gold threads shot into the swarm of Gold Devouring Beetles. Then in the wake of of several loud cracks, dead beetles began to fall from the sky like a heavy rain.

The gold threads had actually overwhelmed the Gold Devouring Beetles. The beetles were greatly resistant against the strikes of magic treasures, but against these golden threads, they were completely defenseless.

When Han Li saw this, he was overwhelmed by furious alarm. He hastily released a sharp whistle to have his insect swarm immediately return and revolve around him. However, the golden threads weren’t about to let the beetles slip away. They shot after the beetles as they escaped, filling the sky with their bodies.

Han Li grimaced and without any further thought, he hastily slapped his storage pouch and took out the ancient flower basket, before tossing it out without hesitation. The flower basket turned into a cloud of white Qi in a flash of light and directly approached the gold threads.

When the white Qi had incorporeally passed through the insect swarm and arrived among the golden threads, he wore a strange expression and quickly formed an incantation gesture with his hands. The white Qi immediately began to spin and glow with white radiance.

The golden threads were enveloped by the white light and were immediately restrained, slowing them down immensely.

The beetle swarm took advantage of that opening to fly back into Han Li’s spirit beast pouches.

However, Han Li’s expression was extremely unsightly at that moment. In that short exchange, he had lost nearly ten thousand of his black-tainted Gold Devouring Beetles. If he hadn’t used the ancient flower basket to respond, he would have suffered devastating losses.

Just what kind of magic treasures were these threads for them to contain such fearsome power? He was in complete disbelief as to what had just happened. His Gold Devouring Beetles were repelled before they could even display their tremendous power.

Han Li had momentarily became despondent before he observed the gold threads undergo a transformation while within the white Qi. After seeing them gently flicker, they dimmed and revealed their true form. They were thin golden needles and were only about an inch long and had a golden luster.

When Han Li saw this, he was truly shocked. Wen Tianren actually used flying needles, the most difficult magic treasure to refine, and in a number of at least several hundred of them no less. This caused Han Li’s blood to run cold.

However, Han Li’s thoughts stirred as something soon came to mind.

At that moment, the lightless golden needles had simultaneously released a dazzling gleam and hurriedly gathered into one spot before condensing into a golden sword in an instant.

The golden sword gently trembled before suddenly breaking through the restrictions of the flower basket and shooting in Han Li’s direction.

Han Li’s expression sank and he took out a sparkling azure talisman from his storage pouch. This was the treasure talisman that Layman Qingyi had given to him at Heavenvoid Hall. As the treasures it had been refined from were also flying needles, they should be an equal match.

Just as the golden sword rushed towards Han Li, it split into countless golden threads with a bang as they continued forward.

Without any further hesitation, Han Li spat a cloud of azure Qi onto the talisman. With a flicker of azure light, the talisman instantly transformed into a streak of azure light.

As soon as the azure light left Han Li’s light barrier, it instantly transformed into an overbearing number of azure threads of light. At first glance, they appeared no different from the golden threads apart from their color.

“What are those?” Wen Tianren was stunned and spoke with a surprised tone.

The golden threads had already arrived at Han Li’s side and began to interweave themselves amongst the azure threads, resulting in pulsing balls of light.

Wen Tianren shouted in alarm and coldly asked, “The Nightazure Needles! What relationship do you have with Layman Qingyi? That’s a treasure talisman of his Nightazure Needles. That old ghost has always been annoyingly stingy and treats those needles as if they were as valuable as his own life. Could it be that you are his disciple?”

When Han Li heard Wen Tianren shout out the name of the Nightazure Needles, his heart trembled but he soon regained his calm.

It appeared that although the matter of the Heavenvoid Cauldron had been leaked, the specific details of what had occurred weren’t widely known. Otherwise, he surely would’ve known his identity upon seeing the needles.

With that thought, Han Li had no intention of further speaking and only scoffed. He then circulated all the magic power in his body and took advantage of Wen Tianren’s moment of hesitation, pushing back the golden light threads and turning the tide of battle into Han Li’s favor.

Wen Tianren’s furious voice yelled from within the violet cloud, “You’re courting death! Since you’re unwilling to explain, I won’t bother to show that old ghost Qing Yi any face. I will have you personally witness the most formidable Devilish cultivation art in the Scattered Star Seas - The Devils of Six Apexes. Don’t blame me for being ruthless!” After that was said, he recalled the golden threads from their confrontation with the Nightazure Needles, having the needles fly back into the purple cloud in an instant.

Han Li scowled as the atmosphere suddenly became silent. Without any reservations, he had the azure streaks of light surround the purple cloud and madly pierce into it. However, it ended up with the same result as before. All of the streaks of light pierced through the purple cloud with little effect.

A cold air of resolve then emitted from Han Li’s face. He immediately recalled the needles and had them return into a talisman before placing them back into his storage pouch.

As the Nightazure Needles were extremely powerful, he wasn’t going to allow the talisman’s power go to waste.

Han Li’s expression wavered as he continued to look at the tranquil purple cloud. A trace of hesitation could faintly be seen from his face as if he wished to act, but he managed to refrain from acting all the same.

In the following instant, the purple cloud suddenly began to roil and summon a gale, agitating the spiritual Qi in the nearby several tens of kilometers which began to pour into the violet cloud like rivers pouring into an ocean. The cloud then began to wildly expand and its color began to turn light grey. Additionally, odd sounds began to blast out from the cloud. They were initially soft before growing deafening in an instant, disturbing the hearts of those who heard it.

After witnessing the strange scene, Han Li’s hesitation had completely disappeared.

He suddenly grabbed his right arm with his left hand and raised it towards the light grey cloud, as his arm began gathering a freezing, malicious Qi.

As the nearby environmental spiritual Qi continued to wildly pour into the light grey cloud, its sounds came to resemble immense thunder, shaking the hearts of all lower-grade cultivators nearby.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 576: The Ghost Mist Appears

Were it a common late Core Formation cultivator, they wouldn’t be able to withstand the golden flames for even a quarter of an hour!

However, Han Li was anything but common!

At that moment, he stared at the golden flames surrounding him with a frown and slapped his storage pouch, taking out a small bottle.

Han Li glanced at the small bottle and let out a sigh. It was the Myriad Year Spirit Milk he had just acquired, and it already appeared that he wouldn’t be able to last much longer without it.

It was quite the cruel joke. Had he not acquired the spirit milk from Yuan Yao, he would’ve found himself in a dead end. But at the same time, were it not for this spirit milk, he wouldn’t have encountered Wen Tianren, a disciple of Archsaint Six Paths, and be in this situation!

Han Li felt extremely conflicted about how this situation had developed.

According to current situation, he was currently losing, but with the half bottle of Myriad Year Spirit Milk, he felt completely secure. Regardless of the golden light that trapped him or the golden flames that scorched around him, Wen Tianren was incapable of persevering without paying a heavy cost. If Wen Tianren wanted to compete in a battle of endurance, then victory assured for Han Li. Wen Tianren’s own actions were about to doom him!

With that thought in mind, a sneer momentarily appeared on Han Li’s face before he sat down inside the light barrier, preparing his counter attack once Wen Tianren had exhausted himself.

Consequentially, a baffling scene transpired. The air that had recently been filled with rolls of thunder and flashes of dazzling light had suddenly turned serene and peaceful. Wen Tianren and Han Li were both sitting down, forming their own incantation gestures in silence. However, the ten meter tall golden flames continued to burn.

When Fairy Violet spirit saw this, her luminous eyes shifted and she inwardly sighed.

From what she saw, Han Li was bound to be defeated as he was trapped within the golden flames. Although Han Li currently had a silver light barrier around him, she believed it would only provide temporary protection at most.

She stood there while wearing a complicated expression, but she had no intention of stepping forward. It appeared she didn’t intend to take any action until the battle between the two of them was concluded.

At that moment, the Mei siblings, Old Man Zhao and the other low grade cultivators were grouped together about fifty kilometers away from the island. Although they were too far away to see Han Li’s battle with Wen Tianren, they were able to see the brilliant flashes of light in the distance and hear the deafening explosions. This alone had left them greatly alarmed.

They had mistakenly believed that this was caused by a battle between the Core Formation cultivator on the island and the white silhouette. As such, they hadn’t dared to leave, but now that all signs of fighting had disappeared, they were all left in dismay. They didn’t know who was victorious or if something unexpected had occurred. Since they still didn’t dare to rashly depart, they could only force themselves to stay put.

On the other side of the island, the beautiful female cultivators that had been escorting the carriage were also whispering to each other with apprehension.

Although they were all the personal maids of Wen Tianren, they were no different than true concubines and were treated favorably by him. On that note, if something were to happen to Wen Tianren, their fates were already sealed once they returned.

However, because Wen Tianren had given them orders to remain at the carriage when he approached the island, these concubines didn’t dare to rashly take action.

...

Time slowly passed while the confrontation continued.

Day eventually turned to night and night turned to early morning. Nearly an entire day passed in complete silence as if yesterday’s battle had never even occurred.

At that moment, both groups of cultivators on either side of the island were impatient and filled with doubt as other cultivators were beginning to appear nearby.

After an entire day of having the heavenly omen above the island, word spread that a peculiar treasure had appeared on this small island. Naturally, cultivators began to appear nearby. A vast majority of these cultivators were at Foundation Establishment stage but there were also a few overly confident Qi Condensation cultivators mixed in.

These people began to arrive at the island from every direction. When they grew near, they discovered Old Man Zhao’s group along with the female cultivators around the carriage.

Those who met Old Man Zhao and the Mei siblings were better off. As Old Man Zhao and the Mei siblings were quite well connected, many cultivators came to them to find out what had happened.

After these cultivators heard that Core Formation cultivators had already entered the island, they apprehensively muttered to themselves and gathered near the old man’s party, holding no foolish thoughts of rushing the island.

As for the cultivators on the other side of the island that chose to speak to the beautiful female cultivators next to the carriage, the female cultivator in charge had taken out a banner of the Starfall Coalition without any reservations and immediately threatened them. Each of these cultivators immediately turned tail with pale faces. Since the Starfall Coalition cultivators were participating in whatever was happening on the island, nothing good would come about from staying around.

After more time had past, two Core Formation cultivators eventually arrived. They were travelling together, and one of them was the deputy island lord of Bright Emperor Island. These two arrived on the side with Wen Tianren’s maids, and naturally questioned them with baffled expressions.

Because the two were Core Formation cultivators, the female cultivators didn’t dare to slight them. The female cultivator in charge casually mentioned Wen Tianren’s name to them as she answered.

The two Core Formation cultivators were shocked upon hearing his name. While Bright Emperor Island was considered neutral, they didn’t dare to provoke the overbearing power of either the top figure of the Devil Dao or the Starfall Coalition. After casually mumbing some sort of excuse, the two immediately flew back from where they came.

What a joke! Although they didn’t even know whether or not a treasure existed on this island, since a disciple of Archsaint Six Paths had arrived, they naturally had no thoughts of involving themselves. Since the young master had yet to return after approaching the island, if something had truly happened to him and they became involved, then they’d be just be heading to their deaths.

Although a small portion of cultivators were scared away by the Starfall Coalition’s reputation, about forty cultivators had gathered around the island from other directions. When they weren’t able to detect any Core Formation cultivators nearby, they rushed in.

These cultivators harbored sinister designs of their own and weren’t about to leave the island of their own accord. They planned to take advantage of the current chaos for their own benefit.

As the black cloud above the island continued to swirl, it had already spread out to cover the entirety of the small island, blocking all the light from shining onto the island.

A dark green beam of light suddenly shot up from the island towards the Yin clouds. At that moment, the clouds furiously roiled for a moment then began to slowly descend and remained about four hundred meters above the island before becoming serene.

The emergence of these pitch-black clouds had given the impression that a tempest was about to approach.

The heavenly omen’s transformations shook the hearts of the cultivators nearby. However, a few of the more quick witted ones felt delight as they believed the green beam of light to be the sign for the emergence of a treasure.

These cultivators were suddenly overwhelmed with greed and glanced at each other for a moment before flying towards the island in groups of ten. They believed that with so many Foundation Establishment cultivators joining hands, even a Core Formation cultivator wouldn’t be able to make light of them.

As for the portion of cultivators that hadn’t joined, they were extremely calm and examined the other’s actions with detached gazes. Since there were others willing to scout the path ahead, they were happy to sit back and watch before taking action.

At that same time, Wen Tianren’s maids were no longer capable of just waiting and approached the island with the carriage in tow.

Unbeknownst to all these people was that deep within the oceans near the small island, a strange black light started to shine after an appearance of a slim black crevice. Soon after, countless threads of pitch-black Qi emerged from the crevice forming into a mist.

This pitch-black mist was only about ten meters wide at the start but it quickly began to expand. In only a short moment, it had already spread to an area of five hundred meters and continued to grow. Not only could ghostly wails be faintly heard from within the fog, but there were unceasing flashes of bizarre black lightning. Even more strange was how the nearby sea creatures were drawn into the black mist like moths to the flame.

An instant later, all life in the nearby seas had already been swept clean, but nevertheless, the black mist continued to expand as if it were unsated.

One kilometer, two kilometers...

It eventually began to emerge from the ocean’s surface, allowing it to be clearly seen by those present. When everyone saw this, they became numb with fear.

From the looks of it, the mist would soon spread across the small island.

Everyone on the island, including Han Li, were at a loss as they watched its progress.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 578: Encounter in the Dark

Shock was clear in Han Li’s eyes as he fell towards the rocks a hundred meters below him. He abruptly twisted his body and bent his waist at a strange angle before kicking his feet out behind him. This caused him to shoot towards a large tree nearby before steadily coming to stand on one of its branches.

Han Li’s head was lined with cold sweat after his near fall. Fortunately, the Shifting Smoke Steps didn’t require any spiritual power to use. Otherwise, he would’ve just met his end by falling to his death. If a Core Formation cultivator were to actually die by falling, they’d become a laughingstock! Of course, many of the nearby Foundation Establishment cultivators weren’t as fortunate as Han Li and were certain to have suffered.

When Han Li finally regained his bearings, he heard a series of clangs from the distance. He quickly turned his head in that direction with a changed expression. Sure enough, the clangs came from the two sets of Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords that he hadn’t taken into his body. Not far to their side were the eight sided mirrors, the ancient flower basket, and the small silver bell. At the moment, they were all completely devoid of life as if their spiritual nature had disappeared.

Han Li’s heart trembled and he hastily tried to release a thread of spiritual sense to inspect the treasures, however his heart immediately grew cold. No matter how hard he tried, his immensely powerful spiritual sense now remained motionless within his body.

Han Li’s blood ran cold as both his magic power and spiritual sense were now incapable of being used. He was now no different than an ordinary mortal. Let alone his magic abilities, his storage pouch and his spirit beast pouches were now useless as well.

He turned around and paled upon seeing that the overflowing black mist had already filled the nearby skies.

With his current speed as a mortal, there would be no chance of him outrunning the ghost mist. After reflecting on the current situation with a gloomy expression, he gritted his teeth and his body blurred. He then appeared beside the lifeless treasures and frantically gathered them all into his arms.

Because he currently had no way of using his storage pouch, he could only hold the items close to his chest. Fortunately, they weren’t too large, otherwise Han Li would’ve been incapable of carrying all of them.

At the same time that Han Li was gathering up the treasures, the endless black fog suddenly descended onto the small island.

Han Li felt an immense attractive force coming in the direction of the mist, and before he even realized what was happening, he was already being sucked in.

Han Li was overwhelmed by shock and shifted his body several times, hoping to use his Shifting Smoke Steps to escape, but it proved completely ineffective. A moment later, he had been absorbed into the pitch-black mist and found himself among several flashes of black lightning that instantly wrapped around his body.

With several muffled booms, Han Li flickered with black light and disappeared without a trace into the fog.

Han Li heard a torrent of countless, strange sounds pour into his mind as the entire world around him blurred and was replaced with absolute darkness.

He felt his body suddenly come to a stop and then fell onto some kind of ground with a muffled thump. The ground was soft and thick, leaving him without the slightest injury, relieving Han Li of his most pressing worry.

He took the opportunity to glance around and found only an expanse of darkness, but he did manage to smell a strong, fishy scent.

Han Li wordlessly ran his hands over his body to find it sticky and wet with several things poking into him. Upon closer inspection, he discovered that he was lying on a pile of live, squirming fish and prawn.

Han Li frowned and slowly tried to stand up when his head suddenly broke out in pain. At that same time, he felt his limbs turn soft and he became overwhelmed with a sense of vertigo.

Han Li inwardly cursed. Without any magic power protecting his body, he was being subjected to the full aftermath of teleportation. It was likely that he wouldn’t be able to stand up for quite a while.

Since this was the case, Han Li emotionlessly lied down on the pile of fish and prawn, saving his strength until he could move his limbs once more.

But right then, yet another ball of black lightning appeared appeared about ten meters above him.

That faint flash of light allowed Han Li to see strange pointed rocks about thirty meters above him, and he was able to make out that this place seemed to be an underground cave. As for the strange lightning, there seemed to be something within it.

Han Li’s heart stirred as he gazed at it. After wildly flashing several more times, it disappeared and dropped a pitch-black object straight onto Han Li.

Han Li was startled and wanted to move out of the way, but his body was powerless. He could only watch on as the object fell onto him.

As a result, a soft woman’s body fell onto Han Li with a muffled grunt. It seemed she had also been teleported there.

The woman was clearly rattled, and not only did she not realize that Han Li was beneath her, she also crawled on him, grabbing onto Han Li’s hair.

Han Li smirked and let out a faint breath of pain.

“Huh?” The woman now realized that there was another person beneath her, an unfamiliar man. She cried out in alarm and hastily tried to stand, but her body swayed several times before she weakly fell back down.

As a result, she ended up falling onto Han Li once again with her upper body resting on Han Li’s stomach. From her look of fright, she seemed to be somewhat young.

“Who are you?” The woman asked with a trembling voice. Her heavy, thumping heart, could be clearly heard in the silent darkness.

The woman’s voice was quite pleasant, but since he didn’t know the woman and couldn’t clearly make out her appearance, Han Li jokingly replied, “Just some guy!”

“Hmph.” A trace of resentment appeared within her eyes as she fiercely glared at Han Li. But because her limbs were in pain, she could only raise her neck and turn her head towards Han Li just a bit, as this action didn’t seem to take much effort.

However, her pleasant fragrance did reach Han Li’s nose, arousing a strange feeling in him. With the addition of her soft, ample body pressing against him, a certain area was unconsciously aroused.

“What are you doing!” The woman immediately felt the change in Han Li’s body, and she fiercely glared at him with a shameful expression. However, Han Li saw this action to be quite adorable.

Han Li bitterly laughed and said, “It isn’t something that I can control. I have lost my magic power and spiritual sense. While I would like to control my body with my cultivation and calm down my little lord, I’ve returned to become an ordinary man. I am helpless to do anything about the reaction.”

The woman snorted. Although she didn’t say anything, she seemed to have heard him. Fortunately, she couldn’t move just like Han Li and could do nothing about it, despite her angry humiliation.

The darkness became silent once more, broken only by the breaths of the two.

Han Li felt this experience to be completely unprecedented. There were countless fish and prawn flailing about underneath him, and an unfamiliar, fragrant woman laying on top of him. This situation couldn’t be described as anything but absurd!

The woman suddenly broke the silence and asked, “Were you among the fellow cultivators that entered the island?”

“Seems likely, right?” When Han Li heard her, he immediately recalled the dozens of cultivators that had rushed to the small island. It seemed like this woman was one of them.

Doubt flickered within her eyes and she snorted before suspiciously asking, “What is that supposed to mean?”

Han Li smiled and thought to brush off her question with a vague response when disorderly footsteps suddenly sounded as several torches soon appeared in the distance and floated nearby. There appeared to be shadows that were faintly visible beneath the flickering torchlight.

Han Li’s heart trembled! There seemed to be people here and they didn’t appear to be the other cultivators that had been devoured by the ghost mist.

An instant later, the torches had drawn close to them.

Han Li’s eyes narrowed and he was able to clearly see the black silhouettes behind the flames. They were five exceptionally large men that were each at least a whole head taller than Han Li, and appeared to be about forty years of age.

They wore green robes and held a sword-like weapon in their hands with huge leather bags on their backs and were hastily travelling forward in large strides.

When Han Li saw them, his heart was shaken by fear. As he was guessing the identity of these men, a strand of black hair swept past his face. The woman had turned her head to gaze at them as well, and seemed to be ill at ease from her trembling..

Han Li furrowed his brow and began to move his fingers as a trace of strength had returned. It appeared that he was recovering his strength rather quickly.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 579: A Place With No Name

A moment after Han Li realized he was regaining control of his body, the torches had grown closer to them, allowing him to see with greater clarity.

The nearby surroundings had been brightened enough to reveal large piles of fish and prawn everywhere. Han Li and the woman happened to be on one of the comparatively larger piles.

The areas further away from them were still pitch-black and couldn’t be seen, but the cave appeared exceptionally spacious as no walls could be seen.

When the men carrying torches were about a hundred meters away from Han Li, they stopped and quickly placed their bags onto the ground. With the exception of one person that vigilantly stood guard, the rest of them began to wildly stuff the fish and prawn into their bags.

Han Li was surprised to see this while woman on top of him couldn’t help but gasp in surprise, but the men hadn’t heard her because of how soft her voice was. Han Li unconsciously turned his gaze to the woman and discovered in the faint glow of red light that the woman had a beautiful face.

The woman immediately noticed Han Li’s gaze, and seemed to blush. She turned away, and her face was once again hidden in the darkness. However, her bashful eyes still glinted in the darkness.

Han Li couldn’t help but find her actions humorous.

This woman was somewhat odd. When they had yet to see each other’s appearance, she was outspoken, direct, and even a bit unruly. Now that he could see her, the initial harshness has disappeared and she immediately grew timid and bashful.

In that instant, they heard a cry of alarm in the distance.

The man on guard suddenly turned around and harshly whispered, “Not good! Scatter! The Firescale Beast is about to arrive!”

Suddenly, the men that were gathering the fish immediately tossed the bags onto their backs and madly scrabbled in another direction. All that was left behind were the flickering torches illuminating the darkness.

At that moment, several hisses could be heard from within the darkness as if something had discovered the men. Several quick thumps then sounded out.

Several fire-red, meter-long silhouettes leapt from the darkness and quickly disappeared with a blur.

For a instant, Han Li was able to clearly see the appearances of the Firescale Beasts. The beasts had a sinister appearance with red scales and a mouthful of razor sharp fangs.

In the blink of an eye, silence once again covered the cave.

Han Li let out a long breath of relief as it seemed that the strange beasts hadn’t discovered the two of them, providing a silver lining for an otherwise dismal situation.

Not long after the beasts disappeared, Han Li could weakly form a fist with both hands. Soon he finally recovered control over his body and could move well enough to hold onto the woman and slowly stand up.

While being held in his arms, the woman whispered with a blush, “Re... Release me. I will recover soon enough.”

Han Li glanced at the woman and indifferently said, “If you don’t mind squirming around with the fish on the ground, I’ll let you go.”

When the woman heard this, she lowered her head and glanced at the squirming fish on the ground with a trace of hesitation. In the end, she chose to remain silent.

At that moment, Han Li jumped off the pile of fish with the woman in his grasp and walked in the direction of the abandoned torches. Although he didn’t know what or where this forsaken place was, it would prove rather troublesome if they didn’t have any light.

Han Li crouched down and picked up a torch, and wore a pensive expression after glancing around.

A short moment later, the blushing woman whispered, “Please release me. I can move now.”

When Han Li heard this, he silently relaxed his arm and the woman gracefully landed on her feet. After quickly patting down her clothes, she also pick up a torch and examined their surroundings.

After a moment, Han Li suddenly headed off in the direction that the group of men had arrived from.

When the woman saw this, she was alarmed and hastily asked, “Where are you going?”

Han Li replied without turning his head, “I’m not going to wait here for the beasts to return. It would be better to find somewhere safe for now.”

When the woman heard this, she wore an expression of fright and quickly followed after Han Li.

Han Li remained silent when he heard this and continued on his way.

After only walking a few steps, Han Li stopped and used the torch to illuminate the ground, revealing the men’s footprints.

The woman was caught off guard and nearly ran into Han Li. She was left slightly bewildered and whispered, “What’s wrong?”

Han Li didn’t answer her. Instead, he crouched down and brought a handful of sand to his nose. He revealed an odd expression after taking a sniff.

“There’s a dense smell of blood. This isn’t a good sign!” Han Li expressionlessly said this before continuing to follow the men’s footsteps.

The woman was startled by what he said and quickly followed after Han Li.

After the time it took to finish a meal, they eventually spotted a glitter of blue light in the distance.

Han Li narrowed his eyes at the sight and quickened his steps.

He soon discovered that the sparkling blue light marked an exit from this black expanse. Although it was only about three meters wide, it was more than enough for a person to pass through.

When the two saw this, they quickly walked through it with roused spirits.

In the instant they arrived at the opening, a white light flashed before Han Li and eight flawless swords quickly appeared against his neck. A hoarse voice coldly said, “Who are you? Where are Ah Hu and the others? Are you new arrivals?”

Han Li’s heart stirred upon seeing that he was surrounded by over twenty young men and woman. Each of whom held a strange sparkling white blade, and wore the same strange green robes as the men from before. They were all gazing at Han Li with differing expressions.

As for the beautiful woman following him, she had been surrounded as well and didn’t dare to move.

Han Li rubbed his nose and wryly smiled, “I imagine that we are what you consider to be new arrivals! Do outsiders often appear here?”

When the middle-aged man heard Han Li, his expression relaxed but his voice still remained cold, “I would’ve guessed it if you hadn’t said anything as your strange clothes are something only outsiders would wear. However, it’s quite fortunate for you to encounter us. After all, a majority of outsiders meet their ends in the stomach of the umbra beasts without ever realizing what was happening.”

He then waved his hand and the youths withdrew their swords.

Han Li rubbed his neck and glanced at the weapons with a trace of astonishment.

When those blades were touching his neck, he felt an astonishing burning sensation as if they were all made of scorching hot iron. It was a truly weird experience.

Han Li then swept his gaze around and discovered that they were in front of a small stone mountain. It appeared that they had just left the heart of the stone mountain. When he gazed into the distance, there was an endless yellow desert.

He then raised his head to the sky and felt an even greater shock.

He saw pitch-black clouds covering the sky. They appeared endless and continuously arced with deep blue lightning, causing the sky to shine with a faint blue light. It was all stranger than anything Han Li had imagined.

Before Han Li finished observing his surroundings, the lean middle-aged man frowned and asked, “Did you encounter anyone when you arrived? They would be my companions!”

Han Li immediately answered without hesitation, “I saw a group of men, however, they were chased down by a few beasts. They ran off in another direction.”

The lean man grew nervous and he unconsciously tightened his grasp on the blade, “Beasts? What kind?”

“I heard those men call them Firescale Beasts.”

The lean man relaxed and calmly said, “Firescale Beasts? That’s good. Ah Hu and the others should have no problem dealing with them. But just to be sure, Fan Li, bring a group of people inside and help them. Then take them through the nearest alternative exit.”

A towering dark man wordlessly brought a group of people into the cave.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 587: Transient Spirit Qi

Han Li frowned for a moment before calmly saying, “Fellow Daoist Mei, since we arrived here together, it could be considered that there is some destiny between us. Since Lady Mei already mentioned it, I won’t conceal it any longer. I feel that I am somewhat able to climb Stormwind Mountain. Regardless of whether it’s the flying umbra beasts that circle the mountain or the hallucinogenic mist, I have methods of dealing with them. However, these methods will only work for me alone. I do not have the skill to bring along anyone else as I would only be able to take care of myself when danger approaches. Fellow Daoist Mei would be certain to die. Since you are so young, it would be better to stay here. Perhaps there will be another opportunity to leave in the future!”

The final sentence was supposed to comfort her, but when Han Li heard himself say it, he couldn’t help but feel that it sounded quite artificial. However, he had been speaking the truth.

Mei Ning’s face instantly paled and she bit her lips in silence.

When Han Li saw the woman turn silent, he sighed and closed his eyes once more.

To tell the truth, he didn’t have a bad impression of Mei Ning. Were she capable enough, he may have provided assistance. But as of right now, Han Li couldn’t afford to increase the burden to himself. He could only still his heart and leave the woman behind. Fortunately, even if she was left behind in the Umbra Realm, she wouldn’t have too difficult a life. At worst, her path of Immortal cultivation had come an end. He didn’t have anything to feel guilty about!

The room settled into silence. After an unknown amount of time passed, Han Li believed that the woman was crestfallen. When he was about to drift off to sleep, he suddenly heard her say, “If I can temporarily restore a bit of your magic power, would you be able to bring me out?”

“What?” Han Li’s eyes shot open and he stared at the woman with disbelief. His sleepiness had completely disappeared.

Mei Ning had her hands wrapped around her knees as she sat on the bed. Her face turned to the side as if she hadn’t spoken.

Just as Han Li was doubting whether or not he had misheard, the woman stretched her body out and raised her head with determination clear in her eyes. “I have a method to temporarily restore a bit of magic power to Brother Han. Although it will last only a moment, it should be of great assistance when Han Li climbs the mountain. However, in addition to taking me away from this land, I have another condition for my assistance.”

After Mei Ning said this, her expression appeared strange, causing Han Li to feel slight doubt.

Han Li stared at the woman and spoke with a heavy tone, “It’s not that I don’t believe you, but even a Nascent Soul cultivator was trapped here, incapable of restoring his abilities. Is Fellow Daoist Mei joking?”

At that moment, his expression was filled with doubt, but it also contained a trace of hope. If he could temporarily restore his magic power, his odds of escaping would be almost certain. Even if it was only a small bit of magic power for a short amount of time, it would be more than enough.

His storage pouch had several threads that didn’t need spiritual power to activate. With their wondrous powers, his safety would be further guaranteed.

As for his spirit beast pouches, although the Gold Devouring Beetles and the Bloodjade Spider require spiritual sense to control, he would just barely be able to use the Weeping Soul Pearl within his body to control the Weeping Soul Beast. Although those Umbra Beasts weren’t malicious spirits, they were condensed from umbra Qi, something reminiscent of Yin Qi. They should at least be easily restrained, and wouldn’t pose much of a threat to him.

With that thought, Han Li grew excited.

With a hesitant expression, Mei Ning whispered, “Although this little woman doesn’t have mutated spiritual roots or heavenly spiritual roots, I possess the Transient Jade Phoenix Marrow constitution. Brother Han should know what this means. Through a secret technique, I will be able to give Brother Han my Transient Spirit Qi. The Transient Spirit Qi is extremely pure spiritual power, and will be able to ward off the Spirit Extinguishing Qi for a moment. Of course, the Transient Spiritual Qi will eventually scatter, and Fellow Daoist will once again be without any magic power.”

“Transient Jade Phoenix Marrow constitution!” Han Li was stunned for a moment. But soon after, he started to examine the woman with a strange gaze as his face revealed a trace of understanding.

Mei Ning slowly said, “That’s right. If Fellow Daoist doubts me, he may examine me to know that my words aren’t false.” At the same time, a slight blush arose from her face.

“The you must excuse me.” After a moment of hesitation, Han Li stood up and walked over. With something so important, he had no choice but to make certain.

At that moment, Mei Ning forced herself to be calm as she rolled up her sleeve, revealing her arm. The arm actually had a spot of gecko cinnabar on it.[1]

As Han Li watched, the woman clenched her teeth and she lightly pressed her thumb onto the spot before quickly releasing it.

Han Li’s heart stirred as he watched from the bedside. He saw the spot of gecko cinnabar gradually fade away to reveal a silver phoenix pattern. The flowing brilliance made it appear astonishingly lifelike.

Han Li muttered in delighted surprise, “So this is the Transient Jade Spirit Phoenix!”

“Fellow Daoist should now know that I spoke truthfully.” Mei Ning glanced at Han Li to confirm that he had seen it and hastily rolled down her sleeve with a flushed expression.

Han Li nodded his head and silently returned to his seat as he started to think.

Although she cannot be compared to those with extraordinary spiritual roots, she still possessed a rare constitution that was rarely seen even once every hundred years. It’s presence was to be celebrated in the cultivation world and everyone knew of its existence.

Although only female cultivators could possess this constitution and it didn’t provide any assistance on the path of cultivation, they would be in great demand by many male cultivators. This was because once the woman entered late Foundation Establishment stage, her body would produce a strand of pure Transient Spirit Qi.

This Transient Spirit Qi was known to be one of the seven pure spiritual powers in the world. While it was of no use to a woman, it could easily cleanse a man’s essence and allow their cultivation to greatly progress.

Of course, while this essence cleansing effect was of lesser value to higher grade cultivators, it was still comparable to ancient rare medicinal pills.

However, this Transient Spirit Qi was something that could only be passed to a man willingly. There was no way to forcefully extract it from her by using a secret technique. Furthermore, in her entire lifetime, she would only be able to give the Transient Spirit Qi once. She won’t be able to produce more of the spirit Qi for the rest of her life. Additionally, if she lost her maidenhood before the Transient Spirit Qi was transmitted, it would vanish.

Han Li had previously browsed through records that were related to this matter. After recalling them, Han Li felt that if he acquired this spirit Qi, it could be possible that he’d be able to use a bit of magic power. After all, Transient Spirit Qi was one of the seven pure spirit Qi’s in the world. At the very least, it should allow him access to his storage and spirit beast pouches. With that thought, Han Li raised his head and swept his gaze to the beautiful woman, calmly asking, “Lady Mei, could you tell me your other condition?”

After some hesitation, Mei Ning resolutely said, “It’s simple. I wish for Brother Han to find my elder brother and bring him out of the Umbra Realm.”

After some consideration, Han Li shook his head and said, “I’m afraid that I will only be able to meet that condition halfway.”

“Halfway?” Mei Ning wore a strange expression. It was clear she didn’t understand what he meant by this.

“Yes. There is another reason why I can’t remain in the Umbra Realm for too long. As such, I can only agree to do my utmost and spend three months searching for your brother. If I am not able to find him within that time, then I will have to set off immediately.”

After some thought, and feeling that Han Li wouldn’t budge on this matter, she nodded her head and agreed, “Three months! This place isn’t that large. You should be able to find him in that time. Alright, I accept.”

Han Li smiled at her frank acceptance. Mei Ning then stared at Han Li and slowly said, “Although I’ve only known you for a short while, I don’t believe that I’ve misjudged you. As such, to prove to you that I intend to keep my word, I will give you the Transient Spirit Qi whenever you ask. If Brother Han wishes for it now, then I will not hesitate to give it to you.”

[1]. TL: gecko cinnabar is supposed to tell whether or not someone is a virgin.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 588: Sensual Kiss

Han Li was surprised that the woman had spoken so bluntly. However, his surprise only lasted for a moment before his expression quickly returned to normal. “The Umbra Realm is extremely dangerous, and surprises are almost certain to happen. It would be best that I immediately recover magic power so that I may take out a few treasures. Otherwise, we may be unprepared when danger comes knocking.”

Whe Mei Ning heard Han Li, she nodded without the slightest surprise, but she soon thought of something and a slight blush appeared on her face. She whispered, “If I still had magic power, I would be able to easily give you the Transient Spirit Qi with a mere touch of the hand. But under these circumstances, I am only able to transfer it to you through... through mouth to mouth contact.” When Mei Ning said ‘mouth to mouth contact’, she lowered her head and her voice grew nearly indiscernible.

Han Li was startled, but upon seeing her heart-wrenching bashfulness, his heartbeat quickened. In order to restore his magic power, he would have to kiss this beautiful woman. This was an alluring affair that Han Li wouldn’t even have thought of, arousing a strange sensation in his heart. The air in the room became obscurely warm.

Seeing Mei Ning silently lower her head, Han Li knew that she wouldn’t take the initiative despite having little experience in this regard. After all, they didn’t have a particularly intimate relationship.

With that thought, Han Li wordlessly stood up and arrived at the stone bed’s side with a blur, sitting closely at the woman’s side.

Mei Ning unconsciously pulled back, but Han Li’s arm was wrapped around her waist, holding her in place.

The woman’s heart began to heavily thump as she raised her head. When she saw Han Li’s mysterious smile, she bowed her head again with a blush. However, Han Li raised her head with his free hand and prevented her from turning away. Mei Ning felt her mind grew completely blank as her heart fluttered. Han Li took a deep breath and smelled her faint fragrance. Then when he saw the bashful charm that exuded from her eyes, his heart grew fervent and he could no longer restrain himself. He lowered his head and fiercely pressed his lips onto hers.

It was warm, fragrant, and even a little sweet, arousing a feeling of ecstacy. As this occurred, Mei Ning’s eyes grew weak and despondent. But a short moment later, she regained her bearings and she weakly attempted to push Han Li away.

Although she had already made preparations for Han Li’s advance, she became overwhelmed with shyness as she faced the real thing and became completely flustered. Although this woman had many suitors, she had never been intimate with any of them.

The kiss sent waves of ecstasy throughout Han Li, leaving him filled with desire.

When she pushed her hands against Han Li, he boorishly pressed against her soft body. Taking advantage of the fact they were on the bed, he greedily grasped her lips with his own as if they were ambrosia.

Given Mei Ning’s inferior strength, she had lost hope of breaking free once she entered his embrace. Although she had weakly struggled for a moment, she had eventually given up all resistance and closed her eyes, taking in the dense masculine scent that surrounded her. Her cheeks were flushed red as her long eyelashes fluttered, and her mind grew confused and lost.

For a time, the woman had completely forgotten to bestow the Transient Spirit Qi.

However, due to Han Li’s exceedingly staunch will, he was able to regain clarity from his crazed passion after a short moment.

Han Li parted lips with Mei Ning for the time being and brought his mouth to her fine small ears. He chuckled and said, “Lady Mei, although the feeling of a man and a woman being together is truly wonderful, don’t forget to bestow the Transient Spirit Qi to me.”

When she heard this, her body trembled and her face grew to an even deeper shade of scarlet.

Han Li’s boorish behavior from before had now disappeared. He gently pressed his lips against her small mouth and began to feel a cold sensation slowly enter his body from their lips.

Han Li didn’t dare to be negligent and hastily climbed off Mei Ning and sat down cross-legged to the side as he began to circulate the spiritual Qi throughout his body.

Soon after, Mei Ning sat upright on the bed and flusteredly straightened out her disheveled robes with a scarlet face. For a time, she was incapable to regaining her bearings. The woman hesitantly stole a quick peek at Han Li and saw that his eyes were closed, causing her to unconsciously sigh in relief.

She then stood up from the bed and walked over to the chair that Han Li originally sat in. A complicated expression appeared on her face as she began to stare at Han Li’s tranquil expression.

After an unknown amount of time, Han Li eventually opened his eyes and saw the worried expression in Mei Ning’s eyes. In that instant, she hastily turned her face away, not daring to meet his gaze.

Han Li smiled upon seeing that the woman was at a loss. However, his smile immediately disappeared as he slapped his storage pouch. Items began to continuously emerge with flashes of white light, appearing at Han Li’s side. Not longer after, a large pile had formed.

There were materials such as demon beast hides among these items. It was unknown what Han Li intended to use them for.

“You can use magic power!” Although Mei Ning held confidence in her Transient Spirit Qi, she had shouted in joy upon seeing that Han Li was truly able to use his storage pouch.

Han Li smiled and said, “I don’t possess enough magic power to even cast low grade magic techniques, but opening a storage pouch shouldn’t be a problem.” After making sure that he had everything he needed, he put away the ancient treasures such as the golden mirrors, the flower basket, and the silver bell into the storage pouch with a wave of his sleeve.

When Mei Ning saw this, she was overwhelmed for a moment. An odd expression appeared on her face when she glanced at the pile of items at Han Li’s side.

Feeling that something was amiss, she hesitantly asked,“Brother Han, I haven’t asked you this yet. Are you a Foundation Establishment cultivator?”

Han Li had no intention of concealing anything and openly replied, “Of course not. I am a Core Formation cultivator!”

“What!” Although Mei Ning had suspected this, she couldn’t but cry out in surprise.

Han Li chuckled and paid no further heed to the woman’s sudden change in expression. He slapped the spirit beast pouch at his side, summoning a small monkey in a flash of brilliance. Surprisingly, the Weeping Soul Beast was extremely excited once it appeared. It sniffed around Han Li several times before frequently hopping around him.

Han Li’s heart stirred at the sight.

Having yet to recognize this famed beast, Mei Ning merely glanced at the monkey with a curious expression.

“Lady Mei, stay here for a moment. I wish to take advantage of my remaining magic power and attend to a few matters,” Han Li calmly said.

“A few matters?” The woman blinked in slight confusion.

Without saying anything further, Han Li began to store various items amongst his robes and departed from the room without paying any heed to the items he left behind.

Upon leaving the room, Han Li glanced around. The sky appeared the same as always since there was differentiation of day or night, but regardless, there was far less movement in the village. It was likely that a majority of people had fallen asleep.

Han Li beckoned to the Weeping Soul Beast, and had it enter his sleeve with a quick scamper. He then smiled at Mei Ning before confidently walking off.

As for Mei Ning, she merely remained in the room with blank confusion on her face.

Han Li walked through the village with extremely nimble movements, avoiding the gaze of others. In an instant, he stopped in front of one of the larger buildings in the village. After taking a quick glance around, he pushed open the door without any hesitation and walked inside. Han Li’s expression then revealed joy. As expected, this was one of the buildings that stored “dark water”.

Han Li took out several large capacity void containers that he early grabbed from his storage pouch and filled up about half of the building’s reserves before leaving.

Then after turning a few corners, he spotted a rather unusually fashioned stone building. His expression stirred and he stopped in place. If hadn’t guessed incorrectly, this should be the residence of the middle-aged man surnamed Feng.

At that moment, he felt his meager magic power begin to fade away.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 589: Guests

Han Li swept his gaze over his surroundings. Ensuring that no one was nearby, he slapped his spirit beast pouch and had a single black-tainted Gold Devouring Beetle silently fly out. Then with great difficulty, he managed to command it with a sliver of spiritual sense. The insect then shot toward the stone room with a buzz and slipped in through a small crack.

The building was extremely quiet.

Han Li inwardly sneered and walked back to his residence without looking behind him. By the time he had turned a corner, he heard a miserable wail from the middle-aged man’s residence.

Han Li pursed his lips and expressionlessly continued on his way. However, the disturbance had already began to attract the attention of the villagers.

Since the middle-aged man was all but guaranteed to come for revenge, it would be better to cleanly deal with him while Han Li still had use of his magic power and spiritual sense. Otherwise, the man would remain a worry on his mind.

The remaining magic power that had been produced by the Transient Spirit Qi had disappeared by the time he returned to his residence. Likewise, his spiritual sense was once again incapable of leaving his body. Han Li could only shake his head in helplessness as he hurried back.

After walking into the room, he found Mei Ning lying down on the bed. From the rhythm of her soft breaths, it seemed she had fallen asleep a while ago.

When Han Li saw her sleeping figure, he recalled the kiss from not long before and felt his heart roil. But after seeing the woman’s figure coldly curled up on the bed, he hesitated for a moment before fetching a large piece of demon beast hide from the pile of materials on the table and placing it on top of the woman.

She soon relaxed her expression, and she unconsciously rolled the beast hide around her, remaining soundly asleep.

Han Li couldn’t help but chuckle at the sight.

This turn of events was of no surprise. Although she possessed a body that was far superior to ordinary mortals, she was still a member of the fairer sex and both her mind and body must’ve been exhausted from all that happened. As a result, she had unintentionally fallen asleep.

Han Li smiled and then turned his attention to the pile of materials on the desk with a strange expression appearing in his eyes.

Not long after, Mei Ning slowly roused from her slumber. Before her eyes were entirely open, she heard a calm voice speak, “If Fellow Daoist Mei is awake, then please get up. We will be busy with preparations over the next two days.”

After she heard Han Li’s words, her face reddened and she sat up. Naturally, the demon beast hide fell off as a result.

This surprised her and she glanced in the direction of Han Li’s voice with a complicated expression.

Han Li was currently sitting in a chair and was handling a rather large piece of demon beast hide. After Mei Ning rose, he smiled at her.

“Would Fellow Daoist Mei happen to be skilled in needlework? I have a few high grade fire-attribute demon beast hides. If it is possible, it would be best to turn them into clothes so that we’d be able to better resist Yin winds.”

Mei Ning’s embarrassment waned after seeing that Han Li hadn’t brought up the matter of yesterday’s kiss. But for some unknown reason, she also felt a trace of indescribable disappointment. Still, her face slightly blushed as she replied, “I can give it a try, but I’ll be requiring a needle and thread.”

Han Li grabbed a faint blue needle on the table and handed it over to her. “This demon beast hide is rather tough. Only flying needle magic tools are able to pierce through them. You’ll also be using the beast’s tendons to sew the hide together. In the end, we will only use this to withstand the Yin winds so there is no point in caring about appearance.”

The needle was a top grade magic treasure that was extremely sharp. Han Li had acquired it from some unfortunate cultivator that he had already forgotten about. He felt that it would prove quite useful as of present and took it out of his storage pouch.

Mei Ning bit on her lips and softly whispered, “I will do my best.”

Han Li nodded and thought to say something else when he heard footsteps from outside. An old man’s voice soon followed, “Is Fellow Daoist present?”

“Who is it?” Han Li asked, confused. He felt that the voice was rather familiar, and soon recalled that it belonged to the long haired old man.

“Hehe, Fellow Daoist and I had quite an enjoyable chat yesterday on top of the stone platform!”

Since it was the cultivator from the day before, Han Li found it awkward to keep the door shut. And since he was also curious about why they had suddenly paid him a visit, he walked towards the door and opened it, revealing the chuckling long-haired old man and two other old men behind him. One was red-faced and white-haired while the other had a hunchback and an eerie aura.

“Please, come in!” Han Li confidently invited the three in without asking them of their intentions.

“So this is Fellow Daoist Mei!” When the three saw Mei Ning, they revealed a slight trace of astonishment before calmly saluting her.

Mei Ning returned the greeting and moved to stand by Han Li’s side. She remained silent as if she were deferring the matter to Han Li.

The three pensively glanced at one another. After they took a seat, Han Li glanced at the other two and slowly asked, “Are these two also...?”

“Fellow Daoist guessed correctly. These two are fellow cultivators who arrived from the Great State of Jin. This is Fellow Daoist Yun from the Heavenly Talisman Sect, and this is Fellow Daoist Jin from the Four Seas Institute.”

Han Li nodded his head to each of them. The two then examined Han Li before politely smiling at him.

Han Li calmly asked, “May I ask what brings you three here?”

The three old men unconsciously glanced at each other. After a short moment, the long haired old man dryly coughed and spoke with a deep tone, “Fellow Daoist Han might not know this, but Elder Feng, the village’s instructor for martial arts, suddenly died after being devoured alive by a nameless, exotic insect. It is said that the exotic insect bit his neck in his sleep, and he died a miserable death as a result.”

With a completely unchanged expression, Han Li indifferently said, “Oh, so it was like that? What kind of exotic insect could possibly be so fearsome?” The three then began to mutter among themselves, as they were unable to tell whether or not Han Li was related to the event.

The long-haired old man stared at Han Li as he slowly said, “This isn’t entirely clear. By the time he screamed, he was already on the verge of death. When the other villagers saw a flying insect fly from his wound, they immediately struck it with their weapons, but as the insect was incredibly hard, they weren’t able to wound it in the least. As the insect was covered in blood, it was difficult to make out the exact details of its appearance.” The other two solemnly stared at Han Li in silence.

With an unchanged expression, Han Li leaned back in his chair and lazily said, “What? Could it be you three believe that I killed him? Are you three here to punish me?”

The old man’s expression slightly changed as he chuckled, “How could that be possible! We absolutely don’t believe that Fellow Daoist Han could’ve done such a thing. Even if he did it, we would be incredibly happy. That mortal named Feng had always viewed us with disdain just because of his martial arts. It is better that he is dead.”

Han Li narrowed his eyes and stared at the three in silence.

The long-haired old man’s eyes shifted and he probingly said, “However, I heard that Elder Feng paid a visit to Fellow Daoist’s room yesterday. Soon after, he left in a crestfallen manner. Additionally, they found that his arm was broken at the time of death. It seems even without any magic power, Fellow Daoist Han still possess some powerful techniques!”

Upon hearing their words, Han Li raised his eyebrows. It seemed these three held some influence in the village. They were actually able to find out that the man surnamed Feng had entered his room yesterday and that he was driven off.

After a moment of silence, Han Li’s voice grew cold. “Could you three Fellow Daoists be here for that matter? If that’s the case, please be direct. I have no interest in beating around the bush.”

“This...” The old men couldn’t help but glance at each other with hesitant expressions upon seeing Han Li be so direct.

Unwilling to speak in circles, Han Li’s expression grew impatient. “Since you are unwilling to speak, then I won’t force you. How about you come back some other time?”

Spurred by Han Li’s words, the hunchbacked old man said, “Fellow Daoist Han, would you be interested in governing the village with us?”

“What do you mean?” Han Li frowned, already guessing what he truly meant.

Seeing that his companion had already struck the main point of the matter, the long haired old man revealed everything, “Since we are fellow cultivators, I will speak bluntly. Surely Fellow Daoist saw that apart from the head elder, all of the others are mortals. They hold greater power in the village because they were here before us. Cultivators are held to the same standard as mortals, and eat and starve as they do. The mortals even have us risk our lives to hunt umbra beasts. Contrarily, we are the only ones that are capable of using spells with the umbra beast gems, yet they all hold the gems in their hands. It is utterly humiliating to be treated as criminals without cause. Since this is the case, us cultivators have joined hands to grasp authority in the village. Would Fellow Daoist Han care to join us?”

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant

Chapter 590: Bone Case

After hearing their offer to take control of the village, Han Li indifferently asked, “So you wish to seize power?”

The red-faced old man spoke with a strange emotion flickering within his eyes, “That’s right, how can cultivators like us serve at the beck and call of those so-called elders? We should be the elders of the village, not those mortals. I am a grand Foundation Establishment cultivator. It is unbearable to have been controlled by mortals for this long. Because we had too few cultivators, we didn’t dare to take action, but with the addition of you two, success will be very likely.”

Han Li swept his gaze over the three and expressionlessly said, “I’m not interested. Please return. I’ll pretend that this discussion never took place.”

Han Li’s response had greatly shocked them. The long-haired old man then forced a smile and further attempted to persuade him, “Does Fellow Daoist truly wish to become an inhabitant of this village? So long as we seize the positions of elders in the village, the power will be divided amongst us few. As a result, even if the conditions are poor, we can act freely.”

Han Li stroked his chin and serenely said, “I think that you Fellow Daoists are misunderstanding something. The two of us never said we intended on staying in this village. We will be leaving in two days. As such, your words are based on nothing more than a fantasy. Lady Mei and I will have nothing to do with the matter.”

After a moment of shock, the long-haired old man couldn’t help but say, “Leaving? Are you two searching for another village since you are unsatisfied with this one? You two might not know this, but our village is the among the best villages in the area. The other villages’ conditions are far worse than ours.”

Han Li smiled and lightly shook his head in silence.

The hunchbacked old man wore a look of astonishment when he came to a realization. “Could it be that you two intend on climbing Stormwind Mountain?”

Han Li smiled and said, “What’s wrong? Since we are unwilling to remain here, is there anything strange about wanting to leave?”

With an odd expression on his face, the red-faced old man twirled his beard and said, “This isn’t something that is merely strange. Don’t you two realize that Stormwind Mountain is extremely dangerous?”

Han Li looked at him and flatly said, “Although I don’t know much about it, I’ve gained an approximate understanding from the chief elder.”

The hunchbacked old man’s face contorted several times before he fearlessly said, “Humph! What does he know of the Stormwind Mountain’s fearsomeness? He probably only knows from hearsay, but Fellow Daoist Yun and I have personally experienced the true terror of Stormwind Mountain. It isn’t something that cultivators can face without magic power. The tremendously powerful umbra beasts that surround the mountain are an instant death sentence if you alarm them. Even if you manage to luckily slip past them, the violent Yin winds and the illusory mist are incredibly deadly. There wouldn’t be the slightest chance of climbing to the top of the mountain. Furthermore, being able to leave the Umbra Realm during an appearance of a crevice in space is only a rumor as no one has truly tested it. Perhaps it isn’t even possible to begin with.”

Han Li’s expression stirred and he asked with great interest, “You two Fellow Daoists have already climbed Stormwind Mountain? Could you tell us about it?”

The red-faced cultivator revealed trepidation as he slowly said, “Of course, Fellow Daoist Han. We also wish to talk of it in the hopes that Fellow Daoist will abandon his hope of succeeding by a fluke. Originally, Fellow Daoist Jin and I were unwilling to spend the rest of our lives here when we had just arrived at the Umbra Realm. After spending a year in preparation, we set off to Stormwind Mountain together along with three other Fellow Daoists. Before we even arrived at the peak, one of our members was discovered by an umbra beast and was devoured. The rest of us painstakingly pushed forward, but two of our ranks were frozen from the Yin winds a quarter way up the mountain. As Fellow Daoist Jin and I carried a few ember stones on our body, we were able to persevere.

“But as we climbed higher, the Yin winds became increasingly more powerful and we were incapable of keeping steady footing. In the end, we only made it halfway up the mountain before were blown off a cliff by the gales; we hadn’t even reached the illusory mists. Surviving by sheer luck, we lost all will to continue onward and could only return helplessly. And after we managed to return to the village, we were bedridden for several months due to having the Yin winds penetrate deeply into our bones. Once we eventually recovered, we completely abandoned any thoughts of climbing Stormwind Mountain.”

Han Li rubbed his chin and pensively muttered, “That is quite fearsome!”

The old man spoke in a sincere tone, “It was far more fearsome than could be described. Please, perish the thought and abandon the attempt. Although it may seem possible, the mountain will take your life. Besides, you are still young. Once we reach our end, all the authority in the village will fall into your hands.”

“Fellow Daoists, please don’t try to change my mind. I will only abandon my hopes after personally failing in the attempt. Naturally, if I am truly incapable of reaching Stormwind Mountain’s peak, then I will give deep consideration towards your proposal.”

The three were somewhat displeased at his response and further attempted to persuade him. However, Han Li remained completely determined.

Helpless, the three turn their gazes to Mei Ning, but she only said, “I will follow Brother Han’s decision regardless.” Their gazes turned blank at her response.

Fortunately, Han Li hadn’t refused them. If he managed to survive his attempt to climb the mountain, they would have another opportunity to recruit him. Since they were unable to persuade them, they could only force a smile before taking their leave.

After they reached a distance away, the hunchbacked old man solemnly asked, “Do you think they will betray us?”

The long-haired old man shook his head. “Betray us? What do they have to gain from betraying us? Surely you saw that the youngster surnamed Han is an intelligent person. He wouldn’t do something so foolish, and the woman is following his lead as well. We can only hope that the two will realize the truth once they draw close to Stormwind Mountain and will turn back. After all, our revolt only has a fifty-fifty chance of success. With the other two, our strength would be considerably increased. Fortunately, Youngster Han unwittingly eliminated the greatest obstacle, Feng Tianji. His martial arts would’ve posed a difficult problem otherwise.”

The red-faced old man nodded his head, “That’s right. This person is truly cautious and wouldn’t do something so strenuous and unrewarding. But just in case, we should send people to monitor them to avoid any potential mishaps.”

“Brother Yin is quite thorough. Please have it done. However, we must be careful and avoid having him discover them. Regardless...” A doubtful expression appeared on the long-haired old man’s face.

The hunchbacked old man was confused and asked, “Regardless?”

The long-haired old man muttered, “It might be an error on my part, but I felt that Youngster Han seemed completely confident that he could depart from the Umbra Realm. He was completely unphased when we mentioned the dangers of Stormwind Mountain. Could it be that he truly has a way to climb to the peak of Stormwind Mountain?”

The hunchbacked old man shook his head and dubiously said, “How is that possible? The Yin winds are unsurmountable. Brother Yun, I, and the countless frozen corpses around the mountain can attest to this. It is only a vain thought to believe one could actually escape this place.”

“Yes, it must’ve been a trick of the eyes!” After some thought, the long-haired old man concluded that it was truly impossible and smiled in self-mockery.

But when the red-faced old man heard this, his heart suddenly stirred and a thought came to mind.

When the three old men departed, Han Li spoke a few words to Mei Ning and left the room. He went over to the residence of the middle-aged man surnamed Feng and saw that he did truly die from having his throat torn open by the Gold Devouring Beetle.

After taking a look at his corpse from a distance, Han Li left and began to continue his inquiries with the villagers about the circumstances of the land, the whereabouts of other villages and the distribution of the umbra beasts. Eventually all of these small details were gathered together in his mind as information vital to escaping this land, and he was able to draw a detailed map from the villager’s descriptions.

In the following two days, Han Li finished most of his preparations and went to inform the village chief elder that they intended on climbing Stormwind Mountain.

The plump old man naturally felt that this was a pity and urged Han Li to stay, but after seeing Han Li’s unwavering resolve, he didn’t push the issue.

After Han Li returned to the residence, he and Mei Ning slept through the night. But in the early hours of morning on the next day, someone stealthily paid them a visit and knocked on their door.

When Han Li saw the red-faced old man, he was shocked. “Fellow Daoist Yun!”

“Fellow Daoist Han, I will keep matters short. Although I don’t know whether or not you truly have the ability to leave this land, you could be considered my last hope. If you truly are capable of slipping past the disasters of Stormwind Mountain, I hope that you can deliver this box to my Heavenly Talisman Sect.” With a serious expression, he took out a rough case made of bone and handed it over to Han Li with both hands.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant

Chapter 591: Spirit Subjugation Talisman

Han Li glanced at the case made of bone, but didn’t move to receive it. With an indifferent expression, he asked, “What do you mean?” He wasn’t about to take the case before realizing what it was.

The red-faced old man let out a long sigh and said, “There is no need for Fellow Daoist to think much of it. The case contains the refinement method for one of our sect protecting talismans, the Spirit Subjugation Talisman. Originally, only the sect master could learn it. I only have one intention; I wish for Fellow Daoist Han to deliver the talisman refinement method on my behalf. I don’t wish for the talisman to forever be lost from the sect.” Soon after, he lifted the cover of the case to reveal several pieces of engraved bone.

A trace of hesitation appeared on Han Li’s face, “The Spirit Subjugation Talisman? Since only the sect master could learn, then your esteemed self must be the Heavenly Talisman Sect Master?”

The old man conceded, “I shamefully admit that I am the fifty-seventh sect master of the Heavenly Talisman Sect, a small dying sect from the State of Jin’s Flower Cloud Province. It is quite laughable that a Foundation Establishment cultivator like myself acted in the position of sect master.”

A strange expression momentarily appeared on Han Li’s face but he soon frowned. After a short moment, he glanced at the old man and slowly said, “The Spirit Subjugation Talisman should certainly be unique considering that only the sect master could learn it. Fellow Daoist Yun doesn’t fear that I would learn of its contents? Additionally, while I have heard of the resounding name of your country, I’ve never been there before, and I am unsure of whether or not an opportunity would truly arise for me to visit. From how I see it, aren’t you being a bit too rash?”

When the red-faced old man heard Han Li’s questions, he didn’t reveal the slightest surprise. Instead, he replied with an appreciative expression, “Since I am giving this item to you, I’ve already accepted that Fellow Daoist Han will learn the talisman refinement technique as payment. To tell the truth, I’m not sure whether you would be interested in learning it after taking a look at it. Although the refinement method of the Spirit Subjugation talisman has been passed down from generation it generation, it had only been refined a scarce few times by the founders. It has merely continued to be passed down despite not being refined by the later sect masters. And since my own sect was already greatly weakened, this talisman will only serve as a sentimental dream of mine.

“As for whether or not Brother Han can arrive in the country of Jin, it doesn’t really matter. I merely find peace of mind that the sect founder’s creation isn’t forever lost from the cultivation world. Even if the talisman refinement method truly isn’t capable of returning to the sect, it will be good enough if Fellow Daoist Han passes it down so that it doesn’t remain lost. When I later face the previous generations of sect masters in the underworld, I will have an excuse.” The red-faced old man spoke with a bitter smile.

When Han Li heard this, he was somewhat dumbfounded.

The Heavenly Talisman’s sect master was only seeking peace of mind. It seemed that the exchange was incredibly one sided in Han Li’s favor and that he wouldn’t suffer any loss. If he truly was incapable of going to the Great State of Jin, then he had no obligation to return the bone case. But if he was able to visit this famed country, then delivering the item would only take a minor effort.

Furthermore, it seemed that the Spirit Subjugation Talisman was a rather miraculous talisman for it to be so difficult to refine. It greatly piquied Han Li’s interest! According to his vast experiences, apart from the commonly refined talismans of the five elements, there were talismans with unfathomable and extraordinary effects known as secret talismans.

These secret talismans weren’t difficult to differentiate among the five elements. Additionally, each sect had their own unique method of refining their own secret talisman, making it extremely difficult for outsiders to copy them.

For example, when the Star Palace Elders had nearly killed him in a sneak attack from Heavenvoid Hall, they had used a proxy produced by the Incarnation Talisman. Afterwards, they used a transportation talisman unique to the Star Palace to escape. Of course,the Incarnation talisman was worth far more than the teleportation talisman despite both being secret talismans.

After some further thought, Han Li accepted the bone case without any further hesitation and solemnly pledged, “I can only promise that I will try my best. Fellow Daoist Yun shouldn’t expect too much.”

“Hehe, that’s fine! I am already completely grateful for Brother Han’s words.” The red-faced old man appreciatively thanked him several times. Afterwards, he had a quick chat with Han Li before tactfully taking his leave.

Han Li stood by the building’s entrance as he watched the old man walk away before weighing the bone case in his hand. It was light; there didn’t seem to be anything profound about the bone case itself.

Mei Ning, who had been silently standing behind him, couldn’t help but ask, “This is the first time I’ve heard of this Spirit Subjugation Talisman. Could it truly be powerful?”

Han Li smiled at Mei Ning and said, “I don’t know, but I reckon it is unordinary at the very least!” Soon after, he sat down beside the table in the room and started to look through each of the bones.

“Yi!” After a mere glance, Han Li yelped in shock.

“What? Is there a problem with the talisman refinement method?” Mei Ning sat down across from Han Li and glanced at him with bright curiosity. Ever since their kiss, they’d become somewhat more familiar with one another and their original awkwardness had disappeared.

“It’s nothing. It’s just that the materials required to refine the Spirit Subjugating Talisman are truly extraordinary. It was no wonder that the Heavenly Talisman Sect didn’t dare to refine this talisman.” After looking through all of the bones, he casually closed the bone case aside.

Mei Ning curiously asked, “What are these materials that Brother Han find so extraordinary?”

Han Li grabbed a bone shard and smiled, saying, “It’s primary materials can’t be considered much. But there is one extraordinary material that can’t be bought with spirit stones: the soul of a metamorphosis stage demon beast. Wouldn’t you say that is extraordinary?”

“The soul of a demon beast at metamorphosis stage?” Mei Ning gasped in astonishment.

However, Han Li’s mysterious expression as he grasped the bone shard had completely escaped her notice.

Having rested for the night, Han Li and Mei Ning left the village without notifying anybody else, much to the astonishment of the village guards.

...

Han Li found himself standing on yet another pile of rocks as he gazed into the yellow desert in front of him. After getting their bearings, Han Li and Mei Ning headed towards the nearest village.

Han Li’s plans were quite simple: find the elder brother of Mei Ning. If he was alive, he was certain to be found in another village, and when he was found, Han Li would bring him and Mei Ning to Stormwind Mountain. Mei Ning felt that this plan was reasonable and followed his lead without complaint.

Then in the blink of an eye, the two faded away into the endless sand.

...

In an expanse of blood-crimson soil, there were a dozen young grey-robed men and women with bone pikes stealthily climbing up a tall mound and slowly surrounding it.

At the top of the mound, there were many green beasts with short and thick necks who were currently curled up in their sleep.

These were umbra beasts by the name of Jade Yin Toads. Their bodies were small and covered in lumps. While they appeared as if they were just enlarged toads from the mortal world, they didn’t possess an ounce of poison on their bodies and were one of the few umbra beasts that were edible to humans.

These people had naturally come to hunt the Jade Yin Toads to ease the crisis of their village’s food shortage.

The group’s actions were nimble and silent. By the time they had completely surrounded them, a Jade Yin Toad suddenly opened its red eyes and saw that there were humans about a hundred meters away.

“Attack!” As soon as that was shouted, the beast began to croak in warning, but in the blink of an eye, over a dozen sparkling white bone pikes were shot towards the beasts.

As a result, a majority of the Jade Yin Toads had leapt away, and only two had met the barrage of spears. However, these two were the most vigorous of the toads and they managed to dodge out of the way, ending up with only scrapes from the spears.

The Jade Yin Toads were among the weakest of umbra beasts. Apart from being able to spout a few mouthfuls of Yin Qi, they had few other powerful attacks. However, they were particularly adept at using their powerful jumps to escape with astonishing effectiveness.

The remaining two Jade Yin Toads took large breaths and spouted out large clouds of black Yin Qi. Afterwards, they jumped twenty five meters into the air and broke the encirclement. Although the group had continued to use their pikes without reserve, they were clearly too slow, and were incapable of catching up to the two Jade Yin Toads.

After the two Jade Yin Toads leapt towards a strange expanse of stone in the distance, a flash of azure light sparked, resulting in the two toads falling to the ground with their throats gouged.

Green blood painted the red ground.

This scene caused the dismayed youths to look on with astonishment.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant

Chapter 592: Absorbing Souls

With gusts of winds, two azure streaks flew out from the umbra beast corpses towards a nearby bolder. Afterwards, a man and a woman clothed in blue beast leather appeared on top of the boulder with a blur.

The man’s appearance was ordinary in contrast to the woman’s heart-swaying beauty, but a vast intelligence shined within his eyes. These two individuals were Han Li and Mei Ning. Han Li held two inch-long daggers in each of his hands. There was semi-transparent string wrapped around both of their hilts which appeared to be made from a slim beast tendon.

Han Li walked over and glanced down at the umbra beast carcasses before turning his gaze to the vigilant crowd. He smiled and amiably said, “I hope you won’t take offense. I saw that two Jade Yin Toads were about to escape and I couldn’t help but take action. But regardless, I have no desire towards these Jade Yin Toads; I merely wish to ask you a few questions.”

One of the older party members doubtfully asked, “You truly do not want the beast carcasses?” It seemed he was the leader of the group of youths.

Han Li nudged a beast carcass with his foot and affirmatively replied, “Of course I don’t. I already have plenty of food.”

Although the man felt this was somewhat strange, he felt that there was nothing to lose and he eventually nodded his head, “Alright, go ahead and ask.”

Han Li nodded, satisfied to see his tactful response, and calmly asked, “Are you natives to this land?”

The man frowned and replied, “That’s right. We are villagers of Red Soil Village.”

“That’s good. We arrived here to make some inquiries. Have there been any new arrivals that have joined your village? We are searching for someone.”

After a moment of thought, he hesitantly said, “New arrivals? None. However, after the appearance of the last spatial tear, we spotted several remains of both men and women in the umbra beast lair. By the time we spotted them, umbra beasts had already cleanly devoured them until nothing but bones were left.”

Standing behind Han Li, Mei Ning grimaced and said, “Bones?”

In the past month, the two had already visited three villages. Although there were a couple of cultivators that had narrowly survived the spatial tear, there was no sign of her brother.

Seeing that Han Li only wished to find someone, he relaxed and openly said, “That’s right. We’ve already buried their remains, but we have their possessions. They were placed in a village warehouse. Would you like to take a look?”

Han Li glanced at the silent Mei Ning before nodding, “That’d be good. We’ll have to trouble you.” If her brother’s possessions happened to be among them, then the search would be over. He had to confirm them just in case.

After calling out to those behind him to deal with the carasses of the toads, he cordially chatted with Han Li, “Hehe! From your tone, it seems you’re quite cultured. I could tell you’re an outsider. Have you just arrived in this land?”

Han Li beamingly smiled in response.

The two then followed the group for a couple of kilometers before arriving at an unfamiliar village.

This village was far smaller than the others. Although they also had stone walls surrounding them, they were only about twenty meters tall and appeared worn out as if it from long neglect.

From the size of the village, it seemed there were only about a hundred inhabitants at most.

After entering the village, their leader pointed at a relatively large stone room and apologetically told the two cultivators to head to the building by themselves. As the toad carcasses were vitally important, the villagers had to deal with them first.

Han Li didn’t mind this and spoke a few words of thanks before heading there with Mei Ning. 　　……

Han Li glanced at the torn, bloody robes and asked with slight surprise, “These truly belonged to your brother?”

Han Li truly didn’t expect that as soon as they entered that Mei Ning would immediately spot her brother’s remnants. Her face had immediately grown pale at the sight and her eyes had become completely dispirited.

Mei Ning stared at the remnants with red eyes and muttered, “How could I possibly mistake these clothes? I personally made them for him. The storage pouch also has our sect’s insignia.”

Not knowing what to say to console her, Han Li could only hesitate for a moment before patting the woman’s shoulders and quietly slipping away from the stone room. He knew that it would be better for her to be alone for the time being.

Just after he left, he began to hear faint sobs from the room. Han Li let out a sigh and then looked to the sky in silence.

A while later, Mei Ning left the room with swollen eyes. She calmly said, “Let’s go. Since my brother has passed, there is no longer any need to visit the other villages. Let’s head straight to Stormwind Mountain!” It seemed she had stifled the pain from the loss of her brother.

Han Li calmly replied, “Before we head off to Stormwind Mountain, there is still something I must do. I need to acquire a few umbra beast gems.”

Mei Ning was stunned for a moment before asking in surprise, “Beast gems! What use is there in collecting them? They’re quite difficult to come by.”

“I have my own reasons for collecting them. I reckon that in the entire world, the umbra realm is the only place where one can find umbra beast gems. Even if one could find them elsewhere, they would likely be extremely scarce. Gathering umbra beast gems would’ve been incredibly difficult if we wished to acquire them when we had first arrived. However, we won’t be the ones handling the umbra beasts. It will be this one.” Han Li suddenly shook his sleeve and a green flash of light appeared before him.”

Mei Ming glanced at the small monkey that had suddenly appeared with suspicion, “This one?”

With a certain expression, Han Li said, “Of course!”

Because Han Li used the safer routes on his journey to find other villages, he was able to handle the low grade beasts by using only his flying swords. However, this didn’t result in him acquiring any umbra beast gems. Knowing that they had some relation to the puppets of Heavenvoid Hall, Han Li naturally wanted to collect a few.

At that moment, he called out to Mei Ning and had the Weeping Soul Beast return to his sleeve. He would spend the night at Red Soil Village before setting off and testing the efficacy of the Weeping Soul Beast on umbra beasts.

...

A twenty meter tall clawed beast leisurely walked out of a valley. Its huge claws were overpowering and its mouth was filled with vicious fangs. As the hegemon of the area, it had no fear of any high grade umbra beasts suddenly attacking it.

But at that moment, its dull ears suddenly heard something moving, and it turned its head with a malicious light glinting in its eyes. About a hundred meters away, a foot tall monkey had unknowingly appeared.

The small monkey was currently staring at the colossal beast with immense excitement.

When the huge beast caught sight of the small monkey, it merely snorted several times, wishing to scare it away. However, the monkey actually attacked, shooting out a yellow mist that enveloped it with fantastical speed.

After the mist of yellow light enveloped it, the colossal beast released a world-shaking roar, but the yellow mist quickly dimmed and shot back into the small monkey’s large nose, carrying streaks of black Qi.

The small monkey chewed with great relish before patting its bulging belly. Its face appeared completely satisfied as if it just had a delicious meal.

At that moment, Han Li leisurely walked out with a relaxed expression. A flabbergasted Mei Ning followed after him.

The woman found this entire scene absurd. She had witnessed the enormous beast turning into a shriveled corpse in the blink of an eye. Another wave of disbelief suddenly crossed her mind when she faintly recalled the legend of a certain fearsome spirit beast.

As Mei Ning recovered from her shock, Han Li had already arrived in front of the beast’s head. With a wave of his sleeve, a sparkling silver dagger appeared in his hand.

He expressionlessly chopped down, splitting the beast’s skull like a watermelon. Soon after, a thumb-sized green gem fell out from the remains.

Han Li smiled at the sight of it and bent down to pick it up. Han Li then turned his head to the west and assuredly said, “There should be many more powerful umbra beasts about three kilometers west. Let’s take care of them along the way.”

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant

Chapter 593: Stormwind Mountain

Stormwind Mountain was a huge mountain located in the northeast edge of the umbra realm. One could only see the bottom half of the mountain from the distance as the rest of it was densely covered in Yin clouds.

The mountain was made up of bare black stone and lacked any kind of vegetation. Additionally, it was over four kilometers high with storms of fierce Yin winds blowing around it. If common men were to climb it, they would only add to the many black ice sculptures already decorating the mountain.

The treacherous conditions of the mountain also caused its surroundings to become particularly gloomy. With endless thunder ringing from the skies and cold howling winds scattering stone and sand, it seemed as if the area was truly haunted.

Since places with dense umbra Qi were beloved by powerful umbra beasts, it was only natural for many fearsome demon beasts to occupy the nearby land. But today, there were some uninvited visitors paying a visit to Stormwind Mountain.

A beast carcass that was over a hundred meters tall fell onto the ground in a flash of silver light. The carcass then shriveled in an instant as the silver light flew away into the distance carrying an expanse of black Qi.

A moment later, a huge world-shaking roar filled the air.

Following a series of heavy thuds on the ground, a thirty-meter-tall silver ape appeared at the side of the umbra beast carcass. The huge ape’s appearance was malevolent and vicious with each of its movements exuding an astonishing pressure. However, Han Li and Mei Ning were sitting on its back.

Han Li swept his gaze over the beast carcass and pushed off against the ape before deftly landing on the carcass’s skull. In the instant he landed, a cold glint flickered in his eyes and the carcass’s skull split open, revealing nothing at all.

Han Li revealed a trace of disappointment, but his face soon turned back to normal.

As of current, he had accumulated over a hundred umbra beast gems. Although he knew there was a small chance that the groups of low grade umbra beasts could result in an umbra beast gem, he didn’t have the time to hunt every single one of them down. He had to climb Stormwind Mountain before the next spatial tear appeared.

Mei Ning had also jumped down from the huge ape’s shoulder. A second later, the huge ape flashed with silver light and shrank to a delicate foot tall form.

Han Li turned around to look at the Weeping Soul Beast’s transformation and couldn’t help but smile.

When he had left Red Soil Village, he had brought the Weeping Soul Beast to many various places to exterminate powerful umbra beasts. After absorbing large quantities of umbra beast soul essence, the weeping soul beast had suddenly gained the ability to transform into a huge ape, and not long after, its fur soon turned an eye-catching silver.

These changes had come as a great surprise to Han Li. According to the slip that Yuan Yao had given him, the Weeping Soul Beast shouldn’t have the ability to enlarge itself, and its fur should’ve turned pitch-black upon advancing instead of silver.

It appeared that this peculiar evolution was a result of two aspects that had coincidentally met: umbra beast soul essence that greatly differed from the soul essence commonly found in the outside world, and the fact that the beast wasn’t completely refined in the first place.

It wasn’t as miraculous as the commonly known variant spirit beasts, but its peculiar transformation was absolutely the first of its kind.

Although he didn’t know whether or not this transformation resulted in strength greater than true Weeping Soul Beasts, Han Li was quite content after seeing these changes continue. After all, the refinement method of a true Weeping Soul Beast was a bloody affair. Although Han Li wasn’t a soft person, he would’ve found it difficult to refine it according to the methods that he was given.

At that moment, the Weeping Soul Beast shot into Han Li’s sleeve with a flash of white and silver light and deep breaths of sleep could be heard.

Han Li faintly smiled in response, but soon his face grew solemn when he gazed at Stormwind Mountain in the distance.

That previous umbra beast had been the last remaining giant umbra beast near Stormwind Mountain. They were now free to climb the mountain without obstruction.

Han Li took a deep glance at the distant mountain and slowly said, “Let’s go! We have to climb to the top of the mountain before the next spatial tear appears. Otherwise, we’ll be stuck here several more months.”

Mei Ning agreed, “Of course! According to the native’s method of predicting these intermittent spatial tears, the next tear should appear in about two weeks. If we were to miss it, we’d have to wait another half year.”

Han Li faintly smiled and took the lead towards the huge mountain.

A quarter hour later, the two stood at the base of Stormwind Mountain.

Although they didn’t feel anything from that distance, they were awed as they stood before the mountain. There were no neighboring mountains, only several kilometers of a single, steep mountain.

Han Li didn’t immediately start off on his climb. He first turned to Mei Ning and discussed the method that would be best to climb the gargantuan mountain. Not long after, the two became two black dots that slowly disappeared from sight as they gradually made their way up.

The first four kilometers weren’t particularly difficult or strenuous for Han Li and Mei Ning, and they made their way up without much effort. But after that point, the bone-chilling Yin winds began to blow at faster speeds and with greater force.

At that point, Han Li and Mei Ning covered themselves in several articles of fire-attribute beast hide clothing, but even with this, their faces paled as the cold winds tore their skin. Were they ordinary mortals, they would’ve long since met their end by freezing over.

After persisting for another hundred meters through the Yin wind, Han Li stopped with a frown and solemnly pondered for a moment before taking out a fist-sized white gem from within his robes. The gem released a faint white luster that quickly enveloped the two.

The piercing Yin winds were greatly weakened upon touching the white light, and were no longer strong enough to do them harm. As a result, the two were able to arduously continue their ascent, relying on their beast hide clothes to resist the iciness of the air.

Eventually, the ground became covered in frost and their footing became slippery, forcing the two of them to slow their ascent and walk with caution. Additionally, their breathes became visible and it became increasingly more difficult for them to breath. Mei Ning in particular was gasping for air with a completely flushed face.

After an unknown amount of time passed as they continued on their trek, they found themselves before a precipitous expanse of glistening black ice. If one wasn’t careful as they climbed, they would find themselves falling off the mountain.

On their way, Han Li and Mei Ning had already put on rough scaled gloves out of necessity. Even with the gloves, the trek to that point had been incredibly difficult and the two would often lose their grip on the black frost.

Han Li raised his head to look at the top of the glistening cliff and sighed. He then turned his head to the pale-faced woman at his side and said, “Let’s take a moment to rest beneath that cliff over there. We’ll continue onward after we recover our strength.”

Although she hadn’t said anything, Han Li could tell at a glance that her strength was nearly exhausted. It would quite dangerous if she continued in this condition.

When Mei Ning heard this, she let out a long breath and nodded with a forced smile.

The huge cliff that Han Li spoke of was actually an inwardly slanted stone cliff. The appearance of such good shelter was quite timely, and the two hastily made their way towards it.

Fog and howling winds blew on the outside as Han Li and Mei Ning walked beneath the cliff. With a cautious expression, Han Li took out a thumb sized bead that he wore on his wrist and had it emit a faint azure light. Just as the fog approached them, the azure light forcibly repelled the fog. However, the fog still lingered nearby as if it were waiting for an opportunity to draw closer.

Mei Ning glanced at the fog and said, “It seems that if it weren’t for Brother Han’s Matron Screen Pearl, we would’ve been unable to make it past the Yin wind’s strange fog!”

Han Li smiled and thought to say something when he suddenly froze and began to concentrate on his hearing.

When Mei Ning saw this, she was somewhat shocked and discreetly kept quiet.

Han Li indifferently said, “Be careful. Someone is approaching us from within the fog.” With a glint of azure light, an azure dagger appeared in his hand. He then stared into the fog in silence.

With complete confidence in Han Li’s words, Mei Ning immediately took a few steps back and stared outward with a nervous expression.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant

Chapter 594: Yin Yang Revolution Arts

Not long after, Mei Ning heard the sound of soft and heavy footsteps slowly drawing closer to them. She nervously glanced at Han Li, who seemed to notice her gaze and gently smiled in response.

Mei Ning unconsciously blushed and quickly focused her eyes away from Han Li, but she felt somewhat relieved as well.

As the footsteps grew clearer, Han Li could hear the faint gasps of two people, much to his surprise.

Han Li frowned and a trace of killing intent glinted within his eyes.

Suddenly, the thick fog parted and revealed a young man with his head held high. He had an elegant face and wore a jade band around his waist that faintly appeared to shine with white light.

However, when the man caught sight of Han Li, his face immediately distorted as he shouted in alarm, “It’s you!?”

This man was the disciple of Archsaint Six Paths, Wen Tianren.

Han Li expressionlessly said, “That’s right, it’s me. You can now rest in peace!” With a flicker of azure light, Han Li tossed the dagger into the center of Weh Tianren’s chest.

Peng! The dagger was easily knocked away as if it had struck metal. The torn clothes revealed a faint flicker of green light.

“Inner armor?”

Han Li was somewhat surprised that his strike was ineffective, but he snorted and waved his other hand, throwing another azure streak. This time, it was aimed at Wen Tianren’s throat.

At that moment, Wen Tianren reacted and dodged in alarm, his body evading the dagger in a blur. Just as the dagger missed, he shot into the fog behind him. It appeared his body was quite vigorous.

With yet another attack missing, Han Li merely glanced at Wen Tianren’s fleeing figure. He remained still with a sneer on his face.

When Wen Tianren quickly turned his head around and saw Han Li’s expression, he immediately felt that something was amiss and he turned around in a blur. But by then, it was already too late. He felt a piercing cold wind on the back of his neck followed by an icy sensation where the dagger struck him. The semi-transparent string of beast tendon that was tied around the dagger hilt was stretched taut.

A stream of blood then began to flow from Wen Tianren’s corpse. His eyes remained wide open during his last moments as if he couldn’t believe that he had died in this manner.

Han Li expressionlessly shook his right hand with his finger pulling on the taut tendon. The dagger then obediently flew out from Wen Tianren’s neck and returned to his palm. At that moment, Han Li turned his gaze back into the dense fog and narrowed his eyes.

A slim figure then slowly appeared from the fog, revealing a gorgeous young woman dressed in white.

The woman smiled sweetly at Han Li and said, “Brother Han! I didn’t think that we’d meet again.”

“Lady Violet Spirit!” Han Li nodded with a calm expression and had his two daggers disappear into his sleeves with a shake of his hands.

Naturally, Han Li knew Fairy Violet Spirit’s greatly changed appearance after hearing her conversation with Wen Tianren when he was trapped inside the golden flames. After seeing her true appearance, Han Li couldn’t help but concede that Fairy Violet Spirit’s grand reputation as one of the most beautiful women in the Scattered Star Seas was well deserved. Even Yuan Yao’s magnificent, breath-taking beauty was a smidgen less than Violet Spirit’s.

But at that moment, Violet Spirit glanced down at the corpse on the ground and sighed, “I truly didn’t think that the self proclaimed top Core Formation cultivator, Young Master Wen, would meet his end at Fellow Daoist Han’s hand. If this were told to others, I suspect that most of them wouldn’t believe it.”

“Since I encountered him in this place, I naturally couldn’t let him go,” Han Li calmly replied. He then walked to the side of Wen Tianren’s corpse and took his storage pouch without reservation. At that same moment, he took a glance at the jade cloud belt with curiosity.

Violet Spirit pursed her lips in a smile and explained, “That is the Four Celestials Belt. It is embedded with four miraculous gems that are capable of resisting wind, fire, water and earth. Additionally, it is capable of keeping one’s mind calm. It truly is a rare treasure. He had relied much on this belt to journey in this land without obstruction.”

“The Four Celestials Belt. It will prove quite useful at the moment.” After some hesitation, he bent down and took the belt off of Wen Tianren's corpse.

He then searched through the corpse without reservation and found a dark green plate of inner armor along with several other treasures.

“Brother Han, who might this Fellow Daoist be?” Violet Spirit’s bright gaze then turned to Mei Ning behind him.

Han Li calmly replied, “That is Lady Mei. She is a Fellow Daoist who was teleported alongside me.”

“So it’s Lady Mei!”

“I’ve had the pleasure of seeing you before!” Mei Ning felt somewhat awkward but she gazed at Violet Spirit with curiosity regardless.

Fairy Violet Spirit was undoubtedly worthy of a grand reputation. Even Mei Ning remained mesmerized by her beauty for a while. She couldn’t help but guess at the relationship between the two.

Fairy Violet Spirit kindly smiled at Mei Ning and revealed an apologetic expression to Han Li, “Fellow Daoist Han, please don’t blame me for not assisting you that day. At the time...”

Han Li waved his hand and interrupted her with a casual tone, “There is no need for Lady Violet Spirit to speak of it! Although I don’t know why you were together with Wen Tianren, I was able to see your unwillingness to be with him. Moreover, I clearly remember that you refused to act against my companion in the valley.”

Fairy Violet Spirit inwardly sighed with relief upon seeing that Han Li wasn’t angry with her and immediately smiled, saying, “Since Brother Han has already recognized my difficulties, then I will say no more. However, would it be possible for me to travel alongside you two?”

“Of course! You’ve already walked halfway into the fog and it would be difficult to turn back. Since we’ve already made it this far, there is no point in wasting the effort.”

“Many thanks, Brother Han!” Fairy Violet Spirit’s moist eyes began to shine, revealing an incomparable beauty.

Not long after, the three disappeared into the mist, leaving behind Wen Tianren’s frozen corpse.

...

At the same moment, a strange scene was occuring inside a cave.

A gorgeous woman sat cross-legged on the ground across from a ghostly image surrounded in black Qi. The ghost was also sitting cross-legged. Although it appeared quite vague, it was reminiscent of a young woman.

“Junior Martial Sister, have you truly decided to cultivate the Yin Yang Revolutions with me? It doesn’t seem to be a wise decision.” A somewhat unfamiliar woman’s voice urged against it.

“Senior Martial Sister Yan should know that because my original core was already shattered from using the Soulrise Technique, I had nearly cut off my path of cultivation. Furthermore, I didn’t expect that after paying such a heavy cost that the Soulrise Technique would be interrupted by the sudden appearance of the ghost mist. Because Senior Martial Sister’s soul has greatly condensed, she no longer has any hope of possessing a body. But fortunately, there is a silver lining. There is dense umbra Qi here is quite beneficial to those cultivating ghost Dao techniques. As for the Yin Yang Revolution Arts, it is a rarely seen human-ghost pair cultivation technique. By taking advantage of the umbra Qi, not only will Senior Martial Sister’s cultivation quickly increase, but I will also have a chance of returning to Core Formation stage. Even Nascent Soul stage wouldn’t be impossible.” Yuan Yao spoke with complete calmness.

“Since it’s like that, I won’t refuse any longer. However, I must warn Junior Martial Sister that although the technique will be incredibly effective by drawing support from the umbra Qi, you will suffer dire backlash and will also lose your right to reincarnation. You should consider it carefully. There is a reason why no one in the Azure Yang Sect used the cultivation art despite possessing it for so long.” The ghost woman seemed to have spoken the last two sentences with a trace of helplessness.

“Junior Martial Sister doesn’t need to say any further. I’ve already made my decision. There will be no regrets!” Yuan Yao wore an expression of grave resolution.

“Alright, since Junior Martial Sister doesn’t fear the consequences, then I won’t regard them either. Let us cultivate the Yin Yang Revolutions Art!” After a long sigh from the vague ghost, it extended its two arms of black Qi.

When Yuan Yao saw this, she extended her hands without hesitation and closed her eyes upon contact, setting forth on the path of cultivation once more.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant

Chapter 595: Breaking Away

On a flat cliff on Stormwind Mountain stood a huge silver ape that was over forty meters tall. It was beating its chest while carrying Han Li, Mei Ning, and Violet Spirit on its back.

Han Li gravely stared at the sky in silence while the two women’s faces were pale, faintly revealing a trace of panic.

There were over a thousand umbra beasts circling above them. There were beasts that were over twenty meters in length along with those that were only a foot long, all with wings that sprouted out from between their ribs. But regardless of size, they all looked fierce and malevolent without exception. However, these flying umbra beasts seemed to fear the overbearing pressure of the transformed Weeping Soul Beast and didn’t dare to draw closer to them. They merely stayed in a deadlock by flying in circles above them.

Han Li felt somewhat uneasy. From the greed revealed inside the umbra beasts’ eyes, it was unclear how long their patience would hold before they started to attack.

At the moment, Han Li was cursing the plump old man who had given him the information regarding the mountain. Although he did say that there were flying umbra beasts, he didn’t say that they existed in such large quantities. It was unknown whether it had been deliberately concealed or if it truly wasn't known.

After passing through the area with the dense fog, they had originally believed that they could have a moment of respite. However, they didn’t expect for these flying beasts to immediately surround them. Helpless, Han Li could only release the Weeping Soul Beast and have it transform.

Han Li was completely confident in the Weeping Soul Beast’s abilities at restraining umbra beasts, but there were truly too many in the sky. Han Li was unsure if the Weeping Soul Beast could deal with so many of them. But having reached this point, Han Li couldn’t afford to think about it much more and could only do his utmost.

Having come to that conclusion, Han Li turned around and whispered something to the scared Mei Ning and Violet Spirit. Afterwards, he handed them a small piece of jade and a soft beast hide shield. He then shook his sleeves and over ten daggers fell onto the ground with a series of clangs.

Each of the daggers had a thin string of beast tendon tied around the hilt, connecting them to each of Han Li’s fingers. However, Han Li had yet to control ten of them at one time, making it an unprecedented display.

With his preparations completed, the umbra beasts above finally lost their patience and attacked.

The largest among them, a three headed umbra beast, suddenly let out a terrifying shriek and swooped down without any regard for the Weeping Soul Beast’s strength.

The battle had finally begun!

At the same moment the demon beasts attacked, the huge ape took a deep breath and shut its mouth before spewing a mist of silver light from its nose, enveloping most of the umbra beasts in the air. These umbra beasts immediately released a miserable shriek as they dropped from the sky.

However, two of the smaller umbra beasts managed to escape the mist’s capture and swept down towards the three humans.

One of the umbra beasts was then smashed away by the huge ape’s first and fell over a cliff. As for the other, it appeared to be a two meter long eagle and took advantage of this opening to swoop down right at Han Li’s head.

Han Li grimly remained in place, but his fingers made a series of swift and nimble movements. Ten daggers then shot into the air and turned into a net of glinting daggers in the umbra beast’s path.

A dismal scream left the umbra beast’s mouth.

Even without the infusion of magic power, the Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords were incredibly sharp. In an instant, the small umbra beast was skewered without resistance. As bloody chunks of flesh filled the sky, Han Li quickly dodged in a blur, but some of them still landed on him. After a slight grimace, he paid it no more attention as there were far more pressing matters at hand: another wave of winged umbra beasts was flying towards them.

This wave had twice the number of the previous group of umbra beasts. Additionally, there were more umbra beasts approaching them from behind with an obvious eagerness to attack.

Han Li’s mind grew stern and he instantly waved his arms, forming a net of swords yet again. However, the net now covered a slightly wider range that also protected Mei Ning and Violet Spirit.

Following the mists of silver light and the azure glints, wretched screams quickly filled the sky.

...

Seven days later, under the scorchingly bright noon sun, an expanse of glimmering sea was deathly calm. There wasn’t even the slightest wave or sea breeze as if the nearby sea was completely void of life.

Suddenly, a series of waves began to roil and suddenly released a cloud of black fog. The pitch-black fog rapidly permeated throughout the air and instantly spread over several hundred meters.

At that moment, thunder began to clap and silver light flashed from the black fog before a sphere of silver radiance appeared from within it. A faint, wide silhouette with a pair of silver wings could be seen within.

Before this figure could be clearly seen, the silver radiance wildly flashed several times before completely disappearing, leaving only echoes of thunder behind. A second later, a person could be seen at the edge of the black mist, but he intermittently disappeared and reappeared, filling the sky with flickers of light and rolls of thunder. It appeared as if they wished to escape from that desolate place as quickly as possible.

The sea then returned to silence. Only the rapidly expanding black fog remained, continuing to silently release bursts of black lightning.

About five hundred kilometers away from the black mist, the silver light faded away to reveal Han Li holding Violet Spirit in one arm and Mei Ning in the other. From how tightly they were holding onto him, it appeared quite intimate.

Han Li appeared somewhat better off than the other two. Despite his overwhelmed senses, he managed to keep a calm face. However, the two women in his embrace were slightly scarlet, revealing a heart-moving tenderness.

Han Li took a glance around and wore an expression of relief. He then relaxed his grasp on the two women in an honorable manner and said, “This should be enough. The ghost mist can’t reach us now.”

“I must truly give my thanks to Fellow Daoist Han. If it weren’t for your miraculous movement technique, it’s quite likely that we wouldn’t have been able to escape.”

“Elder Sister Violet Spirit speaks truly. If it weren't for Brother Han’s amazingly swift actions, we may have been sucked back into the Umbra Realm. We’ve troubled Brother Han greatly.”

As soon as Violet Spirit and Mei Ning left Han Li’s embrace, their bodies began to shine with light as they floated at Han Li’s side.

Several days before, the three had encountered many dangers, but managed to climb up to Stormwind Mountain’s summit by relying on the Weeping Soul Beast’s strength. During the time they waited for the spatial tear to open, the two women found each other’s company extremely agreeable, and not long after, they became sworn sisters, much to Han Li’s surprise.

Several days after reaching the summit, a hundred-meter-wide spatial tear appeared about a kilometer above Stormwind Mountain. Massive amounts of Heaven-Earth spiritual Qi began to flow in from the outside, restoring the trio’s magic power in an instant and allowing them to fly into the air with joy.

However, Han Li truly didn’t expect that in the instant he left the tear that an immense suction force would pull at him from behind. He hadn’t been able to move in the slightest and was slowly being dragged back in.

Fortunately, Han Li quickly came to his senses and immediately unfolded the Thunderstorm Wings as he flickered several times to grab onto the two women, before launching himself out of the black mist. As a result, the two gave him their heartfelt thanks.

When Violet Spirit recovered her bearings, she casually swept her gaze over the ocean and frowned, “Where is this place? How can it be so odd? It’s completely calm!”

Mei Ning’s face appeared puzzled after taking a glance down, “What? It is truly as Elder Sister Violet Spirit says. This is quite amiss, there isn’t the slightest breeze and the seas are completely still.”

Han Li remained silent as he narrowed his eyes and released his spiritual sense. He began to sweep the depths of the nearby seas, and after a short moment, Han Li revealed an expression of shock.

Violet Spirit had also swept her spiritual sense deep into the seas and after a moment, her beautiful eyes were filled with shock, “Could it be Brother Han has discovered something? There are so few fish in the sea and they all seem to be extremely fierce sea beasts. However, none of them appear to be demon beasts.”

“Please wait a moment!” Han Li then took a deep breath and flicked his finger, shooting a ten meter streak of azure swordlight deep into the waters below.

A short moment later, a grotesque sea beast corpse floated to the water’s surface, much to the shock of the two women.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant